<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "micasex.dtd">
<TEI.2 ID="les425su093">
	<TEIHEADER>
		<FILEDESC>
			<TITLESTMT>
				<TITLE> Spring Ecosystems Lecture </TITLE>
				<TITLE> Rackham Div: BS </TITLE>
			</TITLESTMT>
			<PUBLICATIONSTMT>
				<PUBLISHER> Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English, English Language Institute, University of Michigan </PUBLISHER>
				<IDNO> LES425SU093 </IDNO>
				<AVAILABILITY>
					<P> The MICASE project is owned by the Regents of the University of Michigan, who hold the copyright.  The database has been developed by the English Language Institute, and the web interface by Digital Library Production Services.  The original DAT audiotapes are held in the English Language Institute and may be consulted by bona fide researchers under special arrangements.  The database is freely available at this website for study, teaching and research purposes, and copies of the transcripts may be distributed, as long as either this statement of availability or the citation given below appears in the text.  However, if any portion of this material is to be used for commercial purposes, such as for textbooks or tests, permission must be obtained in advance and a license fee may be required.  Furthermore, some restrictions apply on the citation of specific portions of some of the transcripts in educational presentations and publications; all such restrictions are noted at the end of this statement.  For further information about copyright permissions, please contact Dr. Sarah Briggs at slbriggs@umich.edu. </P>
					<P> The recommended citation for MICASE is: R. C. Simpson, S. L. Briggs, J. Ovens, and J. M. Swales.  (1999) The Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English.  Ann Arbor, MI:  The Regents of the University of Michigan </P>
					<P> RESTRICTIONS ON CITATION OF EXAMPLES:  NONE </P>
				</AVAILABILITY>
			</PUBLICATIONSTMT>
			<SOURCEDESC>
				<RECORDINGSTMT>
					<RECORDING DUR="74">
						<DATE> May 16, 2000 </DATE>
						<EQUIPMENT>
							<P> TASCAM Digital Audio Tape Recorder with two external microphones </P>
						</EQUIPMENT>
						<RESPSTMT>
							<NAME> Carrie Sue Kay Sulzer, Janine Ovens </NAME>
							<RESP> Recording </RESP>
							<NAME> Carrie Sue Kay Sulzer </NAME>
							<RESP> Transcribing </RESP>
							<NAME> Amy Burke </NAME>
							<RESP> Rechecking </RESP>
							<NAME> Darell Tibbles </NAME>
							<RESP> Proofreading </RESP>
							<NAME> Darell Tibbles </NAME>
							<RESP> Final Editing, 05/30/01 </RESP>
						</RESPSTMT>
					</RECORDING>
				</RECORDINGSTMT>
			</SOURCEDESC>
		</FILEDESC>
		<PROFILEDESC>
			<LANGUSAGE>
				<P> Primary Discourse Mode: MIX </P>
				<LANGUAGE ID="NS"> Native Speaker </LANGUAGE>
			</LANGUSAGE>
			<PARTICDESC>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Students" SIZE="22"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Speakers" SIZE="7"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSON ID="S1" LANG="NS" ROLE="JF, Lecturer" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="3"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S2" LANG="NS" ROLE="SG, Unknown" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="3"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S3" LANG="NS" ROLE="SG, Instructor" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="2"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S4" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S5" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S6" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S7" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SS" LANG="NS" ROLE="UN, Students" SEX="U" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SU-f" LANG="NS" ROLE="UN, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SU-m" LANG="NS" ROLE="UN, Student" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
			</PARTICDESC>
			<SETTINGDESC>
				<SETTING>
					<P> Lecture Room, Dana Building </P>
				</SETTING>
			</SETTINGDESC>
		</PROFILEDESC>
	</TEIHEADER>
	<TEXT>
		<BODY>
			<U WHO="S1"> okay um, the midterm is a week from today, <U WHO="SU-f">
					<OVERLAP> whoo </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> as hard </OVERLAP> as that is to believe whoo-hoo <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
				<EVENT WHO="SU-f" DESC="LAUGH"/> so um, we will pu- i- in the uh, undergraduate library Science Library reserves are the old, exams, both the midterm and the final, that you can check out. um, but, just to be nice <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> we will also post a midterm, in the lab here. you can take it away to copy it, but that's all you can take it away for so, get it back as soon as you can, if you do take it out. um, and, i am gonna have a review session tomorrow night Wednesday night from six-thirty to eight at Eberwhite Woods. there's a sign-up sheet in the lab so you have to sign up, and there's directions how to get there it's a probably about a mile and a half away if you wanna walk or, ride your bike or something it's pretty close. um, and we'll meet in the parking lot there, at six thirty. and then Dulcy </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> uh i'm not sure what i'm gonna do yet. i- i wanted to uh, take a vote on, i have to change my review session, for extenuating circumstances, like i can't control them, so it could either be Sunday at five, or Monday, maybe at four or five. now, i don't like to, take away, a lot of the weekend time so i wanted to ask you would you rather have it Sunday, or Monday? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Sunday. </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> fine Sunday at five it is. <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> so at Bird Hill i'll put up uh, directions and everything. okay, that was easy. </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
			<U WHO="S3"> alright great. the topic for today's lecture is river floodplains, and what we're gonna be doing is_ first i wanna talk about, the larger picture what it means, a watershed is and what drainage basins are. and then we'll look at some specific drainage patterns which are actually, on page ninety-five i think, yeah in your coursepack. and then we'll talk about the different processes, that are, that go on surrounding a river, followed by the specific landforms of the floodplain, the climate of the floodplain, soils and vegetation of the floodplain. and then if we have time we'll look at slides, of, um last week's lab, when we went to Sharon Hollow. okay, so the first thing, is talking about this idea of a watershed, and what that means and so up here on the board i wrote this definition there, there're a variety of definitions about, of watersheds, or of a drainage basin, but this one seems to be pretty inclusive, saying that <SEG TYPE="READING"> it's the area of land, that drains to a single outlet, and it is separated from other watersheds, by a divide. </SEG> and you've heard you know of the Continental Divide, that is the, the largest watershed that we can think about in North America, and if water falls, if a drop of water falls to the west of the continental divide it eventually makes it out to the Pacific, Ocean and then if it falls to the east of the continental divide it makes it out to the Atlantic Ocean. so that's a broadscale watershed um, with that divide being the Continental Divide. and i'll show a couple of pictures of other_ of the Huron watershed, and um, so you can see what those different flow wa- flow pathways are, into the watershed and what's draining. but what it amounts to is a system of channels, which is also referred to as a drainage network. and i kind of like this, this quote out of this um, article i was reading that said, that this, system of channels represents nature's most effective means, of getting water off of the land. okay so, we really_ it's important that we understand the processes that are going on in floodplains and understand that, this is a natural, process in the landscape, and that um you know it's not good for vegetation to be sitting in all this water, and so, this is just a series of networks, that allows um, the water to get removed from the landscape. so <PAUSE DUR="0:15"/> okay this is a picture showing, the traditional watershed divide, and this c- this picture only shows, the deep groundwater flow pathways, that are coming. so you can see that, the groundwater here, is all flowing into the stream, and this is a separate, this is a separate watershed or a separate drainage basin so, here's the divide that separates the two right there... now it's important to understand though, that, not only does ground water, which is called base flow does_ not only does ground water flow, into um, this stream and get carried away, but also the r- s- more surface, flow or runoff, that's either just very um, not very far beneath the surface, or it runs across the top of the surface. and so, those are both, important elements, contributing to how, a particular drainage basin gets drained, into the channels that are draining it. <PAUSE DUR="0:07"/> okay this shows a picture of the Huron watershed, and, all of these other, divisions are actually just sub-basins within this larger drainage basin, called the Huron watershed. and, i have another, picture showing the particular outlet... so here we have you know a bunch_ everything every, drop of water that falls within, this area, gets drained out to this outlet right here. that eventually goes out to Lake Erie. <PAUSE DUR=":05"/> so are there any questions about what, a watershed i- what a watershed is what a drainage basin is? the way that the water flows out of a particular drainage area, into the different channels that eventually get carried away, the way that that water moves is really dependent on the, the physiography on the bedrock, of the material that's present there and so, it depends the, the drainage will look differently depending on if it's, extremely um corrodible and erosive material versus if it's more_ it's it's very resistant to weathering and erosion, and sometimes it's very homogeneous meaning that, um, you know you have one type of bedrock over the entire area, and other times when you have differential types of bedrock some will be extremely, um easily weathered, and others won't be, and so you'll get different, patterns that way. and that's what i wanna talk about next. so if you turn to your coursepack on page ninety-five you'll see, these basic drainage patterns, these pictures. and these can be, this i- these are just, eight different very basic drainage patterns, there's a lot of, variation in the real world, and there are, differences in between, um some of these can be altered but, this will show you what the basic patterns, look like. the first one is dendritic, and this is actually the most common. it's found in very uniform, homogeneous, bedrock, areas. and so what happens is, it a- it ends up branching a lot and it looks s- very it's called dendritic like tree like. and, it's characterized by, if you can see the one two and three. first order channels which are ephemeral they don't last throughout the year, they're there when there's a lot of water to be drained, and um, what happens is when two first order streams, tributaries when they come together, they make a second-order stream. and it takes two second order streams to come together, before you get a third order stream. and it's these higher ordered streams, the second third even fourth ordered stream those are, permanent rivers that, are present in the landscape. so the first order streams, are typically, only there during spring runoff... okay for parallel which is the next one, you can see that these are formed, they're extremely parallel ridges, formed in linear landforms and again this would be, material that's very homogeneous very alike. the bedrock can either be sedimentary it could be metamorphic but it's all similar in a given area. and that varies from this trellis one, which has differential, material. oftentimes this was formed, on a slanted bed, and so you might have extremely, uh ve- very resistant rock, located at the top of the ridges, and getting drained down into valleys that, are more corrodible. and so you have um, a different- difference in the rock ma- maybe going from metamorphic rock, to sedimentary rock which would be, um weathered more easily and so you get these, different, gaps between the ridges forming. and you have similar sized tributaries coming in to, another, branch, and then into the main trough. section D shows a rectangular drainage pattern, and this one's really easy because it's all, made up of these right angles. so, the main, drainage is a right angle and then the tributaries to those, come in mostly at right angles and this is, found where it's very strongly jointed rocky terrain. and it sort of guides the, it guides the water in those, along those joints. and um, so the way that you tell that from this one this, these just are broken up there's they're divided, there's gaps in between the ridges, and, it, it just looks like there's, there's more tributaries coming into it, on the trellis. radial is when it's uh if you think of a volcano, it's one peak, and everything is draining down from this one point. so here's the center, water's getting carried downward from this one point and, and it ends up, goes off radially. and that varies from this annular drainage pattern which, is also found when you have a dome. however this again occurs when there's differences in the material. different- differences in the weathering of the material and, and the, the drainage path will seek out, the um least resistant path. and so, when you have these areas that are coming in it's because, it was able to break through, very easily weathered, rock surfaces. and so you get this circular, appearance to it... and the last two are uh ones that we'll talk about, that kind of a combination of the last two are what, glacial drift, what the kind of drainage that glacial drift has. but the first one is multi-basinal and that's any ti- any time that you have, very hummocky topography, and sometimes we have specific names for it like, when it's limestone topography, it's called karst and what happens is, um it gets dissolved the limestone gets dissolved differentially and you get sinkholes and caves and rivers underground. um but anytime you have really hummocky mat- really hummocky surface like this, and, you don't necessarily know where it came from, it's also called multi-basinal. and then, contorted, i- is what happens_ the difference in contorted is that it's very, it's just not very specific, and it it forms when there's glacial drift, and it's very messy there's not very or- there_ it's not very orderly the pattern of it's not very orderly, and so the rivers are are taking whichever route that they can, because the underlying rock surface, the structure is not there. so it's just, flowing around the glacial drift. and and the way that it looks it it's just looks (strange,) contorted. so glacial drift is kind of a combination of both. multi-basinal can occur we've talked about how, the glaciers could depress the land in the bedrock, and um, and depending on how the drift was laid when the glaciers were retreating, would have maybe allowed it to be, multi-basinal as well. so it's kind of a combination of the two. are there any questions...? okay, then, what i want to talk about is um, a little bit about the processes of rivers, and understanding and understanding more about what the purpose of a river is. and so, rivers are basically they're great, levellers that transport material from high in the landscape, and they wash it out to lower in the landscape. so they're moving this material from upward, down, to lower grounds and water basins and then they get deposited there. and they carry a large amount of material with them, this material is called alluvium, any material transported by a river is called alluvium. and this diagram here the one up, here shows, that there are different types of materials, that the river carries. one type is this bed load, which, is just, located in the bottom, it moves very, slowly it kind of rolls with the river but it's, it's along the bottom, and those are where the coarsest materials are found. so they kinda roll and tumble along, the, lower surface of, the river. and then you also have suspended load, which are the finer particles that get carried with the flow of water. and, uh we talked about this before that depending on how fast the water is moving would depend on, wh- what size of particles settle out. so those clays which are the finest materials, they will say s- stay suspended in that flow, until it, it almost comes to a complete stop. and then the clays with- would um settle out. but if the river's moving faster it'll be able to carry larger particles. and over here this term saltation is what is referred to when, the river's moving much larger particles. and it's actually, just, it's sort of a bouncing, leaps and tumbles of larger particles, that occur when they get picked up by either wind, or by water. so if you think of how sand dunes we'll talk about dunal formation, that's how sand dunes get formed too. it's the, the tumbling of these particles by saltation, and this happens, either through wind or through water. <PAUSE DUR="0:09"/> okay and then there's two other terms that i wanna talk about related to what types of materials, that the river carries, and, one, relates to the size of the particles carried. okay and this, the term, referring to this is called competence how competent is the river in carrying, larger, particles. and so, if there's a lot more, of the larger particles mixed in the flow, then it has a high- it's said to have high competence. versus low competence if there were more smaller particles. and then also it relates to, the number of particles that are carried. this term is capacity. so if the, if the river has the ability to carry a very large quantity, of mat- of material, then it has a high capacity. versus a low capacity if it doesn't carry very much through there. and while both of these relate to wa- to the velocity of water, this one relates more me- we- mentioned that before, the velocity, how fast it's going, it'll be able to c- if it's flowing faster it'll be able to carry larger particles. and although this one does relate to velocity it is much more dependent on, a discharge, the volume of water that's going through, a particular river. larger volume, it'll be able to carry more, particles with it. <PAUSE DUR="0:08"/> are there questions about that? <PAUSE DUR="0:08"/> okay then the next thing i wanna talk about, is the flow of water, and what happens, just as a natural process, of of me- of rivers. and the natural tendency of a river if you think of a river starting out completely straight, the natural tendency is over time we're talking, you know hundreds thousands of years, but over time this river will meander. there'll be different things that block it up in one area have to go around, maybe a log or maybe, a rock or something and so, what happens is it'll start to go one way. so if the river's flowing and, over time it starts to go this way, it's cutting this bank. as it goes it's taking material away from that bank. it's directly cutting into it. but there's a slower flow on the inside of the meander. and this is where material gets deposited. it's a little bit slower f- flowing, and so, it's almost it's removing material from here but then eventually downstream it'll deposit those materials that it's that it's removing. so we have a cutbank, and the point of that position which is called a point bar. and that's just the natural process of rivers over time, you can get_ not only, do rivers, migrate, from like left to right, but they also, can migrate the bends can start to migrate south in the direction, that the river's flowing. i have a different diagram to illustrate that... which is this one right here at the top. so you can see that, the river's flowing and this is a much more, dynamic bend wi- of the meander but you can see how, it shows where the original, path of the river was, and that over time from cutting away, and depositing you get these big point bar deposits. and it's still_ it's cutting away from the direction that it's flowing and so the, the river it's migrating that way migrating that way, but also, here it was, and it starts to migrate, away from, where it was originally. and it migrates in the direction of the flow. so you have d- two different modes of migration on the river and it's due to this meandering motion. okay so this flow, that you see in a river, this is just you know rivers are flowing that's a normal that's a continuous process, that occurs, daily yearly, s- every century. but then we have this other process that occurs on river floodplains, why they're called floodplains, and that's flooding. and this, although it's, a regular process it is infrequent. so and we can have different, we can have different sizes of floods, very major ones that are called hundred year floods, that are typically said, well once a century you'll get, a large flood on this border, versus smaller floods. and what happens, when there's a flood, is that, here's the f- here's normal before the flood, the flood stage water okay so the water's, has risen, onto the banks adjacent to the f- ad- adjacent to the filling channel. and you get these different deposits right adjacent to it. so during a flood the thick coarse materials, will be deposited right here right adjacent to this channel. and then, as waters still keep toppling over that, they start to flow a little bit, their velocity slows down as they splash on top of where these coarse materials are, and some of the finer materials settle out over here on, outside of that. and so this is what's called a levee. over time, it keeps building up by many different floods, and, you know even s- even smaller floods, keep splashing up and you get very thick, amount of coarse material, sands and gravels there, and finer silts and clays, further out. and we'll be talking more about the, the other formations of the of the land forms, of the floodplain but that's, that's a big one that occurs, from directly from that flooding effect. so two processes just the normal flow of the river, which is very continuous, and the rivers meander over time, compared to, another type it's a regular process but it's it's more infrequent. it it... and then this diagram, just shows how i- if we looked at, a cross section of the river how it would flow, and how it that depends on what other obstacles are in the way. so, for example the profile would be like this if there was a lake, because the river actually adjusts to whatever the the base flow is at that local level. so, for example, we have a lake here whether it's, a reservoir because there's a dam there, or it's just a natural lake, the river's, adjusted to this level right here. and then further down it's adjusted to the level where the ocean is. but over time if something hap- if that lake got drained, what would happen is, the river level would just be adjusted to this ocean, level right here. cuz that would be, the base the base level at that river. so that's how, usually it's this concave upward, profile, but it does get altered by some local, some different, local physiographic differences that, might might change over time and therefore it would be, like this other this ocean base level... is that confusing? kind of, okay well let it soak in <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> and then <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> let me know if you have questions about it. alright, so those are a couple of the processes, and now i wanna talk about the other, features, that we have and this is in your coursepack on page ninety-six. so we're gonna look at (xx) different features that are formed, within the floodplain and then we'll look at a cross section, so that you can see what we'll be walking on, over today when we get out on the actual, floodplain. okay so the first one we already started talking about the pointbar, and these, again they're formed on the inside of these meanders... (cutbank) opposite on the outside where the river is cutting. i drew, i kinda colored in blue, on the one side the levee, okay we already talked about the levee. and then we have a couple of other features, the o- an oxbow lake, is one they actually have a really nice diagram down lower, showing how this forms. and what happens i already mentioned that, we have this natural meander over time. but during a flooding event, water always seeks the shortest route. so during a flooding event, it might actually get channelized to go straight, down the main, the main channel. and, it kinda leaves this other channel that's out of the way, it kinda leaves it stagnant and over time, <SIC> as waters just kind of sitting there pools up, </SIC> there's coar- there's very fine clays that_ and s- and silts that get deposited right there adjacent to the main channel, and it actually cuts this oxbow lake off, from the main channel. so you have just this other, it always looks, like a, like a U-shape, like that. okay so that's a oxbow lake and you can see, up here, showing the oxbow lake and how, there's that clay plug, which, is blocking it off from the main channel. meander scrolls are, are evidence of where the channel used to be. and so you can tell that the channel was migrating from over here, over and finally you can see here's meander scrolls in there, but then once that, channel_ once, the meander got cut off, formed the oxbow lake, you can still see where, where it was and now, it'll probably, migrate in a different, it'll just keep migrating this way but, further south. where the- before, compared to where the oxbow lake was before. swales are areas in between these meander scrolls, where very silty, um materials are ponded up, in between there it's, because water was left to settle there, very fine particles settled out... and then sloughs, are over, here and up high maybe you can see that those are areas that are very they're very wet, and sometimes depending on, the flooding event they can be sort of reconnected and, and they can have active drainage ways through there. but for the most part there's a lot of just organic matter deposited back there, and um, just they're wet areas, where a lo- vegetation gets, able to build up, over time. and that so much of the backswamp, backswamp deposits are very fine organic matter, deposits, very rich deposits, that um, there's actually and i'll show this a little bit in the profile but, there's actually, a slight decrease in the elevation, going away from, the main channel, over towards these terraces. and because of that decrease in elevation, water is able, when water gets splashed over there during the flood event, water remains there, and then, water returns back to the channel or seeps down, but it stays ponded up in those backswamps. and it's very s- it's it's very easy to identify we'll be seeing a really great, backswamp today. the active floodplain, you can see the line up at the top, the active floodplain is called, um the fir- usually the first bottom, in between the levee, and the other terraces we have, the first bottom. not including, that's called the first bottom backswamp cuz it's a backswamp located on the first bottom. so this whole area would be the first bottom, and then up from the first botto- that's the, that's the active floodplain that's the one that's flooding currently. and up from there we have different terraces you can have, second bottom third bottom those are all different terraces, and, um, second bottom can flood sometimes. currently the third bottom rare- rarely ever f- floods. although we'll talk in a little bit about, how human disturbances in the landscape, are starting to alter them a little bit. um but eventually what will happen is the second bottom, will, no longer it will be replaced it will become the third bottom if this channel, gets lower. over time there's incision and, and the channel gets smaller and smaller and smaller. and so what'll happen is that current_ the second bottom will become, or the first bottom will become the second bottom, and then, you'll get a new first bottom, that will occur, there. so it's a constantly changing process. are there, any questions...? (xx) alright. f- and, before we look at a cross section of this, i have this diagram, which shows how humans are kind of starting to alter, these areas and and flooding is a natural, disturbance in these, in- in a floodplain. um and what happens in the- as i- i said before is the way that, the land- the landscape gets rid of excess water. and it really depends on the type of material you have if it's impervious or pervious. and so because we're doing things like agriculture, housing, people wanna live adjacent to the river, but they don't want their hou- their homes to be flooded. and so you have channelization of, of streams. also dams, built for for power. so we have problems there're many disturbances to the floodplain, and these lands form- these landforms, um were b- were alternate landforms in changing the flooding regime. and so what happens is in an effort to, decrease flooding, because people don't want their homes to be affected or th- agriculture, to be affected, there are fewer floods, but these floods are more devastating. and, one of the best ways to understand this is to understand, the trade-off between having surface water runoff, and groundwater, filtration and it being discharged that way. so if you look at that top figure we have a forest. it shows that eighty to a hundred percent of, the water that comes in, is going into the groundwater. and only ten to twenty percent is going over into the channel. and, that's because there's vegetation there the vegetation kind of slows down, the water if there's a really h- a large rainstorm, and it gets a chance to seep back down into the water, cuz it's very pervious. but still about ten to twenty percent will, will drain into the channels, over land. if it's cultivated, you have only about forty to fifty percent actually getting drained down. fifty to sixty percent is making it to the channel so we still have, some vegetation, that might kind of slow the pathway down and it's still, pervious, but not nearly the amount to block it like canopy tree- canopy vegetation would. residential areas where we have, a lot of sidewalks, where we have lawns so, fifty to sixty percent, is gonna make it down, forty fif- to fifty percent is going to go, off into the channel. and if you look at urban cities, zero to ten percent actually gets down into the groundwater to drain. it's all concrete, so ninety to a hundred percent actually, gets drained into the channels. and so, in altering the land- i mean it's important it's, looking at the land use around a particular area, and how we've altered these, river channels and it's important for_ that's why it's important for us to understand the processes that go on there. because, to be sustainable with the environment and to have, agriculture in residential areas, but to understand that, flooding is a natural process and this is how water is transported, away and that's how we get rid of it and, and to alter that as much as we have, has really damaged, the areas around us the f- the floodplain landform. and so it's important for us to try and mimic natural, the way that natural floodplains would work. and so that's what we're, talking about today. are there any questions about this...? here's a picture, showing, some of this doesn't show it that well. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> showing the effect of flooding, in a, residential area. and you can see the cars and, devastation. <PAUSE DUR="0:07"/> okay <PAUSE DUR="0:16"/> alright this will be repetition on what we just talked about most of what we just talked about, but it's looking at it in a different way, looking at a cross section of a floodplain, and so we can look at the topography and how that will be different in these different regions. so we've got the river here the active, river. and then the first bottom extends up to, the second bottom, showing that is the active flooding. the area that's actively flooding, this (i screwed up.) <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> okay. this shows the levee, which has sands and gravels and again how those finer silts and clays get deposited on the other side of the levee. and then, the slough which has the very fine materials in between, in the middle, and then on the other sides of the sloughs often these are found um, these have more sand, and gravel deposits more coarser sediments in there. and sloughs are actually more typical in very large river channels. so we don't really tend to see those that much, um like on the Huron, River which isn't quite as big of a channel. and then you can see that, this goes down in elevation and so, it actually the water will settle down back here when, all the other water, gets r- back into the channel or seeps down. the backswamp will be left and this is where, gets, water's able to settle out w- the fine- very fine materials are settling out, and then you'll have characteristic vegetation back there, swampy areas. and um, yeah, let's see what else. okay so, did somebody have a question? okay, and silts and clays then up here we have the second bottom, third bottom terraces you can even have more terraces than that. but again those will be coarser material, and they're very infrequently flooded. however, because of these increased human disturbances, and we have, less frequency of flooding, but there are, they're more disastrous, we are tending to see nowadays that these third bottoms are getting flooded where, they would have never gotten flooded in a natural, floodplain situation. we have_ and there's an- there's another diagram we'll talk about that more in a minute but there's a diagram showing a cross section of this in your, coursepack, also. on page ninety-seven... okay... so the next thing, is to talk a little bit about how the climate is different in these floodplain areas and how that affects the vegetation growth. <PAUSE DUR="0:11"/> okay, so, one thing that we've hit on a little bit when we talked about the lake plain is how, um, the the types of species that are growing there, the lake plain is one of the warmest areas, in Michigan climactically. and so we have a lot of species growing there that are seen further to the south, and they're able to, to grow there because of this difference in climate and so, on the floodplains that are located within the lake plain, the hardiness zone mimics that, of one just further to the south. so we see a species that are growing there, uh like Redbud, and, Kentucky Coffee Tree, other species that are very much typical of the South but they're naturally growing there, because of a difference, um. and, this relates to... to the vegetation and it's important to understand looking at, you wanna look at climate how the physiography in the floodplain, is different and how that affects the vegetation but it's important to understand, something that triggers, the vegetation to flush out, and what that is is heat sum. okay and so heat sum is just, the accumulation of heat that allows, um plants to, to flush out. and plants will flush, out depending on, um once they reach a certain threshold, of this accumulated heat. and, what this means is that metabolically, plants will be active if, they accumulate so many hours above either five degrees Celsiu- Celsius or forty degrees Fahrenheit. okay, actually, i kind of forget, i (would put) it on the board. let me do that. it's easier to understand... okay. so the heat sum, is accumulated heat over a certain threshold... and if you look, at for example a mean temperature, if plants are experiencing a mean temperature of sixty degrees, for five hours on a particular day, then sixty degrees Fahrenheit, that's twenty degrees, Fahrenheit over forty degrees. okay so they have to at least reach forty degrees to become metabolically active. and this is, twenty degrees Fahrenheit over that, for five hours. so you multiply twenty degrees Fahrenheit, greater than forty, times five hours which is h- a hundred degree-hours. and different plants have different degree r- degree-hour requirements, before they will flush out. but it's important to understand, that that is what triggers flushing in the spring. is that confusing, are there questions about that...? okay yes. </U>
			<U WHO="S4"> why did you subtract, the forty from the sixty? is that the forty is like the threshold? </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> forty is the uh, forty is a threshold where, plants won't really be meta- they won't be metabolically active, until it's forty degrees Fahrenheit. and then once it starts getting warmer, then it's like well it can't just be you know a really nice day in February, for f- for plants to flush out but they have to, accumulate so much heat over a particular you know time period. so then they know that well it s- it's safe enough in this region that i'm not gonna be susceptible to late spring frost. i'm putting, human, vocabulary <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> on these plants. but, basically they're adapted to the environment where they grow and so they know th- that if they, can reach so many heat hours, that, depending in this climate, that's when they'll be able to flush out with very low risk, of getting frosted out. so yeah it has to be above forty degrees Fahrenheit, and then they accumulate these hours over time. so, one day they might have, you know, sixty degrees for five hours, another day, it might only be fifty degrees for for five or ten hours or something, so that'd only be ten hou- ten degrees above the threshold. and you'd multiply ten degrees, times however many hours that (were) and so then that would be added to, the hundred degree-hours from before. okay, does that make sense, yeah. </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> and then if it gets cold, does that, so, i guess, looking at the heat sum, they're accumulating but then if it gets cold, does it subtract from that or <OVERLAP> does it just stay? till it gets warm again. </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S3">
				<OVERLAP> no, uh- i- it just </OVERLAP> it just stays. they've got it. you know and it's a couple_ exactly that's why, a couple weeks may go by and they're like oh, good thing we didn't flush out. so um, yeah, it just stays, a part of them and, um they have to reach so many degree-hours and i think it's probably, you know in a very safe zone the deg- the number of hours that they are required to reach, is high enough such that, it typically won't h- won't occur unless, it's springtime. <PAUSE DUR="0:14"/> okay, so it's important to understand, the heat sum and how that relates to, seasonal differences and how the physiography, affects that, in the river floodplain. so this top diagram shows, here's the sun in early April, not a lot of direct sunlight right into the bottomland right into the channel, you know direct sun is hitting over here, and so the upland species are receiving, six hours at fifty degrees. okay fifty degrees is ten hou- ten degrees above that threshold, so, on a partic- you know a given day in April they might, accu- start to accumulate sixty, degree-hours on a particular day. you compare that to the bottomland species though, right, adjacent to, the river, they're at five hours only at forty-seven degrees. so it's cooler down there, seven degrees above the threshold, so at five hours times seven degrees, um thirty-five, degree-hours. so, in early April those plants that are right adjacent to the river, aren't accumulating as much heat, as those plants that are upland. where they're getting the direct sunlight... then if we compare this to May. so, what happens is these upland species, will flush out sooner than, the species that are present in the bottomland, but, those upland species might be more susceptible if there is a late spring frost. so, these species down here are kind of buffered by risk of a late spring frost because they don't flush out as soon. now if we look here's in May when, more overhead direct sunlight, the upland species, averaging fifty, degrees for thirteen hours, so thirteen times ten degrees above that threshold, that's a hundred and thirty, degree-hours. if you compare that to the bottomland where now we have, direct sunlight, but we also have what's called re-radiation, because of the physiography and because of, these terraces, there actually, the sun is able to reradiate, off of these, terraces, and so, twelve hours at fifty-five degrees Fahrenheit, that's a hundred and seventy degree-hours. so now they're receiving more. and this is something that's, very advantageous to plants because, early in the spring, they're not gonna flush out as soon but later into the fall, these plants will actually be stay, active, it'll stay warm down there and they'll be able to, be really active much longer. yeah. </U>
			<U WHO="S6"> what about like cold air flowing down into the valley. <U WHO="S3">
					<OVERLAP> okay </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> does that </OVERLAP> affect em at all? </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> well it does but the difference is that when you're adjacent to a river, so the channel's really open, it's not windy down there and cold air is able to be, you know breezed out of there. and also because we're adjacent to water, it's more humid, and there are site conditions that, during the day it's not as hot, because you're adjacent to the water, and there's cool, cool air that stays adjacent to- above_ cool air masses above the water, it stays adjacent there, but then over the d- the day the water takes a long time to warm up, but eventually it does and at night, it's actually warmer air masses over that water. okay so it's it's moderated in that sense too not only, is it a seasonal moderat- seasonally moderated, but daily, it's- the days aren't as hot, and the nights aren't as cold. so it's sort of a double double whammy there. plants, are have, you know, there's a- this is great climatically for plants down in, this, bottomland. are there other questions about that? so everybody understand the concept of accumulated heat, for flushing out...? did you have a question Norman...? okay, so that is just looking at, the climate and because of this we have a lot of different microclimates, located in the river floodplain. uh looking at that profile, you notice th- it's very, much there's a lot of ups and downs in there. so we have, a little microclimate similar to what we saw in the lake plain, but even more on a larger scale. <PAUSE DUR="0:05"/> okay, so that's looking at the climate. next i wanna talk, about the soils, that are present in, the floodplain but we haven't really talked about soils very much in this class as of yet, and i had you read pages ninety and ninety-one in your coursepack for today, so, i'm going to start and kinda_ we'll give a brief talk about that page, and then talk about how that relates to, the soils that are present in the river floodplain <PAUSE DUR="0:09"/> okay, so, looking at this we have, this o- this over here, people have probably seen or, talked about before, the horizons of the soil or this is also called the soil profile. and this occurs because, there's downward movement of water, through the substrate okay through the parent material. and, one thing i think that, is confusing is that, people tend to think that, these layers are getting added, to the the top of the parent material that was there, so if you think about after the glaciers left, and there was an outwash plain or something. well, whatever that outwash plain this down here is called parent material, but this whole thing at one point was the parent material. it's all the mineral, what's now called the mineral horizons. and it's not that these, horizons are getting added on top it's because of this downward mo- movement of water, through the parent material, it actually brings different things it, it chemically alters it can chemically weather the soil, and it can add, if the vegetation is there, it can, add organic material humus and it can push, these materials through there. so it's a downward movement, and different processes that we'll talk about, and the only thing that gets added, is up at the top these organic layers are, are literally from the litter of vegetation. but you have s- there are soil, profile there's soil profile development, even if vegetation wasn't there. when the glaciers left, there's chemical weathering there's acid, present, naturally in rain water, and as this percolates through, through what that parent material was, it starts to alter it and creates these different horizons. so, up on top we have the organic horizons which are O-I O-E O-A, and they're differentiated based on their amount of, decomposition. so O-I is very, much you can see it it's litter you can almost, you can usually identify what it is. O-Es, you can't really identify it, but it's kind of gritty, and O-A, is extremely decomposed matter, that's often almost, oftentimes greasy, in nature. so those are the organic materials and that is because they're, it's material getting deposited on top. but all all, the rest of this was parent material at one point, and, it creates these different horizons, now called mineral horizons, based on different processes. so the A horizon, has a- it's dark often and because it has a large amount of, of humus coming from these organic layers, so it's discoloring the very top part of the parent material, and the the big thing here is, the zone of mixing this is considered the zone of mixing. earthworms often present in the A, horizon, so stuff is being mixed from, the organic material getting mixed in, so that's why it has this dark appearance. the next one is the E horizon which stands for eluvial. that's another way of saying, it's the zone of leaching. materials are getting leached from this area, and they're getting deposited, in this B horizon, which is the zone of deposition. so it often has a reddish color where clays are accumulated there, because, this downward motion, this percolation through there, is um, allowing different oxides to accumulate, in this B horizon. get leached from the E, so it's often very light colored, whitish, down into B this zone of accumulation. and then the C horizon is just what's called, parent material. that's unaltered parent material. so it hasn't been affected by any of these other processes. that's what you would've seen, all the way up to this top here. we could've, seen it after the glaciers left. okay so that's a little bit about how, the soil profiles, how they get formed. and then there's six major soil orders... and um there's other ones too but these are the major ones that we'll talk about. so entisols are ones, that have very little profile development. they're new soils, so there's not much of this development yet, in entisols. and you see these on dunes and also alluvials, so river floodplains_ the direct, river floodplain that's very new, will have an entisol. the next one is an inceptisol and that, is a recent soil, profile development, but it's not quite as new as entisol. so we have um very, very little accumulation in the B horizon, but we have a little bit more development up higher, in the A and the E, and, this is characteristic of older alluvium. so if you think of the second bottom and third bottom, those old river terraces, those would be inceptisols. cuz they're not quite as fresh as the current floodplain, but they're still they're alluvial soils, haven't had that much time to develop. another type of soil is a mollisol, and this is characterized by very very rich, very black, soil. and you see this a lot in prairie vegetation very thick, masses of, of grass, um are stuck down in that vegetation. so it has very thick A horizons, and they're very dark. and so in the prairie- in areas that would've been prairie around here, we do have, um mollisols but this is like the characteristic one, over like out in the um, central United States. alfisols are very common in, southeastern Michigan, and these occur where, there's warm site conditions very rapid, decomposition and mixing, s- medium to high nutrients, and that's very typical of a forest in temperate climates so a lot of the forests around here, have alfisols. and in spodosols, that's a order that's typical of northern Michigan, often it's coniferous, forests dominated by conifers, and these have characteristically a thick O-E and O-A layers, because there's very limited decomposition so there's a lot of build-up of the organic layers. those are typical of spodosols. and then finally histosols are organic soils, and they develop when there's water saturated, ecosystems such as marshes, bogs, and swamps. and that's a very different, the keyword here is saturated. these sites are saturated, compared to, flooded, and there is a difference. saturated means stagnant water, just sitting there pooling up, where flooding, uh th- is the, periodic process of water coming on, to the floodplain and then leaving again. and so these histosols are typically more than thirty-five percent organic matter. just, it's just sitting stagnant in the water. and another thing about alluvial soils, um these two especially, they're very rich. and oftentimes the soils can be either circumneutral, or or basic. they're very calcareous. and that's um because of those, clays that are abundant in the river floodplain, in those areas where they're able to settle out the clay's is pulled up, in the nutrient (colorways.) <PAUSE DUR=":05"/> okay so we've talked about the climate of the river floodplain, and how great that is for plants. looking at the soils these are very rich soils, present on the first bottom and the second bottom, so the soils are really good for plants too. so this is, pretty much, win win, except we have to talk about, the vegetation growing there, and how the only thing that they have to really worry about, is the flooding, and that the vegetation that's growing there is actually has to be adapted to, this flooding regime. because everything else is there so great so of course, the vegetation would want, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> to be able to grow there. okay so th- here i've drawn, just so you can mark on that page (xx) what page... page ninety-seven, you can write that first bottom entisol is very new, inceptisols second and third bottoms is the older of the alluvial, soil, and then alfisols, mollisols. um, this is pointing upward because that's what would be present in southeastern Michigan, but if we were along the river floodplain in northern Michigan i- it might be a spodosol because that's what the surrounding area, order would be like. so, what's adjacent to this is all dependent on where the river, is located. so this just refers to southeastern Michigan. and then the other thing i wrote on here were some of the characteristic, species that are found here, and um like i said the vegetation that grows here has to be adapted, to this very high, level of water, when there's flooding stages and so, one of the things you'll see oftentimes is buttressing, the base there's like these little, knees and we'll get to see it today that the, uh, the vegetation kind of grows on stilts, because of high water levels, and um, also there's a l- another um, disadvantage to living here is that, for a lot of the time, very low oxygen, concentration because, it's flooded. and so that's another thing that a vegetation's adapted to low oxygen concentrations. and an interesting thing is that because, this is a highly disturbed site, lots of water, very low oxygen, the, the species that are growing here, are oftentimes ones that you see around town characteristically for, landscaping because they can tolerate a lot of, stress, they can tolerate low oxygen, so, they'll plant them where there's a lot of cement because they know that, they can tolerate urban stresses, and um, some of the smog and different pollution that goes along, they're adapted now to, grow in cities, and um low oxygen, because they're growing in cement as well. so, some of these species, talking about the the trees that are present there in the first bottom there's three characteristic species, that are typically seen on the first bottom. one is, <FOREIGN> Ulmus americana, </FOREIGN> the other one <FOREIGN> Fraxinus pennsylvanica, </FOREIGN> and <FOREIGN> Acer saccharinum. </FOREIGN> so <FOREIGN> Acer saccharinum </FOREIGN> is, the Silver Maple, and <FOREIGN> Fraxinus penn </FOREIGN> is the, Red Ash, and then we have the American Elm. so those are three dominant species, of the river floodplain, on the first bottom. and, looking at the um levee, a lot of times you'll see <FOREIGN> Platanus sycamore </FOREIGN> growing on the levee. and then, we have in the slough different salix, different species of salix can grow there. and also out on the point bar, <FOREIGN> Populus deltoides </FOREIGN> cottonwoods, and oftentimes it's it's Black Willow, growing out on the point bars where, you have that deposition, in the meandering river. so those are some of the typical overstory species. in terms of the shrubs that are present there, there aren't as many, shrubs, present right in, the floodplain because of, the uh the uh, large amount of stress there. so sometimes right on the levee you'll see, different cornuses different dogwoods, um but for the most part, the shrubs don't have the ability to withstand, such as as large amount of flooding as the trees do. so another thing that we see here instead, is, a lot of vines. cuz they don't have as much competition from shrubs, it's very open, and so we'll see things like, Poison Ivy and Riverbank Grape, and Virginia Creeper and even different types, of smilax species of smilax, growing, um in the river floodplain. and there are sometimes characteristic, lower understory, um species but not as many shrubs. sometimes in the backswamp you'll get, um, it's more open, there aren't as many trees or they're not as dense growing back there, so (buttonbush) can often grow back in the back swamp. and then today what we'll be doing is looking at a lot of the herbaceous vegetation, that is adapted to this, and some of the um, vegetationally, a lot of the plants that are growing here are adapted to grow, and vegetate, will reproduce vegetatively. so, um a lot of these plants have, their water dispersed, and if parts fall off, from like fragmentation of the willows, and also the cottonwood if, parts fall into the water, they can get washed downstream and have the ability, to grow just from that one part if there's, um, primordia, present in that in that stem or in that branch that fell off. and for the herbaceous species there's a lot of bulbs and corms, and underground stems rhizomes, that have the same thing because, they're dormant in the spring when it floods, so they're not really affected by that and if they get washed away, then they'll just, grow somewhere else. so we'll see those today like the green dragon, and you'll see, ginger, and um, and <FOREIGN> Matteuccia struthiopteris, </FOREIGN> you'll see a lot of, vegetation that's characteristic here. and um, at the same time though you have to be careful about, vegetation that is characteristic of floodplains, and vegetation that, you just, it's growing there but it grows a lot of other places. so it's kind of like the lake thing there're some things, that're always found there but a lot of things, that're just growing there because it's very suitable, the site's very suitable... anyone have any questions about that? any of the vegetation? okay. then i just finally wanted to show you, this diagram i put up before about, the areas that we've gone in lab and where we're going. so, um, we talked about the first two already number three, was down at the glacial lake plain which is off this map. and um then, last, Thursday we went to Sharon Hollow, which is a combination of ground moraine, and outwash. and then today this shows the location of the lower Huron River floodplain, where we'll be, be going. and, i think we even have slides, to review, some of the, plants that we saw at Sharon Hollow. so before we start the slides does anyone have any questions? </U>
			<PAUSE DUR="0:24"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> could you guys close the, shades in the back, <U WHO="SU-m"> no </U> please? <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
			</U>
			<PAUSE DUR="0:11"/>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> (just wanted to know if) you know, are we supposed to get rained on today? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah, all day. that's good for mosquitoes though. i mean, good for, not having as many mosquitoes. <PAUSE DUR="0:06"/>
				<EVENT DESC="BEGIN SLIDE PRESENTATION"/> what's this, what do we have here? good- this is good quiz review people. <U WHO="SU-m">
					<OVERLAP> Cancer Root? </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> we have </OVERLAP> a quiz at um actually i should say that, the quiz is gonna be in here again. um we'll start around, a little after one one oh five one ten, and uh, there'll be fifteen plants just like last time so if this is on there what would you say? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m">
				<FOREIGN> Conopholis americana. </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> Conopholis americana, </FOREIGN> right? what's the, common name? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Cancer Root? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Cancer Root. and the family? a family that's all, um, wholly parasitic? <U WHO="SS"> Orobanchaceae </U> Orobanchaceae, exactly. </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Rattlesnake fern.
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Rattlesnake fern yeah. now how do you know it's not <U WHO="SU-f"> a sort of fern? </U> something else? <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> how do you know it's not another um, a a <FOREIGN> Botrychium oneidense </FOREIGN> or <FOREIGN> Botrychium dissectum. </FOREIGN> it looks pretty dissected to me. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> and it's not as leathery. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> it's not as leathery so at the touch. and then this is the key thing. <U WHO="SU-f"> the fertile frond? </U> the fertile frond. <OVERLAP> so (because) </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-f">
				<OVERLAP> isn't it always gonna have </OVERLAP> the fertile frond? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> no it won't always have the fertile fronds um, uh, i mean, generally when we we quiz you we try to, give you that stuff but the feel of it is much different, as well. if you s- for example if you had this, in a vegetative, (forunno,) fertile part, and you have <FOREIGN> Botrychium dissectum, </FOREIGN> also, without any fertile part you could tell by the, the difference in the feel, much thicker. yeah. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> um are the other Botrychiums that like triangle shape? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah they are. <U WHO="SU-f"> they are? </U> and that's a good character for um, these are actually the only three Botrychiums that we're gonna do and they're all, that sort of deltoid shape, which is really a good, good (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<FOREIGN> Adiantum pedatum </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> Adiantum, pedatum. </FOREIGN> what's the family? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Adiantaceae </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Adiantaceae. and the common name? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Maidenhair Fern? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Maidenhair Fern. excellent. <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> what's this? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Sensitive Fern. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah exactly. you guys are good. this is Sensitive Fern. <U WHO="SU-f"> Onoclea </U>
				Onoclea very sensitive. <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
				<FOREIGN> Onoclea sensibilis. </FOREIGN> um, and what's the family? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> An Apiaceae? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> An Apiaceae yeah so this, this cau- i- the first frost, it's down and that's why it's, has it's common name and, and uh, species name. ooh is that someone's finger? or <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> someone's sort of hairy finger? <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> this is, what? </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				sanguinaria
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				sanguinaria. sang- <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> (san- veria.) what's the- what's the name for blood in Spanish? </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<FOREIGN> sangre? </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> sangre. </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> sang- <FOREIGN> sangria? </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> sangria. </FOREIGN>
				<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> lots of things <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> associated with (this) so. this is um, Bloodroot very good name. um, what's the family? the whole family has these, these sort of latexy um, colored latex, little </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> Papaveraceae </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Papaveraceae right. it's the poppy family. so i- you know opium comes from the um, the latex of the poppy, of the poppy plant. same stuff i don't know if you (you've heard) enough of this (on Fri-) <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> this is it this is so, great so we're taking you to the back a little, in time here because, you don't get to see it flower because it flowers, really like the first week of April almost, um, it's very early. and when it comes up this is a nice little patch. i think i explained to my group that when it comes up the leaves even more so than this are curled around the flower and the flower comes out, in between basically and then it's this beautiful white flower with yellow, pretty showy yellow stamens and it dies back, to form the fruit. so it- it is often in these nice little clumps. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> Hydrophyllum? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what's that? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> Hydrophyllum? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> n- oh this is still Bloodroot, sorry. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> oh that's a <OVERLAP> Bloodroot </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-f">
				<OVERLAP> oh </OVERLAP> this is Bloodroot? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Bloodroot i'm sorry. can't you tell? <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
				<U WHO="SU-f">
					<EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
					<OVERLAP> yeah </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> this is </OVERLAP> yeah this is Bloodroot. um, <OVERLAP> Sanguinaria canadensis </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-m">
				<OVERLAP> are those petals? </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> those are petals the white parts are petals yep. very showy flower, Papaveraceae. so and this is what it looks like when- we're doing a little, stroll down, Sanguinaria, avenue. this is the, um, the leaf. obviously. many lobes very, distinctive, in its sort of orbicular shape with those, strange lobes. and then this is the fruit, and it's opened up and those are the seeds inside, the little pod. <U WHO="SU-f"> huh, yeah </U> what's this? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Bishop's Cap, mitella
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-m">
				<OVERLAP> my favorite flower </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> Bishop's Cap yeah. </OVERLAP> mitella
				<U WHO="SS">
					diphylla
				</U>
				diphylla. w- and it's called diphylla because, of these two leaves on the, the scape the flowering stem. but it also has basal leaves so, don't forget about those and here's a, nice close-up, <U WHO="SS"> ooh </U>
				<U WHO="SU-f"> nice </U> of the petals if you didn't get to see them. <U WHO="SS"> aw </U> it's goo- aw. <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> you know, just for kicks um, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> this plant is also perigynous. this family's perigynous actually but we a- we don't, make you, memorize that um. so you can kind of see that it has a little cup, formed there and then, the petals come off, and then there's te- so this is actually a, a five-five, ten-two, floral formula you can't really_ see if we can focus on that one up there... uh nope. so it's got, five sepals five petals ten stamens, you can count them up. one two three, four five six, seven eight nine ten. and the two carpal- you can't see it very well. two carpals, but we'll see the fruit on this. and you can see it opens up, (xx nice) two carpals. oh <U WHO="SS"> Squirrel Corn. </U> squirrel corn. little yummy piece of corn down there. someone tried to eat one one year. <U WHO="SU-f"> ew </U>
				<U WHO="SU-f"> oh God </U> so this always happens so, <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> please, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> resist the urge... what's the what's the uh what's the </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> didn't make it to the finals </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> didn't make the finals </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah didn't make it to the finals right. lost him out at Sharon Hollow. um, <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> what's the what's the uh scientific name here this could be on your quiz, what's the scientific name of this? </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<FOREIGN> Dicentra canadensis </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> Dicentra canadensis </FOREIGN> exactly and the family? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Fumariaceae </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Fumariaceae exactly. and here's the other one. </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> this is <FOREIGN> Dicentra cucullaria </FOREIGN> and look at this wait prepare yourself, for this next slide </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> oh </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> those are the flowers. so don't they look like little pants, <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> hanging upside down? that's why it's called, Dutchman's Breeches. <U WHO="SU-f"> they're cute </U> they are cute. so you've missed em for this year but, next year... okay this is kind of a tricky one. <OVERLAP> what the heck is this? </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-m">
				<OVERLAP> (dethery fall) </OVERLAP> Solomon's Seal? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> no, although that's a good guess. <EVENT WHO="SU-f" DESC="LAUGH"/> it's actually it's i'll give you a small hint it's not from last it's not from Sharon Hollow. it's from the lab before that.... so so what- what a- wh- wh- what'll ha- let's just analyze <U WHO="SU-f">
					<OVERLAP> i think it's (belbus cross) </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> what we're looking at here. </OVERLAP> what is this? what are we looking at? wha- i mean what are the structures? what's this? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> the white stuff? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> the white stuff. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> come on make an educated guess here. you're all e- educated. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> it's a what? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> Anemone? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> anatomy? <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> Anemone. hey, right family, right family so you're looking at showy </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> sepals? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> not- no </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> stamens </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> no </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> stigmas </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> stigmas, showy stigmas. what has showy stigmas, as the sort of, most showy part of the plant? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> is that, Hydrastis?</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> nope not Hydrastis. this is, very cruel. okay. <EVENT WHO="SU-f" DESC="LAUGH"/> it's Thalictrum.</U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<OVERLAP> oh </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-f">
				<OVERLAP> this is the Thalictrum? </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> oh <FOREIGN> Thalictrum dioicum </FOREIGN> it's it's uh unisexual, and uh (this is really close) this is very up close. so i have a feeling, a few of you didn't get to see it, this well in the field. but this is what it looks like, um, this is a female plant, with showy stigmas. ah </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> ah, oh </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what's this? </U>
			<EVENT DUR=":05" DESC="UNINTELLIGIBLE SPEECH"/>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> i don't know what it is. </U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> Actaea, pachypoda. pachypoda. </FOREIGN> um <FOREIGN> Actaea pachypoda </FOREIGN> and it's uh what family is it in? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Ranunculaceae </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Ranunculaceae it's called White Baneberry. um may have told you that another common name is Doll's Eye, and there's the eye of the Doll's Eye so it's got a white berry with a, black top. it's a little creepy, sometimes too so (if i-) but p- i'll tell you what pa- y- does anyone know what pachypoda means? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> sounds like pachyderm. <OVERLAP> like it </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> sounds like </OVERLAP> what? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> i always think elephant when i say it. cuz it's like <OVERLAP> pachyderm, pachy- </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> oh pachy- yes </OVERLAP> well actually, it's it's the sa- it's named the s- similar. i think pachy means thick, and poda means foot. and, so, before i trip on this thing, this there's two um actaeas and we're only gonna take this one, <FOREIGN> Actaea pachypoda </FOREIGN> and <FOREIGN> Actaea rubra </FOREIGN> and in <FOREIGN> Actaea rubra </FOREIGN> the, pedestals are really fine and delicate and in in <FOREIGN> Actaea pachypoda </FOREIGN> they're thick. <U WHO="SU-f">
					<OVERLAP> oh </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> so that's the the thick, </OVERLAP> foot, part... ahh. </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> May Apple </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> May Apple. what's the family? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Berberidaceae </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Berberidaceae which is the same family as </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Blue Cohosh </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Blue Cohosh which is </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<OVERLAP> Caulophyllum thalictroides </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> Caulophyllum thalictroides </OVERLAP> what's the uh so we al- uh this is </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<FOREIGN> Podophyllum peltatum </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yes exactly. <FOREIGN> Podophyllum peltatum. </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SS"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what's that? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> Downy Solomon's Seal </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> Downy Solomon's Seal yep. scientific name? </U>
			<U WHO="SS"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> (melaeic) yep. <FOREIGN> Polygonatum pubescens </FOREIGN> in the liliaceae. ooh a trick plant. take a close look at this. you'll be seeing it, sometime like this in this form this is tricky. <U WHO="S3"> don't tell em. </U> i'm not gonna tell em. </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> look at the stamen. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what's going on with the stamens just, you know, observationally? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> Wild Geranium? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> it's not Wild Geranium... </U>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> is it the Hairy Sweet Sicily? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> no, not Hairy Sweet Sicily. <PAUSE DUR="0:05"/>
				<U WHO="SU-f"> i'm stumped </U> okay what if i <OVERLAP> show you this next </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-f">
				<OVERLAP> oh. large (xx) </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1"> large (xx) no. okay here's- here's a quick hint but you gotta, you gotta look at it fast. </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> you wanna see it one more time? okay ready? </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> ah </U>
			<EVENT WHO="S1" DESC="LAUGH"/>
			<U WHO="SU-m"> oh the Great Water Leaf </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> the Great Water Leaf <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> exactly, exactly. what's the k- what's the scientific name? </U>
			<U WHO="SS">
				<FOREIGN> Hydrophyllum appendiculatum </FOREIGN>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<FOREIGN> Hydrophyllum appendiculatum </FOREIGN> exactly. and uh, it's in the hydrophylaceae so, it's really important, on these plants <U WHO="SU-m">
					<OVERLAP> there's no water spots on those leaves </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> is that, as they get bigger- </OVERLAP>
				<EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> i know exactly as they get bigger, the leaves lose those water spots they don't, <U WHO="SU-m">
					<OVERLAP> oh, g- great </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> have the same. so you always have to look </OVERLAP> basal and become familiar with this, um sort of oddly sh- it's almost like a maple, you know like a, sloppy maple shaped leaf. very pubescent, um but make sure you look at the base, uh, which have the water-stained leaves. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> can you go back to uh, can you go back one? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> sure, this one, or the one before? </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> on the, um, on the, on adult (appendiculatum) the stamens are longer than the, petals. </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> longer <OVERLAP> than what? </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> yes. </OVERLAP> exerted stamens. </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> exerted they're kind of (xx) sticking out there. the other thing is too, (drain leaf is more,) cut into pieces and is more together. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah, yeah, that's uh true. okay, so quiz at, one ten. and you are free to go. </U>
			<EVENT DUR=":21" DESC="UNINTELLIGIBLE SPEECH"/>
			<P> {END OF TRANSCRIPT} </P>
		</BODY>
	</TEXT>
</TEI.2>
