<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "\\lsa-f4\eli\micase\Transcripts\AllTextsXml\micase-prag.dtd">
<TEI.2 ID="les500ju136">
	<TEIHEADER>
		<FILEDESC>
			<TITLESTMT>
				<TITLE> Honors Intro Psychology Lecture </TITLE>
				<TITLE> Rackham Div: SS </TITLE>
			</TITLESTMT>
			<PUBLICATIONSTMT>
				<PUBLISHER> Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English, English Language Institute, University of Michigan </PUBLISHER>
				<IDNO> LES500JU136 </IDNO>
				<AVAILABILITY>
					<P> The MICASE project is owned by the Regents of the University of Michigan, who hold the copyright.  The database has been developed by the English Language Institute, and the web interface by Digital Library Production Services.  The original DAT audiotapes are held in the English Language Institute and may be consulted by bona fide researchers under special arrangements.  The database is freely available at this website for study, teaching and research purposes, and copies of the transcripts may be distributed, as long as either this statement of availability or the citation given below appears in the text.  However, if any portion of this material is to be used for commercial purposes, such as for textbooks or tests, permission must be obtained in advance and a license fee may be required.  Furthermore, some restrictions apply on the citation of specific portions of some of the transcripts in educational presentations and publications; all such restrictions are noted at the end of this statement.  For further information about copyright permissions, please contact Dr. Sarah Briggs at slbriggs@umich.edu. </P>
					<P> The recommended citation for MICASE is: R. C. Simpson, S. L. Briggs, J. Ovens, and J. M. Swales.  (1999) The Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English.  Ann Arbor, MI:  The Regents of the University of Michigan </P>
					<P> RESTRICTIONS ON CITATION OF EXAMPLES:  NONE </P>
				</AVAILABILITY>
			</PUBLICATIONSTMT>
			<SOURCEDESC>
				<RECORDINGSTMT>
					<RECORDING DUR="49">
						<DATE> February 20, 2001 </DATE>
						<EQUIPMENT>
							<P> TASCAM Digital Audio Tape Recorder with two external microphones </P>
						</EQUIPMENT>
						<RESPSTMT>
							<NAME> Shannon Dubenion-Smith </NAME>
							<RESP> Recording </RESP>
							<NAME> Shannon Dubenion-Smith </NAME>
							<RESP> Transcribing </RESP>
							<NAME> Jessica Rett </NAME>
							<RESP> Rechecking </RESP>
							<NAME> Amy Burke </NAME>
							<RESP> Proofreading </RESP>
							<NAME> Rita Simpson </NAME>
							<RESP> Final Editing, 11/13/01 </RESP>
						</RESPSTMT>
					</RECORDING>
				</RECORDINGSTMT>
			</SOURCEDESC>
		</FILEDESC>
		<PROFILEDESC>
			<LANGUSAGE>
				<P> Primary Discourse Mode: MLG </P>
				<LANGUAGE ID="NS"> Native Speaker </LANGUAGE>
			</LANGUSAGE>
			<PARTICDESC>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Students" SIZE="40"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Speakers" SIZE="4"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSON ID="S1" LANG="NS" ROLE="SF, Instructor" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="4"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S2" LANG="NS" ROLE="JU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S3" LANG="NS" ROLE="JU, Student" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S4" LANG="NS" ROLE="JU, Student" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SS" LANG="NS" ROLE="JU, Student" SEX="U" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
			</PARTICDESC>
			<SETTINGDESC>
				<SETTING>
					<P> Classroom, Dennison Hall </P>
				</SETTING>
			</SETTINGDESC>
		</PROFILEDESC>
	</TEIHEADER>
	<TEXT>
		<BODY>
			<U WHO="S1"> um <U WHO="S2"><OVERLAP> yeah </OVERLAP></U><OVERLAP> Sarah, </OVERLAP> huh? <U WHO="S2"> who? </U> Sarah Bruner you? </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> that would be me. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yup, uh i found the article, that uh i actually, i ran into it, this weekend, that uh, supported your point about uh the stereotype threat for white males. uh, didn't you make that point when we were talking about stereotype vulnerability? </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> about, it being helpful to certain groups? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> oh yeah i guess that would, you're right i'm sorry. this is about Asian-Americans. <U WHO="S2"> okay </U> yep and the study, that was done, was done at Northwestern, and what they did was to make, uh they took a group of Asian women, saw how they performed without any particular cues on a test, then they uh cued, identity as females. and this test was something that uh was particularly, male oriented. and the women did worse. then they cued uh, another comparable group, with the uh, cue, Asian, and Asians generally are better at math and this sort of thing, and the women did better, than in the control group. so uh, it was a, positive effect, if you were cued that you're gonna be better than other people, a negative effect uh if you're cued, that you belong to a group that's likely to be worse than another group. so. i think that was the point you were talking about. </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> alright thank you. </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":06"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> there are a couple of uh lectures that are kind of relevant to what we've been talking about there's one this noon, Is There a Development Trajectory to Homicide by Young Males? by Professor Loeber from the Free University of Amsterdam in the Netherlands. and it's going to be at the Center for Human Growth and Development, which is the old s- well it's three hundred North Ingalls Street, uh room one thousand it's up on the tenth floor. so anybody interested, lunch is provided, uh but if you're interested in youth violence uh, uh that'll be an interesting, lecture. then on Friday, there's a seminar on culture and cognition, at ten thirty A-M Friday, by John Jost who's a professor at Stanford on the system justification function of stereotyping, in Italy Israel and the United States. and uh, i assume that's something about uh why stereotyping is maintained by, uh various groups. that's gonna be in thirty forty-eight East Hall ten thirty A-M Friday. <PAUSE DUR=":08"/> we're now kind of at the midpoint of the course. that is we finished, general psychology last week, and developmental psychology, now gets back to whole human beings pretty much, uh general psychology's talking about variables within people, that uh influence their behavior and tries to find general laws that affect, all, human beings regardless of culture and so forth, which turns out to be very difficult to do, uh, and now we get into things that deal much more with, people as persons, and uh their whole characteristics we'll be talking about personality right after the break, developmental psychology is, uh essentially how the person develops. and in general the pace now is going to slow that is, you'll notice we're taking, two sessions on developmental psych we'll take three on personality, uh your reading assignments will drop off in most cases, though it depends somewhat on which book you have on certain topics some books are longer than others, as it has also been the case, previously. so, uh you'll have more time to work on your team research once you get back. today i'm going to try to, do two things, and maybe a third as, i'm going to have you participate in a review exercise, uh which i hope will help you, in uh, getting schemas to, use when you take the midterm on Wednesday, and i wanna talk some about, four or five points in developmental psych_ i think your books cover developmental, pretty well, but these are points that either aren't, mentioned, or that i want to highlight more or at least comment on. so uh, i'll be, giving you the review exercise, about every ten minutes to break up the lecture, so it may seem disorganized but essentially after each topic, or before the first topic, you'll be doing the review exercise. and then if we get time at the end i'll say a little bit about test taking which i talked about earlier, and some of the strategies that should help you on, taking the test or preparing for it. so, first, the review exercise. and this you just do the top page to start with and then the second page about ten minutes later and, so on after that... so now start on the top page and i'll, tell you more about it, later. <PAUSE DUR=":11"/> this is an exercise that should help in building a general schema. and, Ernie Zaremba one of my doctoral students, who teaches psychology at Washtenaw Community College,carried out a neat set of studies, showing that simply taking, something like this, actually helps your performance later in the course, uh on other topics as well as on the topic uh covered. so, it uh, doesn't uh necessarily mean that these terms are actually going to be on the test, but it should help you in getting a framework, and probably also help you later on in the course in terms of, developing schemas relevant, to the rest of the, topics in the course. <EVENT DUR="1:16" DESC="PAUSE WHILE STUDENTS COMPLETE EXERCISE"/> did you get one yourself? <U WHO="S3"> yeah. </U><PAUSE DUR="2:41"/> how many aren't through...? well you can work on it while i talk. the uh, basically what developmental psychologists are trying to do is to find out, what kinds of aspects of development are more or less universal, that are built into our species, and what kinds of things are, pretty much determined by, our culture our parents our environment, uh and uh it turns out most things are an interaction of both. uh even something like height, uh is influenced a good deal by nutrition. the Japanese are taller now than they used to be for example. so, there aren't any, simple answers to the questions that a developmental, psychologist asks and uh, Matti Shawn and Ryan showed you in their, class on Monday, that uh, here's something like, the effect of T-V violence which seems like a fairly simple thing to study, and turns out it's very complex, it affects some children in some situations, to become more aggressive but uh there are a lot of other variables that influence the effect. uh parents, and patterns of child rearing whether the parents are aggressive and or not, peers, uh poverty has an effect uh, so it's hard to untangle any one effect from others. and, most psychologists i should say do agree that uh television violence is on the whole pretty bad, but uh nonetheless that doesn't mean that it's invariably bad or bad for everyone. so the first of the four points that i wanted to make is about, methodology, uh cross-sectional method is essentially, trying to study developmental processes by comparing, five-year-olds with two-year-olds with eight-year-olds and ten-year-olds and so forth, and you take samples, at each of several age, levels, and you assume that the differences between the say the five-year-olds and the eight-year-olds, are a result of the development. but the problem is, that uh, what happens, to an eight-year-old, may be different from what happens to a five-year-old, who becomes eight later. that the environment changes, over time, and thus uh this cross-sectional method, it's the easiest method to use, but uh can sometimes give you screwy results. so, uh most developmental psychologists like to use longitudinal methods. and in longitudinal methods you follow a group, kids or adults, over a period of years. and people don't like to do that cuz it takes a long time to get_ if you're working on a dissertation i tell my students don't, use a longitudinal design because, you gotta wait until, you know five years or something to find out how it comes out, so we need to use some other kind of design, if you're gonna get out of here in any decent period. but the longitudinal design has the advantage that you do see development sequentially, in a given group of people. the problem is, that, the historical period or the culture, that is say the group of people you're following say from ten to nineteen, may be quite different, for one cohort or one group of students than it will be from another group, say ten years later. um my development for example was influenced by the fact that i was a boy during The Depression, i uh World War Two occurred i had to go into the Navy, uh there was the McCarthy Era while i was a young faculty member, a lot of things happened Civil Rights campaign, uh student activism in the sixties the Vietnam War, all of these things influenced my development, and are quite different from the development, uh the events that will influence your development over the next uh, fifty sixty years, from now so longitudinal method has its, problems too. and what psychologists have developed, is what's called the cross-sequential method, which gets around, some of the difficulties of both of these. uh and that's not mentioned in any of your textbooks as far as i can determine cross-sequential is essentially, if i want to study teenagers, i take and what happens say, from twelve to twenty-two say a ten year period. so i start out, and i take a group of twelve-year-olds and fifteen-year-olds and eighteen-year-olds, and say twenty-two-year-olds, and i measure them, all i get measures on all of them so i've got a cross-sectional, analysis, of development from twelve to twenty-two. and then i follow, each of these groups, until they reach twenty-two. so, the eighteen-year-olds i follow four years the fifteen-year-olds, seven years the twelve-year-olds ten years and so forth, so i've got the longitudinal data on them as well. but then in addition to that, each three years say if i'm using a three-year cycle, i pick up a new group of twelve-year-olds and follow them too. so i get rid of the particular historical circumstances, that affected the development of my first group of twelve-year-olds as they, moved up to twenty-two, by, seeing if the same sorts of things happened to a new group as they moved through that period that's called the cross-sequential method. and it's probably better than either of the others and it's more expensive and more difficult to carry out. okay flip over your review sheet and do the second page. <EVENT DESC="3:02 PAUSE WHILE STUDENTS COMPLETE EXERCISE"/> how many aren't finished? okay a couple well you can finish up while we g- why do you suppose i took a break in between having you do the first and second page? anyone have a guess...? basically it's to get, presumably out of your, working memory, what you did on the first page so that you approach the second page more or less, drawing on your long term memory, rather than just kind of repeating, exactly the same thing you did on the first page and that's why we have a different cue word for you to start with in the second page there'll be still a different one on the third page. okay. second topic, is stage, versus, continuity stability versus change, and basically, uh i think it's been well established now for probably, fifty years, that we don't exactly progress ex- the way Piaget thought we did. that is, uh, Piaget had certain set ages, that things were to occur and where certain transitions occurred, and uh it turns out some kids, transition earlier some later actually, some of the things he thought didn't occur till later now we can find as your books show, uh infants are really much better than we ever realized now that we have better methods of studying them, so, that's uh, the stages are helpful i think in giving us a kind of sense of, things that happen in development, but the notion that, development's kind of discontinuous that is that you're in one stage, then you make a s- sudden transition to another stage and so forth, and sometimes i- it is, it does seem kind of amazing, how all of a sudden a child who couldn't do something one day, in a just a little, few days later all of a sudden can do something so, you can see how Piaget got the notion he got it from his own children, that there were a few_ i remember asking Levinson, the mid-life crisis guy once, well does the mid-life crisis have to occur at forty? mightn't it be later say for, academics who don't g- actually, get into their, career until probably thirty or so, as compared with other people who start, say going to work when they're eighteen or twenty? he said nope it's forty years plus or minus one or two well it's not people can, have crises at almost any time, but the problem is, that once you get certain stage ideas into the culture so people believe them, we develop stereotypes. uh if uh, you know if one of my colleagues falls in love with a student at age, forty or forty-five or something people say oh he's going through the mid-life crisis. so we we we lab- use these labels, and uh, kind of take it for granted people get_ teenagers for example. if a teenager, uh, does something the parents don't like they say well it's just teenage rebellion. cuz we've got a concept of adolescence. other cultures don't necessarily have a concept that there's this stage called adolescence. so they don't have these stereotypes, and the stereotypes affect, the people at that particular age and they affect the perceptions of other people at that age. and even though we have these stereotypes not all teenagers are rebellious most men don't experience a mid-life crisis, the transitions don't occur when they're supposed to. what about stability versus change? general notion has been, people pretty much stay the way they are. uh you know you're you, and you're gonna be pretty much the same sort of person the rest of your life. now that you've established your identity, which according to Erickson is what you should be working on now. uh well, uh Baltes and Brim Baltes is at the Max Planck Institute in, Berlin, Bert Brim's now retired and he's head of the Russell Sage Foundation, uh both friends of mine they both uh, they published a whole book on continuity and change what they showed was, that there is some kind of, stability, most people are in the same environment, uh and as long as you're in kind of the same community the same environment. with the same kinds of, peers family pressures and so forth you stay pretty much the same. but on the other hand, there is some kind of continuous development, that probably depends upon your interests, uh you develop more knowledge we've talked about crystallized and fluid intelligence you develop more vocabulary probably if you're in a, a job that requires you to use words, so there's a certain amount of continuity, certain amount of stability, and yet people at any age can change very dramatically probably the most common example, is men tend to die before women. and you f- very frequently find that a woman who's been pretty much a conventional, say homemaker in the old days who, uh acceded to her husband the way the Southern Baptists want their women to do, uh, and who uh, you know never took much responsibility for finances or anything else, uh all of a sudden uh kind of blossoms out, uh finds the strength and uh develops the skills that are necessary to manage her own life very well. uh religious conversions are other examples of people who, make dramatic changes, in their lives so there's always the potential for change. okay go on to the third page of the, ordered tree. <EVENT DESC="2:57 PAUSE WHILE STUDENTS COMPLETE EXERCISE"/> how many aren't through? okay... uh the third topic, i wanna take up, is chance. uh and that i talked about, uh Al Bandura's, uh theory of observational learning, he's probably one of the, maybe the foremost uh kind of, i don't know if you'd call him a personality theory or theorist or developmental theorist or what have you, he's a great guy, and uh, he has emphasized, more than any other psychologist, because psychologists_ are you awake Phil? <U WHO="S4"> i'm sorry </U><EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> okay, looked as if you were about to fall off. uh, the uh, he emphasized this more than any other psychologist probably. even though psychologists keep trying to find all of these, variables that cause behavior in a certain way, he stresses you know no matter how hard we work, there's always the role of chance. you simply we aren't gonna be able to predict all behavior because chance variables play a big role. i keep telling people at basketball and football games they don't realize how much variability there is and how much the outcome depends upon chance. uh some of my best nights, they'd pop things out over the infield and i'd lose a game, some nights when i didn't have much stuff uh they'd hit them all at the fielders and i'd get a no-hitter. so uh, and that's pretty much chance i think. they stick their bats out at the right spot. by accident. anyway, uh Al for instance told me once he said, the thing that got me started on chance was, that the way i met my wife was that i was playing golf, and she was in the foursome behind us and she hit me with a golf ball. <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/> well that that's kind of a chance occurrence. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> you know, uh uh uh actually, uh when i was a senior i didn't date much because i was playing in a bar at Novi on weekends, and i hadn't i decided i'm gonna have a date before i graduate, and we're gonna have a dance uh, in May so toward the end of April i decided there o- uh i was going to ask one of two girls whom i'd admired, probably for four years, without really, interacting with them at all, for a date. well it happened that, we took, a bus out to Lincoln School to do our practice teaching she was doing, well i was doing algebra, and uh my wife was doing, the library, and uh my wife was sitting there waiting. so i asked her for a date and she said yes and a month later we were engaged to be married so uh, uh if the other girl had been there first no telling <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> where (i'd be) what would have happened. uh so chance variables, play a big role, in behavior uh, there's a chapter in a book called the History of Teaching in Psychology about me based on an interview with me, and they titled it I Was Lucky. because i kept saying over and over as they, asked me about things i'd say well i was just lucky. uh i mean i worked too but basically a lot of my career essentially depended upon being, here at a particular time and place and being involved in things_ well i was lucky to survive the war in the first place but anyway a lot of things, are pure luck and bad things can happen as well as good things i mean, uh the book the whole book of Job is about the fact that bad things happen to good people. kay right now uh, sort of thing that uh, kind of came up a little bit in talking about violence on television, is resilience. that is, uh, some people bounce back, from bad events, and uh, become even stronger because of something that happens to them i've heard, people who have had heart attacks say well you know i'm a much better person now cuz i've quit smoking and i'm watching my weight and i'm exercising, and so they bounce back and become stronger as a result of what would ordinarily be considered, a bad event. so chance, is always going to be something that you need to think about when you think about human behavior. okay go on to your fourth, page. and last page. <EVENT DESC="2:29 PAUSE WHILE STUDENTS COMPLETE EXERCISE"/> let me explain to you what you've been doing, uh, when you're through i'd like to have you pass them up to the front uh and uh, you'd probably_ i don't know if we'll use them or not we might analyze_ basically, uh the method, that you've been b- using is the ordered tree method of studying, ways, concepts are structured inside your head. it was developed by Judy Reitman Olson who's now a professor of psychology and business administration, uh and her student Henry Reuter who took her his PhD with her, they studied laboratory, they'd give people lists of words to remember, and then they would give them this exercise, to uh, see which words tended to cluster together, uh in recall, or in ordering actually i think they just had people recall words and looked at the order of recall, rather than uh, than we did, and, write them down. uh i think maybe they did it both ways come to think of it. anyway Moshe Naveh-Benjamin uh my colleague at Ben Gurion University, uh then developed this as a way that he and i could study, learning in courses. and so we've used it now for probably twenty years. uh maybe he's not that old i don't know fifteen twenty anyway, uh, to uh, to study learning in courses, and Ernie Zaremba my doctoral student, uh teaches seven, uh or at least at the time at that we're doing this, was teaching seven sections of introductory psychology at Washtenaw Community College. so he had a chance to really, run, a lot of different variations. and so he, would give this sort of exercise, to one class, and then see what their performance was later on. he'd give it to another class, and then have them do it later in the term. see how they perform. uh, he'd give it to uh, to another class, and then go over the results kind of in a tree such as i've done here, and see what effect that had then he compared that with a group that didn't do it all. well just taking the thing once, as i suggested, uh made a dif- positive difference as compared with those who never saw, an exercise of this sort. uh those who took it twice did somewhat better, uh those who did the best, were those who took it and then had some discussion of the organization, uh and he did it, i think he did it for instance in biopsych, and even though they just discussed the tree in biopsych, these students did better on mental disorders later in the term, than students who hadn't had the tree and the discussion about it. so here is my tree, uh of these, things, and our computer program essentially will print out for each of you, uh using that, uh assuming we get somebody to enter it and get it into the computer sometime, uh something like that for you. uh, uh generally, uh as you go through the term, uh what we find is, that early in the term, uh the concepts are not particularly grouped together. uh you don't i mean you put them more or less randomly all four times and, maybe some of the concepts in psychology go together just in natural language so you get those together. so you have a few little clusters, but it's pretty much just a level, thing with a few pairs here and there, not much of anything else in the computer program. as we go through the term, uh when we give it say, beginning of the term midterm, final, maybe one time in between someplace, uh what happens is, that your conceptual structure gets more and more organized as things get grouped together a little more consistently. and, if the organization, comes out to be similar to that, of your professor, and that's not just in psychology we've done this in biology and, Eng- even in English which is not as highly structured as biology and psychology, uh, the more organized and the more your structure, resembles that of your f- professor, uh the better grade you get. so it seems to be a pretty good measure of, kind of how you're developing the schemas that we talk about, and presumably how well you're able to use them then in answering whatever's on exam questions. any questions about it? okay well pass them on up to the front and i'll collect them. and i'll go onto my fourth topic, which is, children in poverty... uh, this is covered really only in Whiteman of your four textbooks. and i think it's important that you all get it, even though it's not in the other textbooks. we have today thirteen million kids who are in poverty. that's three million more than we had twenty years ago. so, even though the nation's been prospering, uh things have been getting worse for children. uh as i probably mentioned before, a lot of our Congressmen are against abortions but they don't care if kids die or suffer once they're born. uh at least they don't want to appropriate any money for health care well we rank twenty-third or twenty-fourth in the world, in terms of infant mortality. that is we have more k- babies dying, than any other civilized i mean any other Western country. so, we are in bad shape as far as children go. uh we don't, give good education good health care good nutrition, uh other countries provide health care for, pre-natal care for mothers and care for the mother and the child, health care, uh, in infancy we don't do any of that we'd much rather, cut taxes for millionaires than, put any money into the future. uh, and one of the reasons i guess i'm interested in this is this is one of the centers of research on poverty and its effect on children, uh a couple of the professors in social work are among the national leaders, of research in this area uh Danziger and, i forgot Cohen, uh, so we know a good deal about how poverty is related, to children's development. now again let me remind you it's the same way with T-V violence that is, it doesn't affect all children in the same way, and poverty relates to a lot of other things that is, generally speaking probably kids who are poor, are_ spend more time watching television than kids whose parents are taking them to Little League baseball games and, ballet lessons and everything else they can, do so, these things tend to get intertwined. but uh John Hagen of our faculty in psychology and (Fulman,) uh studied poverty, and its effect on children in Detroit, they found that children who're in poverty, were more likely to believe in aggression that is that you should fight, uh you know if somebody's taking something from you, uh there's a neat article in the current issue of the uh Psychologist the uh British journal, that uh left to themselves children in preschools quite often can negotiate and settle things. they do it better than if there's an adult there if there's an adult there they, fight until the adult stops them but uh if they're just by themselves they negotiate. so, children in poverty are more likely, to uh, have favorable attitudes toward aggression, they're more likely to be fearful of violence, i remember uh, a National Academy meeting in Washington some years_ in Chicago, some years ago that a woman from one of the Chicago s- schools. and she said uh the problem for our kids on the south side of Chicago, is that the only place they're really safe, is in the school. the problem is getting them there and back <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> without getting beaten up or, robbed or or taken advantage of along the way. uh they are more likely to approve stealing, uh drug dealing is normal in their situations, uh they have poorer health as i've already mentioned, and that's not necessary uh, wh- uh Lyndon Johnson when he was president conducted a war on poverty, and cut poverty to about fourteen percent, uh now we have about that is fourteen percent of children were reared in poverty, uh now it's about twenty-five percent so it's gone up and uh there's no reason why it should, in a wealthy nation like this. the, let me just give you, one suggestion for your journal. uh that is, uh it would be interesting a- or if you don't do it for your journal do it for your own interest. uh i've done this and it's kind of fun. uh draw a graphic representation of your own development. that is put in kind of critical events, how you've branched out maybe with different kinds of interests at different times, uh people, who had some influence on you, uh you know your parents your peers, aunts and uncles grandparents maybe, uh and if you want to, try to project it into the future and see what kind of critical events or things you think are going to happen in the future. but that would be a good way for you to kind of elaborate, what you've learned about development from your reading so far. if you're interested in developmental psychology, there's a book by two of our, well my former teaching assistants or research assistants Phil and Barbara Newman, which is probably the best-selling developmental psych book, uh there's also a very good one by Mussen and Conger and Kagan, uh if you're interested in continuity uh the book by Baltes and Brim i mentioned Constancy and Change in Human Development's good i've got some readings here quite a few readings on test taking, uh and if you're interested in your own development you might be interested in a book by Holahan H O L A H A N and Sears called The Gifted Group in Later Maturity. and this is a longitudinal study that studied a group of kids who scored in the top one percent, maybe it was the top half of one percent uh highly gifted, kids, uh who were followed over, i think it's maybe sixty years now. uh the last i knew they were still following those who were still alive so, that deals with kind of what happened to people with your range of intelligence. let me summarize. uh, one, methodology, studying things in developmental psychology, uh has problems as you saw in the studies on television, but were able to get, nonetheless i think fairly reasonable evidence that gives you somewhat, more confidence in certain variables that are affecting development, and the better, design you have something like cross-sequential probably would, assure you can be that your results are going to hold up. two, people, tend to be stable, in personality and other characteristics, but uh they still, always have great capacity for change and i think that's what's tended to be underemphasized in our, kind of folklore. third thing poverty's a major problem for the child for children particularly. i mean it's bad for anybody but it just has particularly bad effects on children. and fourth uh, don't forget the role of chance, but that nonetheless, uh even if bad things happen to you you can always bounce back. uh, i don't know for test taking i guess, uh any questions about the test or, strategies to use? there are going to be i think eight multiple choice six short answer, uh an essay, and you'll have your choice of essays, but uh, plan your time because we just have fifty minutes to get it in, uh we'll probably try to pass them out as you come into the room so if you get here, on time you'll have a better chance to finish up. and uh, i guess the main thing is be sure and read the heading if it's a multiple choice question read all of the alternatives in the heading to be sure you've read it. uh i find that one of the things people miss the most is that they pick one of the first two answers, and haven't read the other ones which may turn out to be better and we try to write in seductive alternatives i mean uh alternatives that maybe are partially right but aren't as good. and the same way for essay, tests uh people, underline key words in the essay tests uh, cuz people just forget that they were supposed to have contrasted or compared or done something else. okay good luck on Wednesday. </U>
			<P> {END OF TRANSCRIPT} </P>
		</BODY>
	</TEXT>
</TEI.2>
