<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "micasex.dtd">
<TEI.2 ID="stp285su013">
	<TEIHEADER>
		<FILEDESC>
			<TITLESTMT>
				<TITLE> Multicultural Issues in Education Student Presentations </TITLE>
				<TITLE> Rackham Div: SS </TITLE>
			</TITLESTMT>
			<PUBLICATIONSTMT>
				<PUBLISHER> Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English, English Language Institute, University of Michigan </PUBLISHER>
				<IDNO> STP285SU013 </IDNO>
				<AVAILABILITY>
					<P> The MICASE project is owned by the Regents of the University of Michigan, who hold the copyright.  The database has been developed by the English Language Institute, and the web interface by Digital Library Production Services.  The original DAT audiotapes are held in the English Language Institute and may be consulted by bona fide researchers under special arrangements.  The database is freely available at this website for study, teaching and research purposes, and copies of the transcripts may be distributed, as long as either this statement of availability or the citation given below appears in the text.  However, if any portion of this material is to be used for commercial purposes, such as for textbooks or tests, permission must be obtained in advance and a license fee may be required.  Furthermore, some restrictions apply on the citation of specific portions of some of the transcripts in educational presentations and publications; all such restrictions are noted at the end of this statement.  For further information about copyright permissions, please contact Dr. Sarah Briggs at slbriggs@umich.edu. </P>
					<P> The recommended citation for MICASE is: R. C. Simpson, S. L. Briggs, J. Ovens, and J. M. Swales.  (1999) The Michigan Corpus of Academic Spoken English.  Ann Arbor, MI:  The Regents of the University of Michigan </P>
					<P> RESTRICTIONS ON CITATION OF EXAMPLES:  WARNING -- Citation of examples is restricted for one or more speakers in this transcript.  Permission to cite examples from this transcript in any presentation or publication must be obtained from the English Language Institute. </P>
				</AVAILABILITY>
			</PUBLICATIONSTMT>
			<SOURCEDESC>
				<RECORDINGSTMT>
					<RECORDING DUR="72">
						<DATE> April 16, 1998 </DATE>
						<EQUIPMENT>
							<P> TASCAM Digital Audio Tape Recorder with two external microphones </P>
						</EQUIPMENT>
						<RESPSTMT>
							<NAME> Jesseca Long, Janine Ovens </NAME>
							<RESP> Recording </RESP>
							<NAME> Jesseca Long, Janine Ovens </NAME>
							<RESP> Transcribing </RESP>
							<NAME> Carrie Sue Kay Sulzer </NAME>
							<RESP> Rechecking </RESP>
							<NAME> Marianne Carduner </NAME>
							<RESP> Proofreading </RESP>
							<NAME> Janine Ovens </NAME>
							<RESP> Final Editing, 7/12/99 </RESP>
						</RESPSTMT>
					</RECORDING>
				</RECORDINGSTMT>
			</SOURCEDESC>
		</FILEDESC>
		<PROFILEDESC>
			<LANGUSAGE>
				<P> Primary Discourse Mode: PNL </P>
				<LANGUAGE ID="NS"> Native Speaker </LANGUAGE>
			</LANGUSAGE>
			<PARTICDESC>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Students" SIZE="17"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSONGRP ROLE="Speakers" SIZE="11"> </PERSONGRP>
				<PERSON ID="S1" LANG="NS" ROLE="JG, Instructor" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1">
					<FIRSTLANG> SPA </FIRSTLANG>
				</PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S2" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (Julia)" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S3" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S4" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="ALL" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S5" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (John)" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S6" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (Mary)" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S7" LANG="NS" ROLE="SG, Presenter (Sheila)" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="3"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S8" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (Bob Hooper)" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S9" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (Melissa)" SEX="F" RESTRICT="CITE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S10" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Student" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="S11" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Presenter (Dave)" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SU-f" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Unknown" SEX="F" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SU-m" LANG="NS" ROLE="SU, Unknown" SEX="M" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="1"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SU" LANG="NS" ROLE="UN, Unknown" SEX="U" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
				<PERSON ID="SS" LANG="NS" ROLE="UN, Students" SEX="U" RESTRICT="NONE" AGE="0"> </PERSON>
			</PARTICDESC>
			<SETTINGDESC>
				<SETTING>
					<P> Large Classroom, School of Education </P>
				</SETTING>
			</SETTINGDESC>
		</PROFILEDESC>
	</TEIHEADER>
	<TEXT>
		<BODY>
			<U WHO="S1"> first i uh, i couldn't figure out, what i was gonna, like give you guys, and, i always fall back, on the same thing, which is candy. so... <EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
				<EVENT DESC="PASSES BAGS OF CANDY"/> one going this way. one going that way. um, the plan for today is, for the, the last ten, twelve people to go, to finish, to do their presentations today. then we will um i will give out the course evaluations, um, actually there's, two of 'em. one of 'em is more of an evaluation of me and the course, and the other one is a more of an evaluation of yourself, and what you think you've, you've done in the course. okay? um, the, the one that's more of, y- an evaluation of you, i'm gonna get, and then the evaluation of the course and myself, um, i'm gonna have, i'm gonna need a volunteer to take it downstairs to the, to the main office and just slide it under the door, um to turn in. okay? so, without, further ado i think we will um, <EVENT DESC="STUDENT HANDS HIM SOMETHING"/> oh, thank you. <U WHO="SU-f"> mhm </U> i think, Kathy said that she wanted to go first but, obviously she's not here, <U WHO="S2">
					<OVERLAP> (xx) </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> so we'll go with the first person, </OVERLAP> huh? </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> can i say something really quick? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> yeah </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> i don't know if everyone who's here heard about this recording thing last week but we're taping, and if someone doesn't wanna be taped, please say so before you start and we'll shut it off. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> okay. um, well, before we start does anybody have any questions concerns comments, questions? uh yeah? </U>
			<U WHO="S3"> how do we um get our curriculums back from you? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> i will leave them outside my door in a box. um, i will probably, i'll probably, put everybody's stuff if i have like, any papers, that i have that you may have turned in, i'll put it in one of these <EVENT DESC="HOLDS UP ENVELOPE"/> everybody'll have one so you just look for yours, and it'll be a box, in a box right in front of my door, and, um, oh, i wanna say that by, what's today? today's the sixteenth? by next Friday, morning, everything will be graded. that's my goal. to have everything graded and outside my door, in those brown envelopes, okay? by Friday morning. so you can look for them, after, Friday morning okay? so, any oth- oh, any other questions? next Friday? yeah next Friday not tomorrow, huh'uh. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> huh'uh... okay? and i forgot some of your um, your_ some of you who, turned in your own selections and your, position paper rewrites, i have them upstairs i'll go get them when, we're doing the evaluations. i'll run upstairs and get them and bring 'em down, okay? so, well, any more questions? no, okay, well, the first person to go is actually John, on the list, so </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":12"/>
			<U WHO="S5"> um, i'm gonna present my own own selection today, and uh what i did, uh the title of my project, or paper is called <SEG TYPE="READING"> multicultural identity formation, and the effects of (xx) advertising. </SEG> and what i did basically is i looked at, kinda like what Ben did in a way, i looked at Sports Illustrated and Rolling Stone. um, two magazines that i feel, um, kind of tell who i am, i like sports and i like music, rock and roll. um, and, what i did was i looked through about eight years of Sports Illustrated, i read magazines that i've, kept, cuz i've been reading it for about eight years. and about two years of Rolling Stone and what i did was i looked through um, looked at the ads and looked for um, um looked at the images of the, the the advertisements were, um showing me, um, to see what their assumptions of, um, of what my identity is as a person, someone who might wanna buy their product, and, and how that conflicted with, the own s- my own sense of identity and who i thought, i was, um, as someone reading these magazines buying these products, um, um, i'm gonna just start pass- i'm gonna pass around_ what i did i uh, the uh, the advertisements i cut out and i put this little, um, collection here and what i looked at was, alcohol uh, clothing and cologne. um, and i'll just start passing this around. um... i looked mainly at um gender, and uh, sexuality, messages that came out of these um, these three um types of advertising, and how they, uh were used to sell the products that they were trying to sell um, some of the questions i asked myself, was um, wh- what are these images telling me? um type of person i am, that would wanna buy these products and how do i_ do i see myself that same way? um, and do i conform? so their expectations of me. like, do i buy their products? um, does my identity change in a way from um, uh reading these magazines, um looking at the um advertisements? and i'm just gonna go through one, that uh, one that i looked at was one of the first ones and there's the Budweiser, advertisement for Sports Illustrated. and what the picture um, it's a picture of a guy, uh man he's catching a football, diving, and on the on the left side on the, panel on the left side says um, um <SEG TYPE="READING"> three things you never drop, a touchdown pass, a beautiful woman, a cold Bud. </SEG> um, and it's obvious from, just those three things what they're trying t- they're they're um, i mean they're associating, um women, female sexuality, even uh, sports and um, alcohol. um, and while i while it seems simplistic i think the ad combines a lot of, gender and sexuality messages in an interesting way, um, to me it seems like by associating sports and women, um with beer um they're trying to attract the consumers that they feel will buy, that's reading the magazine that's gonna buy their product, a male heterosexual, um who likes sports, um, and, i- or by associating those all together and putting them in a group it seems to me that they were, they were trying to put all those things together things that, i should, necessarily have, or want, as a as an individual um, and i thought that, that kind of conflicted wh- of the assumptions that i have of myself, in my own, the way i looked at my lifestyle. it seemed to me uh like a presh- uh, i saw the ad as like a pressure on my, my social lifestyle, in a way because it reinforced, like these things that i should necessarily have, like female companionship maybe, and, and maybe when i don't, if i didn't, that'd be um, i could feel incomplete because, they're listing these things all together um, and i also thought that, in a way it degraded women in a way by just lumping them into this category as being, possessions maybe, because sports, beer, those are things that, well they feel that men, um, want or like. um, and i thought it put, it was telling me what all men have, these three things, um, and i thought that it was kind of lumping me, into this category of all men, um, and, that's how i, that's how i saw that. and then i won't go through the rest, but i looked at um, clothing ads, like um... Abercrombie and Fitch Tommy Hilfiger Calvin Klein, Benneton, there was an interesting ad for Benneton in there with the uh, you've seen it the two horses? um, you just you'll see it it's it's it's interesting. um, then i did cologne, and that that that used a lot of, um, uh, sexuality and gender to um, sell their product. basically what i what i came t- what my analysis was of the whole thing was that, i mean um, um these businesses are trying to sell a product and the way they're gonna do that is by attracting, um, this certain type of consumer, who th- they w- they're gonna wanna determine who their buyer is and what shapes, their identity of who they are, and uh, i thought they the- the extent to which advertising messages affect our sense of self is debatable in itself um, but from what i've seen from looking at these, um gender sexuality race, they play out in very deliberate patterns in here to sell um products. um, i couldn't determine if i actually um conform to their, what they thought, the person i thought, um the person they thought i was, but, i buy a lot of those things so, i guess it works. but. so. that's it. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> John, i know you told me a while ago um, when you were doing this that, you're_ you've been a mem- been a subscriber or a member? subscriber, since, eighty-nine eighty-eight i think you said? </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> yeah about ninety. <OVERLAP> eighty-nine </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S1">
				<OVERLAP> yeah </OVERLAP> for um Sports Illustrated </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> yeah. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> do you feel that there's been a change in image, of Sports Illustrated? </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> um </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> like are they being more_ are they putting more in terms of alcohol are they doing more in terms of swimsuit issues are they doing more </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> oh yeah, this, tha- i thought that was um, the swimsuit issue in fact, uh each year, they've put in more swimsuits, and it's been less the magaz- the actual issue has been less, less sports, the swimsuit issue has been less sports each year, and to this year to my surprise i got the issue and, i'm looking through it, i looked fo- i'm looking for the, looking i'm looking for the s- the articles to read, um, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> and i i didn't find any, and i was really confused, it was just, literally i was (flipping through) even the ads were just, women in swimsuits and, i come to find that the whole ad, the whole swimsuit ad, wh- issue is which is really thick, it's just pure swimsuits and then they released a different issue, that was all sports. just the regular issue for the week, just, regular. so, i mean, there is obviously a, a moving trend towards, i mean i don't know w- i don't know what that says but, that's, that's one thing. <PAUSE DUR=":05"/> is that it? alright. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> alright thank you </U>
			<U WHO="S5"> thank you </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> our next victim is Mary. </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":07"/>
			<U WHO="S6"> okay um, i'm gonna be doing my curriculum guide and i'm gonna go through it um, first i'm gonna go, um go over how i approached choosing my topic and then why i chose it and then i'm gonna go through my lesson plan and some of my resources. um, first off um, i wanted to do a topic related to science because i'm in the elementary education program, and i'm majoring in science so i wanted something that i could, you know hopefully use in the future. so um, i didn't know exactly, specifically what topic in science i wanted to do so, i went to the Ann Arbor library and i, i looked through books, like toward the reference area and then i came across a debate i wasn't even aware that they had this but they have like, um set of curriculum, um, like the standard curriculums for like science and math for the Ann Arbor, Public Schools so i looked through them, and then, i looked under like, um the elementary grades of, and it was like required like, they listed the science topics that um, were required in their science curriculum and i chose environment because i figured that it would be, a good topic to use for science and to like bring, multicultural issues in too. and um, let's see i chose, environment because um <PAUSE DUR=":10"/> i chose environment because i saw that like multicultural issues can be (far across) because i could go through like the different, types of environments acro- a- around the world and like, how that affects um the people who live in them. and then um, basically when i went_ when i started looking through my current research, um, articles, there's one passage that i got out of a book ca- called The Future of Science in Elementary Schools, and it lists um, a number of ways teachers are proficient, and it lists as, <SEG TYPE="READING"> ensuring fairness in student teacher interactions, finding bias and stereotyping in texts and instruc- instructional materials, providing a wide range of role models to students, identifying school policies or practices that negatively impact, on students because of this g- of their gender race or ethnicity, and establishing the kind of learning environment where all students learn science and understand its importance in their lives. </SEG> and the last one um, having_ establishing the kind of learning environment so, that the kids understand the importance (in) their lives i saw the environment i could bring, like, environmental issues where, they could um, relate it back to their own lives how they could help out the environment. so i thought that was a good way of um, bringing it into my lesson. and um, basically, um, my lesson plan is a twelve, it's like, a twelve day lesson plan and i, made it um, base- i based it on um, having it close to Earth Day which is on April twenty-second so, i planned it out to have it like g- starting the week of Earth Day so it's sort of like, it sort of kicks off my lesson. and um, my first um, day's lesson is going to be, um, just a general, lecture on like the different biomes of the world and i wasn't gonna go t- too into detail because, i'm planning for the kids to um, form small groups and, like, presenting on each biome so it was just like a general introduction to the biomes. and then um, then afterwards, for day two i was gonna go, through the different kind of animals in each biome, and then um, on day three which would be like, planned out to be Earth Day if it was this year, i was gonna um, take 'em on a nature walk and then, show them like different pl- have them like collect leaves and stuff, for plants and then, later on like, go back to the classroom and like, classify them, in charts, and then, for day four to five, i have, set for research days which i'm gonna have them form into their small groups, for their biome presentation and then have them research and then, i have um, a list of resources, um, list in my curriculum guide of what they can use like i listed websites and books and magazines that they can use for their research. and then for day six would be the presentation day. and then um, day seven would be um an introduction to earth cycles and i mainly used this book called Earth Watch and it, brings_ it, um introduces like the earth cycle which, um includes like air water, and soil cycles, and um, there were some, activities that i used from this book also. and then for day eight then uh well for day seven, after introducing the earth cycle i was gonna go into, the air cycle and then, the following day would be just water cycle with an activity then day nine would be the soil cycle, with an, activity on erosion, and then on the tenth day i was gonna show the movie um Fern Gully The Last Rain Forest, which is a movie that um Fox put out, um, then for day eleven i was gonna have um, go over recycling and other methods to save the earth, and then for the last day day twelve i was_ they were_ we were gonna um, go on a mini field trip to a recycling station, and then afterwards we would come back to the classroom and discuss like what they saw. and then i also planned out like daily things that we_ daily activities we would do every day. um, one would be i would give them, on the first day of my lesson, um, a sheet of the s- fifty simple things, that they can do to save the ear- this <EVENT DESC="HOLDS UP BOOK"/> the book Fifty Simple Things You Can Do to Save the Earth i was gonna list the fifty things on just like one sheet and like pass it out. and then um, go over like, five of these things each day with them. and then, um another book which i have as a teacher resource is um, called Dear World and it's like a list of um letter passages from children around the world and how they feel about the environment. and i was gonna read like three passages a day from like three, different kids from, different countries, and that was like another daily event, and then um, and then pretty much, the rest of my curriculum guide are just_ what sort of_ i found like a l- a lot of resources for, um, the environment and, i- it goes across from videos to like C-Ds and, and books, and, there was tons of websites so it was, there was a lot of resources. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what did you think of the Ann Arbor curriculum, for science? </U>
			<U WHO="S6"> um, it w- it was pretty, it was pretty similar to what, i had, as an elementary student and so, it was, pretty on target i guess. i mean i- like the whole curriculum guide was like a huge binder and it, listed_ it was pretty much like a package of like, activities and like day to day lessons and stuff so i pretty much used it sort of like a model, because i mean it had like a concept map and everything, so it was pretty well-organized (i thought.) </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":05"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> thank you </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> our next contestant is Julia. <PAUSE DUR=":06"/> oh and keep passing around the candy please cuz i don't want to take it back to my office <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
			</U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":07"/>
			<U WHO="S2"> um, i'm gonna do my own selection. i, for my own selection i just kind of grabbed a bunch of random pictures, and told a bunch of random stories that had to do with multiculturalism from my life so this is probably gonna be kind of, random as well just kind of, shouting stuff out. i um... when i was younger i never really had very much exposure to anything multicultural i, i've always kind of been in the majority in a very, homogeneous society it feels like and i never really, thought about anything, that we've discussed in this class i mean i'm sure i did at some point you hear things on the news and the radio but it's not like it was ever a big issue in my life, but um, one thing that's kind of brought me into this whole, multicultural train of thought is the fact that i really really loved France, for no apparent reason. really really wanted to go to France knew no French people knew, no one having to do with France. so when i graduated from high school i went there for a year, and um, and all kinds of crazy things happened, you guys may have heard me mention, a couple in this class before but, there are a few i mentioned in my own selection and, a few i didn't, that um, that i wanted to tell you about. there was one time and i- this is one of the most distinct memories i have, it was really, well i'll tell you what happened first i guess i was i was in this class this senior year class, um, and in France you go to the same classes with all the same people all the time and one of the classes that we had was history and geography. and i was all psyched to be studying about like Napoleon and Louis the fourteenth and all this stuff and i walk in and they're talking about Woodrow Wilson. <EVENT WHO="SU-f" DESC="LAUGH"/> which was huge shock for me right because you don't study that stuff here i mean you don't study other people's stuff (i should say,) i- unless you take a world history elective or, your high school happens to, require it. um, so i was kind of bummed about that and a few days after, the first day of class, we watched this video, about this battle in Vietnam now i can't remember what it was called but it was the one, and i don't know if you should call it a battle, the one where the American soldiers went in and just killed everybody all these kids and, and, <U WHO="S7"> My Lai? </U> women and all this stuff wh- </U>
			<U WHO="S7"> My Lai was it? </U>
			<U WHO="S8"> My Lai </U>
			<U WHO="S2"> yeah is that what it was okay so we watch this video on this right and of course i knew about it, but i'm sitting in this room with thirty other, students my age like friends of mine French kids watching this movie and it was so, tense and i don't know if i was overinterpreting, i think i was to a certain extent but, cuz it's something that will make you tense anyway watching something like that but, of course i'm American in this room, and i remember people kind of turning around looking at me and, and having this feeling that, that i was the one responsible for this to a certain extent or <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> at least that i had to <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> that i had to, not justify it but, apologize or, or something, and i remember getting really angry thinking well what, the heck French, France is why we were in Vietnam in the first place and all this kind of crazy stuff and do these people ever study that and do they study Algeria no one ever wants to talk about Algeria which is this big, you know France colonization awful, stuff going on, comparable to that, situation in Vietnam and, i just i remember it very vividly cuz it was the first time i remember ever having to be, representative of a group, that wasn't looked upon very well. if that makes any sense. and i really didn't know what to do. so that was just one random story. i remember, this other story that i just think is kind of funny, i was in_ this is last year and i was in um, i was in Rome and i'd never been to Rome before and it had totally... impressed me i can't i can't even explain it a lot of people say it's dirty they don't like it i don't know if anyone's ever been there but it was just very very impressive to me now i'm Catholic but it wasn't, because of any, you know Catholic, revelations or anything it's just cuz it was so huge and beautiful and there were so many people and we were at the Vatican, and we were climbing for like five hours, not really, to get to the top. and there's this (xx) you know you can step outside there's this round, dome on the top and you step outside and look out all over the Vatican and it's gorgeous, but of course there's a fence so that you don't, fall off. and you_ i couldn't take a picture over the fence cuz it was taller than i was and i saw these, these guys who were, i don't know how to explain it like the the side you know there's this dome behind you, and there was this piece that stuck out like this, <EVENT DESC="DEMONSTRATING"/> and then it swerved up like that so you could stand on that little piece right there, and reach over. now one thing i noticed about Rome is that i don't know how many people have been to Europe i can only say Europe cuz that's the only place i've ever been but there're people who speak different languages everywhere, and you get to be able to recognize them Italian Spanish and all this kind of stuff, but um, but in Rome it was amazing because there were so many people from so many different places that i had no clue, what language these people were speaking or where they were from and half of them i probably hadn't ever heard of the country, um, that they were from which is, pathetic too but anyway, um, and these guys were talking this language i couldn't understand what they were saying but i saw them do this, do this, take this picture so i went, to get up there, and i realized that, that you couldn't do it by yourself like you needed the g- the one guy to stay in front of the other guy to hold him up because the piece (of) <EVENT DESC="DEMONSTRATING"/> standing up top would knock you over if you were standing on this one <EVENT DESC="DEMONSTRATING"/> so i'm standing up there trying to take this picture, and um, and they saw me and the one person came up and kind of held me up and it was really nice we went like ha ha ha and, not making any sense to each other. and i took my picture. they were they were older they were in their fifties i would say, and... and the one guy asked i i don't know he, oh i said i said, thank you in French cuz i don't know if any of you've had this phenomenon where, when someone's speaking to you in a foreign language, i automatically speak in French cuz that's the language that i'm always, messing up and confused in not in English so it was kind of a reaction and the guy asked me if i was French and i was like no no no, and i told him i was American and the two guys like paused, and looked at each other, and started laughing and were saying something i could tell that this was a weird situation... so i tried to ask them where they were from, and they told me that they were from Iran. and my first reaction was like, <EVENT DESC="SHUDDER"/> it was awful i was so mad at myself i was on top of the Vatican like in the middle of Rome with all these great people and these people tell me that th- they're from Iran and my reaction is, <EVENT DESC="SHUDDER"/> and i tried to cover it up, and i don't know how well it worked but it was it was really just a strange experience this like, fear or oh no i'm not supposed to_ i don't know what it was i don't even know that much about Iran but i just knew that that wasn't, <EVENT DESC="HAND GESTURE; PUSHING AWAY"/> something, it wasn't, th- you know <EVENT DESC="HAND GESTURE"/> back i i don't know it was really bizarre. so anyway i have all these random stories there's a lot of um, tension with Arabs, and French, in France, and um, kind of comparable to white-black issues in the United States I guess. and i have all kinds of stories about that but it's funny cuz i try to think about this multicultural stuff in this class, and um, and i feel like, i'm really lucky because i've been exposed to a lotta things, in the past few years because i've travelled and because i've met people from different cultures. and um i don't know what i would be like if that hadn't happened to me. um, but at the same time, the more i think about it it's not, all these crazy, random stories that, that help me realize what's going on it's really, the people that i meet, that i care about and i m- i th- know i've mentioned this before, um so i'm not trying to sound too repetitive but um... but i think about the first year i was in Grenoble and i spent, most of the year with five American people, not with French people and i was stressing out the whole time saying i have to be meeting different people and speaking different languages and doing different things cuz i have to be, more open-minded and more all of this stuff and i need to learn French, which i think is true, but when i look back on it it's funny because these five people were American, and came from totally, random different backgrounds small towns, you know, big cities, different, socioecon- economic status all that kind of stuff. and i know that i would not have been friends with a single one of them, if i'd met them here. i know it_ one of them was from this little town of two hundred people and no stoplight and she was a cheerleader and was not at all the kind of person, that i would've gotten along with in high school cuz ugh cheerleaders and, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> and, and like, i can't r- one guy was just, a skater person i i still couldn't understand what he was saying in English by the end of the year and he wore these little horns on his hat and it was just not, not something that i was used to but i really, really became so close to these people because of all the issues i had to deal with being in a foreign country and being in a place where i was thrown off guard, and where i needed someone and the same way for them. and i guess that's really, really just my big spiel about multiculturalism in my own life is just that... you can really learn things from individual people. and i think that it really comes from where you don't expect it and i really think that with kids if you want, to have them understand that you can't talk to them in these really broad terms and give 'em these, things that mean nothing to them really and these stories you hafta, somehow find a way to get them... to feel it through someone that they care about. so anyway. that's what my selection was about. </U>
			<EVENT DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<EVENT DESC="SOUND DELETED FROM ORIGINAL FILE FOR CONFIDENTIALITY"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> thank you, um. Melissa, (xx) </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":09"/>
			<U WHO="S9"> okay, i'm losing my voice so, (so talk up,) but i'm gonna share my um, curriculum lesson plan with you guys. um, and the theme i picked, um i'm an el- elementary school, major, and the theme i picked was multicultural education in the elementary school i wanted it a very broad base because um... i believe that multicultural education should be integrated into every subject area that i'm gonna teach, and so it was really hard for me to limit it, to um, to um, three weeks, and let alone to one subject area so i wanted to, just make some broad, activities to help children, um, learn about themselves because i believe that um people who underth- understand themselves and where they come fro- i'm sorry i know i sound funny, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> um, people who understand themselves, um and their culture where they come from i think that they're more apt to understand other people and other people's cultures. and um... and i also wanted um this lesson plan, to um help my students, learn that um, that it hurts when you're the one being discriminated against, and um, i wanted to try and, disintegrate some already existing stereotypes that like we've all already talked about coming from our own backgrounds but i wanted to help, dis- um, disintegrate some of my students', stereotypes, and i also wanted to expose them, to um, a broad spectrum of cultures and backgrounds, and things because, i also believe that knowledge is power and if you don't, if you understand something then you won't fear it. and so um, i chose third grade for three weeks, um, and my opening activity was probably one that, i know we all know as the blue-eyed brown-eyed experiment and i'd divide the class into kids who have blue eyes or, green eyes and kids who have brown eyes or hazel eyes, and i would make the blue-eyed children um, like a se- second-class citizen, like i would try_ i mean, obviously these are like third graders i'm not gonna be like harsh to them i'm gonna be very careful of everyone's feelings but um, i would say you know if someone with blue eyes answered a question i'd be like oh, no and, if someone with brown eyes i'd be like yeah that's great it's perfect i mean even if it wasn't like even close to the answer or whatever. and i would make it obvious that, it was a discrimination issue here. and then i would have, my children go back to their journals and reflect in it, how they felt when they were the one being discriminated against and how they felt when they were the one being, benefit- or, when they benefitted from, the discrimination, so to speak. um, i wante- i also want to know um... if eye color, is a valid excuse, to treat people differently, um and i would have them write in their journals about that and then, after that um i would like them, us to come together and have a discussion, and i want, to know like how they felt, throughout the whole activity and, i would relate um, eye cla- um the, like randomness of judging people on eye color to the randomness of judging people, by the color of their skin, and um, i also would like, to have them define words like racism discrimination, respect and prejudice. and then, i'm gonna do a similar activity, like maybe the next day or so um, with women versus men and, you know, and voting issues kind of like that. and then um the, second part oh that was in the first part and that was like the intro to discrimination, and in the second part of my activity, is um self-acceptance. and um, the first thing i would have them do is talk with their family, um... and um, oh the fir- oh sorry i would have a discussion or, lead an activity or read a book or show them a video, and tell them that, there are many different kinds of families you could have both parents living in your home one parent no parent foster parents grandparents guardians etcetera etcetera, and um i wanted my children, to become comfortable with the family that they belong to, and um i wanna make sure that i'm not gonna alienate everybody so i'd definitely include every kind of family i have, in my um, every kind of family my children come from in my lesson. um, i also want, i would also would like my children to make a list of, um, what they like about who they are, um, their family ethnic background relatives um, any kind of ambitions they have, um the neighborhood they come from, anything that they like about themselves, um, and um i wanted_ the reason why i did this is because, um i wanted my children to become proud of who they are and i want them to display it to the whole class, and um... and then, the third activity i would have them do is um interview, family members, and to find out, um and obviously family is like a very broad term to me um, if like one of my kids is an orphan i would obviously have them interview like anyone they consider to be family friends whatever, and um, i would like them to interview people, ask them where they co- wh- like where in the world they've come from, um, what their family values are if that's like a, a term that third graders could understand, and um, bring in pictures of the people they interviewed, and i wou- i wanna have like a huge map in my room and, put the, put the pictures of the people where they said that they came from so that everybody can see that, you know, we're not all from one place like our relatives came from all over cuz we're from America, and i wanted, um, (the) children to start associating to their culture, and expose children to different cultures in different parts of the world and i also thought that that might help them with geography but, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/> um, and then, this, this is just something i wanna do like throughout the three weeks of my lesson um, i wanna have guest speakers maybe one or two per week, and ask parents, volunteers friends um, family members whatever to give lectures in the classroom about what it's like to be an American from all different backgrounds, um, and i would ask my students to prepare, questions for the visitor, and um... then try and compare cultures if they feel qualified to do so, and the reason why i chose that activity is because um obviously i want them to become exposed, to um, to different things and um, i also wanted to expose, all my students to, music from all over the world in every genre, um... i also wanna expose them to foods clothing entertainments, um values, holidays i'm not really one, to do the ethnicity of the month thing so, i've like this is obviously something i would do all the time. and um i want them to learn about holidays and wha- where holidays originated from and what the meaning is behind them and, how they're important to a lot of people and they should never be knocked or whatever. and then i also wanted to do once a day present the students with an exceptional person from various backgrounds, um, maybe a person from history or present day, and um, definitely students that_ or definitely people that my students could identify with and, um admire for their accomplishments and, i've, listed some but obviously you don't need to know that but, um, and i also um, i wanted them i wanted to do this because i don't want my students to grow up with the knowledge of just like typical white history i want them to know like, like, uh see themselves represented in history basically. and um, and the last thing i had planned was, to um, read, stories that represent, nonstereotypical portrayals, of people in plots, and um i have a list of books in the back, some of them, are called um... um In a Circle a Long Time Ago a Treasury of (Native Lore it's) Native American stories, Two Hot Tamales it's, Hispanic, stories whatever, um, this is again to give, my students exposure and the way i would assess them is, i would want them to prepare, an overview of a person who they are interested in just like i had done throughout the unit, and i also wanted to check their learning logs to see um how they reflected on the two experiments, and also to write a letter to one of our guests thanking them for sharing their knowledge and comparing, the guest's lifestyle to their own and finally, um i would grade them on the interview that they, um, the interview and the portrait that they provided from their family... so, that's it <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
			</U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> thank you </U>
			<U WHO="S10"> i actually have another question <EVENT DESC="LAUGH"/>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S9"> oh i'm sorry <OVERLAP> (xx) </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S10">
				<OVERLAP> that's </OVERLAP> okay i have a question for each person. um, actually it's kind of for the whole class cuz i've, i didn't do the same thing but i've been_ one where you said like have 'em write down um, things that they're proud of about themselves, <U WHO="S9"> uhuh </U> i did a unit on, um, self-esteem and stuff like that and i, kinda like struggled with that, that was gonna be my opening, project and then i thought, wow like what if i have a kid, who just sits there and says i'm not proud of anything? and i like i battled with that for, pretty much all week and ended up, i did put it in but what_ have you guys ever experienced something like that in the classroom or, do you guys know what i'm talking about like just having a kid that's like i'm not proud of anything and just flat out is not proud of anything and how you kind of deal with that or </U>
			<U WHO="S9"> i think if you know your students and if you think that the child is well-liked among his peers you could ask the class for help and say like okay what are some of, i mean obviously depending on their age you wouldn't do this in, high school i don't think, but <U WHO="S10"> right </U> i think in elementary school you could say okay well we all know that, this person has good traits cuz every person does and, so what are some things that we could help, he or she <OVERLAP> think about. </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S10">
				<OVERLAP> yeah </OVERLAP> i don't know i was just_ i've, just been thinking about that this week a lot. </U>
			<U WHO="S9"> i think it's a good point definitely valid. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> questions? um, next contestant is Dave. </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":08"/>
			<U WHO="S11"> um... m- i'm doing my own selection, um, basically the night before this was due i rented, Dangerous Minds, which is a... a movie that i kinda, me and my roommates all said it was a pretty cheesy movie, um, you know a, sexy ex-marine teacher, wins over her uh, urban classroom through karate. i thought it was kinda cheesy. um, and then that Coolio song was kinda, annoying, uh </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
			<U WHO="S4"> what song? </U>
			<U WHO="S11">
				<OVERLAP> Coolio </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="SU-m">
				<OVERLAP> Coolio </OVERLAP> song </U>
			<U WHO="S4"> you didn't like that (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S11"> (well) it kinda got overplayed, for a while. um... but then after i was, after i got done watching it i kinda, realized that that could be me someday, um that i could get thrown into that classroom, um... and... i don't know i was kinda, it kinda intimidates me cuz i don't know what i would do, you know if i was in her place, um cuz i don't know karate. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> i asked myself you know why i'm so scared of this classroom, um <PAUSE DUR=":05"/> i uh, i also watched the movie um... what was it called? <EVENT DESC="LOOKING IN PAPER"/> Higher Learning, um, with Ice Cube. and uh, i know in the movie he uh, he has this one line where he says uh, that like in the white academy, they're behind, they're behind enemy lines, and uh, so i guess basically... he compares, you know a classroom with a white teacher and a, minority, student body, to like, a war zone or whatever. and uh, in my paper i just kinda talk about how, you know i'm not sure what i would do, in front of that classroom, um... cuz i don't have any connection to them. i mean in the movie one of the students says, uh... says, you don't (kno-) you know you don't know what i've seen. you don't know you know, what's happened in my life. and i think if i was in front of that classroom i wouldn't uh you know, that would be true for me too, because uh, my multicultural world's basically been pretty sheltered, um... i talk about... my uh my multicultural world, um... i grew up in a small town (Yale) Michigan, uh... i'm lost here <PAUSE DUR=":05"/> uh my cla- my graduating class was about two hundred people, um, and i_ in the, school district was like huge it was like a third of the county, um, so it was a really small town no stoplights, um, there was one minority one Lebanese kid, in the classroom, uh... there was just there was no minorities in the town, um... so when i came to U-of-M, i really you know i hadn't had any exposure to minorities. um, i had no idea what a Jewish person was, before i got here. i was really pretty naive. um... but then even when i got here to U-of-M, i kind of uh... most of my friends were like white suburbanites, um... and, i'd say you know U-of-M really didn't help me, you know prepare for_ to be in front of a classroom, like the one in, in uh, Dangerous Minds. so basically i go on you know to ask you know what, how, you know how would i deal with that, and my answer i guess is, you know maybe maybe, Dangerous Minds isn't that cheesy. you know maybe, something like karate or, whatever, something to make a, connection. and uh, get their attention for, fifty minutes... it's worth it. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what do you feel is one strength that you um, that you see yourself bringing to a classroom? </U>
			<U WHO="S11"> (what?) </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> what, what do you think is, could you um, <U WHO="S11">
					<OVERLAP> one strength? </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> y- </OVERLAP> o- one strength do you think that you could bring to the classroom...? about yourself. </U>
			<U WHO="S11"> just like, energy? i don't know... i don't know. what do you mean strength like? </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> (xx) i think you talked about it in your paper in terms of um, in terms of Dangerous Minds what's the strength, that you could see yourself bringing... i don't remember exactly (xx) </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":05"/>
			<U WHO="S11"> i'm not sure. </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> alright thank you. </U>
			<U WHO="S11"> yeah. </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> uh, Bob. </U>
			<PAUSE DUR=":11"/>
			<U WHO="S8"> (this is) my own selection uh, i kind of talked about my transition from Grand Rapids to Ann Arbor. and i talked about Escalante and Stand and Deliver but, everyone's just, letting everything out so screw that. um... <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> uh, i guess i mean i'm from Grand Rapids uh, Grandville to be exact. it's pretty much, white. uh the biggest discrepancy is, are you Catholic or Christian Reform pretty much uh, white middle-class, um, one or two African-Americans are at my school. i remember there was, it w- was just horrible too cuz, the one African-American was a member of the gang from downtown so that was, like the representative of of black in my school with_ and um, uh no other religions. and um, and everyo- as everyone was talking i was thinking back and uh, how like, just, how, racist like the white supremacy that exists in my high school or even just, the Christian supremacy um, like i wrote in here i remember, my junior year was the last year we were allowed to dress up for Halloween in my high school cuz uh, five students showed up in K-K-K outfits for Halloween. and um, <EVENT WHO="SU" DESC="WHISTLE"/> which i understand that_ i mean there was, there was a little white power group that i mean they, no one really knew 'em they were they were, there weren't in the social_ they were just on the outsides but uh, but they, what, what was shocking is they didn't, have to take off their costumes until third hour they made it three hours, without having to take off these costumes and i think back and i'm like, how could these teachers let, these, K-K-K (garbs) last for three hours and, and it just makes me really think uh, like wow, and um... and i remember myself, i uh, we used to... the the fr- the c- uh the f- the words we used, i didn't realize like i used to say uh, he jewed me. uh i used to say that uh uh people would always say oh that's so Jewish. and i don't even think i, put it together with, a Jewish person it was just a word. um, like i didn't put together kosher like oh that's all kosher it didn't make s- i didn't even put those, that word together until last year like it, just, like a separate different word and um, and uh, (m- m- m- my) junior or senior year i started to realize_ i was like Jewish wait minute you know like we're talking about, people this is this is this is, prejudice this is bad. so i i, um, i think, uh the Robert Frost poem the, two roads diverge in a wood and i took the one less traveled by? that, really got an impact to me and i started, i wanted, i w- i was reaching for the different. i wanted to be different i didn't like the, to be in the norm. so i started to defend like, uh i think my junior and senior year i'd when someone said oh that's so Jewish i started defending this. i'm like shut up i'm Jewish. and that was my way of doing it and, so i got called Hooperstein for like, a year by a bunch of people but um, i just, </U>
			<U WHO="S1"> wait, what? </U>
			<U WHO="S8"> Hoop- my last name's Hooper and see they're like okay Hooperstein, like, the people who were s- who were, prejudiced or who'd use this, this term. whatever. um... i and i was just really reaching for the different like there was a foreign exchange student in my class and from Germany and i was like a different kid you know he's, so i i, he ended up living with me. that's how close he got to my_ i got really close with him and he didn't like the family he lived with i had him move in with me, got really close i was just, really uh, chasing, the different and just... that the community uh, the Grandville community just wasn't, multicultural i r- most people over there like, were raised, all their parents were raised in Grandville a lot of 'em and, their grandparents lived in Grandville and, a lot of my friends, went to Grand Valley which is right near Grandville, got married to someone from Grandville, have kids in Grandville, it just they just don't get out of this little bubble. they're all talking about the bubble. and uh... so then i came to Ann Arbor. i think, that was a big deal uh, i remember the first week before classes i was walking around with a girl from, she didn't go to Grandville from Grand Rapids and uh, and there was several students walking around with yarmulkes on and she asked me what fraternity, that, what fraternity wears those hats? and i'm like, you know, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> don't you watch T-V even? like, like, well th- it just goes to show like how blind, people are, where i'm from like just, like i don- i_ there's there's no such thing as a homosexual in Grand Rapids. sure there are, but in, w- in the world i saw when i grew up, you wouldn't dare, uh, come out of the closet um, actually my freshman year here i (admit) when i was still into this different i wanted to shock my hometown and me and my friend went to the fireworks, big fireworks and, we w- we had all our friends follow us and we just held hands, me and my guy friend, <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> the whole way back to our car. and y- we almost caused like three accidents, um like, people would just go <EVENT DESC="SHOCKED EXPRESSION"/> like, you would not believe the triple takes we got like people would be driving like uhh and the- ert <EVENT DESC="PRETENDS TO SWERVE CAR"/>
				<EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> you know, i mean, it was amazing the effect we like, how much we shocked that town and, and, (like) i, i became a homosexual, like, people who didn't, don't know me anymore i'm not close to_ i don't have ties back to friends. like my sister told me you know everyone th- thought i was gay and all these things and, it's just, i'm out of there. so, i came to Ann Arbor and i was thinking alright here's, here's uh, i i i was look- i was, looking for change i was looking for diversity. remember um i don't know if you remember orientation they had a, a diversity group thing they had a line and they ha- they said questions and how comfortable are you with this? i remember one of the questions was uh, your roommate is uh is gay. and i was like, i want my roommate to be gay and everyone's like what? and i'm like, you know i w- i want, i was, for some reason i just wanted change i wanted to, to experience everything i w- and uh, so i i moved in my roommate we didn't get along it turned out. he was gay, um. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> uh so, we actually, we actually started getting along well the fir- like, we didn't get along, when i, didn't know he was gay i actually, (cuz i'm like) man, he's g- i'm like, he's gonna come out of the closet. i'm like i know it he's, he's gonna come out of the closet he's gonna find a comfortable niche and he's out of the closet. little did i know he was out of the closet for a few years just not to me. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> um, so he fi- so we finally, had a late night talk you know laying in bed lights off don't wanna go to sleep. so i learned that and that was_ i liked that that was, i i've, i got a, i, i learned a lot about what it was like to be, a homosexual and what pressures there are, um... it w- it was it was interesting i mean, like y- he was the only guy who would yell at the hockey players to put their clothes back on on our hall. and i di- i and i i do- i like, before that like, cuz the hockey players, i don't know, they, they we lived with a bunch of hockey players on the hall and they'd, get out of the shower with their towel and, you know walk back to their room or whatever. and, everyone was just like, oh well you know... tha- they're, that's just hockey players. and the- th- li- the- only g- the one gay guy on the hall is the one who says put your clothes on, like and like, i think in high school if i would've envisioned, that same situation i'd have been like the gay guy'd been the one peeking around the corner. but, it's not that way at all, um. so i, i started to just, i got a, i i, i became more comfortable with more things, uh... i came home and there's a thirty-five-year-old guy kissing my roommate and i'm just, you know at first it's like... you know, whoa you know what the heck is going on but, it became ordinary it, it wasn't different uh, and that's what we've been talking about a lot is how um, people who, different cultures different colors different whatever just, at first they're just different like you say you're talking to, uh, lesbian bisexual i don't know and you're like i don't (i- ch-) like, you just have these thoughts going through your head like you're, like you have a manufactured conversation like you're <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> (trying to,) you're thinking. your like, all of a sudden okay different now, i don't i don't want to be prejudiced so you're just thinking okay what am i saying. and tha- that's just that's not a way to talk to someone and and that's what you find yourself doing, um... so i've really learned that uh, like in the in this paper i kind of analyzed what affects, uh, how i view multiculturalism and pretty much, (it) came down to my, everyday actions, media and academia. and everyday, life and surroundings is the biggest aspect (uh) who my friends are, and um... and i found, i really need to uh, the only way for me to get a better understanding of, uh of a person is to get to know them really well. um, how'd i put it in here? <EVENT DESC="LOOKS AT PAPER"/> (kind of) built a platform for, conversation and, makes me, um... it makes, it makes the different, and not ordinary become ordinary. like, a gay guy he's different you're talking to a a gay guy. (but) once you get to know him you're talking to Brian, i mean it just doesn't, and that's what i've, i've really learned but uh, so i started (to find) that, i i'm, and i don't want to be prejudiced and don't want to be ignorant, i want to get to know all these people for who they are, but in order to do that i have to understand, if some_ i- if i have a black friend i have to understand what pressures are, it means to what it means to be black for me to unders- understand this person. so, i find myself... being prejudiced and ignorant in trying to get rid of my prejudice and ignorance. does that make any sense at all? um, with these manufactured conversations oh, black man okay. uh, yeah hi you know i'm, i'm... i'm comfortable, it's, i i know you, (here y-) let- let's talk <EVENT DESC="INDICATES A THOUGHT IN THE BACK OF THE SPEAKER'S HEAD"/> black man black man i mean i_ and, i have black friends but... like, it's still not there, uh, i, i talk a a new, a new person comes along that's different and different different different hi uh, let's get to know you they're different they're different and, unless you really know someone i i- i- i find it's really difficult, to do um, i i've, tried to go to, much less categorizing and more just questioning. trying to, erase clean slate with every person i meet. i don't know anything about anybody. and uh that, that's helped me a lot, in dealing with different people and getting to understand different cultures um... even, if you're white clean slate, i don't know, anything about you. and if i go with that... yeah i've, i... i, can i don't, i can't get by as easily i (have to make,) i can't make the assumptions that you normally make, that help us to, you know solve problems whatever, but it helps me to get to know people better just, fft, no clue who you are. you're black you're white i can't even tell. it's hard to do though, um... i don't know what else i talked about in here um... i started to talk about how Ann Arbor is uh, how i i was all happy to get in Ann Arbor with this multicultural environment i'm outta this bubble of Grand Rapids, but i i'm i'm in a bubble of Ann Arbor now too and i'm starting to, really realize that uh how Ann Arbor's just, it's_ you can't be prejudiced in, in Ann Arbor you're i mean you're you're set, you're set on fire i mean that's just bad, and i'm_ you don't get the honest feelings, you don't_ everyone's got this little caution button you know everyone they talk to and uh, and it's just not representative of the rest of the world, uh Ann Arbor's this closer-to-utopia kind of multicultural town, and uh, it's really skewing my view of of different, cultures i'm i'm getting, everyone that goes to University of Michigan, from this culture there's_ i don't think it's very representative. i'm not representative of Grandville. uh, i don't think so um, so i'm really, i'm looking forward to getting outta here almost now, to, establish another multicultural view cuz right now it's really skewed by, academia. um, i just pretty much saw my (opportunity) i really, think for me to have a better understanding of different cultures and people i have to, uh, better understand the forces, that drive the way i see things if i understand how media affects me, how academia affects me and how my surroundings affect me, i can, better wipe the slate, clean when i meet people and, interact, i guess. and i kinda i i (push) that to how Escalante does this (xx) than that but <EVENT DESC="MAKES RASPBERRY NOISE"/> that's about it. alright. </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S1"> um, Sheila </U>
			<U WHO="S7"> um, i'm i'm in the School of Library Science, and, some of the projects i've had to do i've had to interview a media specialist and one of the things they always say is nobody knows what i do, nobody thinks i do anything around here, so um i'm gonna tell you about my, my uh curriculum guide here so that i can let you know kinda what we do. um, in fact my project has something to do about holidays i forget who it was mentioned holidays </U>
			<U WHO="SU-f"> (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S7"> um... the basic premise of the project we're go- it's for ninth graders, um who have just come into the high school and so it's kind of an introduction to, um media center and all that we're going to um, develop a permanent resource for the media center on holidays, um, they're gonna be divided into groups and the groups are gonna go and develop the history of a holiday we'll have six different holidays, and then each person in the group will have a um, personal paper on what it feels like to celebrate that holiday, and then we're gonna have pictures, um that represent the holiday and all this is gonna go on the web and we're doing this in conjunction with um, schools around the world, um Southeast Asia, um i forgot where i said i was gonna do it South Africa Japan India, and one other one. can't remember what it was. um so we could get, th- what the holidays they celebrate what ones we celebrate the same and what the differences are the similarities um, one of the things i think'll be interesting is that there are holidays we all celebrate like New Year's, um what do they think the history of that holiday is as compared to what you know we think the history of that holiday is? and that probably comes from back when i was in school when we were in the middle of the cold war, um, they used to tell us about how Russia had rewritten history, to make it, go their way, you know which, probably was a mistake because um i'm a part of the hippie generation and as soon as they told us that we started wondering what our government was telling us, cuz you can't tell somebody a government can rewrite history and then not make 'em think twice about their own government, so it'll be interesting to find out um, if we all view the history of these holidays the same. now um, the library teacher doesn't do a lot of instruction, and the instruction that she does works better if she does it in conjunction with, other ar- subject areas. um it used to be you'd go into the library and she'd hand you a sheet, and she'd go go find the Dewey numbers on these or she'd hand you some authors and say go find your books or something it had nothing to do with what you were doing in your life or your classroom, and, it works a lot better if we tie it in with the classroom so... to develop the histories of_ for my part they have to come to the library they have to use at least three different types of, reference book sources, we've got handbooks almanacs encyclopedias regular books, dictionaries, on holidays, um and in working in conjunction with the English teacher because they're writing the uh_ i_ you know if i have an English teacher to actually work with i could do this better i had to make up all this, cuz i'm working by myself and i don't really know what you guys do or what you'd call it but they're gonna have to write this informative or factual paper, with a bibliography, on the histories. and then when they come back in to do their um, personal, um observances of the celebration, um, what we're gonna do is work on word processing, the computer lab is in the library so, i'm gonna teach 'em word processing, and in the English_ it's tied in with the English teacher who's teaching 'em how to do a descriptive paper. and, then we're gonna um, i have to have 'em come in and teach 'em how to turn all this into H-T-M-L to put it on the web, i'm gonna have 'em come in and, use different references to find pictures and how to scan 'em onto the web i have to teach 'em that, then at the end when all this is done and all the schools have everything up on the web, it's a nice web resource but we wanted something permanent for our library, so we're gonna work with the art teacher, and i'll go in there and i'll bring books in and explain how the cover of the book, and the endpapers of the book and the design of the pages reflect the content of the book, and then in their art class they're all gonna design a cover and everything for our holiday book, and then we'll have um, in the display cases we'll set up all their projects and then a couple weeks later we'll have a vote, on whose gets to be the cover of our permanent book in our library. so the kind of library skills that they're learning are um use of different information resources the ability to make a bibliography, use of equipment computers printers scanners word processing and H-T-M-L software, gathering analyzing and synthesizing information and then presenting information to others because we've got a couple group projects going on, um, for me they're gonna have to present to others, what resources they used, um, how much inf- what type of information they had how useful they were for this project. um, for the English teacher they're doing informative descriptive papers bibliographies um and for the art teacher they've got an art project. eventually this resource, will probably be used um in the social studies, um, either when they're looking at a s- a country in particular or just looking at societies, compare and contrast the kind of holidays we do and that kind of stuff. um, it has multicultural implications because they're working (in) diverse local groups, they're establishing contact with global groups, they're collaborating with others, um it's making a concrete experience of this abstract notion that we want them to get of a unified whole coming out of diverse pieces, and perspectives coming together, um they're making a book from diverse groups, um a unit plan has been made from diverse um subject areas, um and they'll be comparing and contrasting their perspectives on how (xx) similarities and differences. so, um, in conclusion uh th- your school librarian would like to hear from you, the stuff that she has to teach works better if she teach- teaches it with you, she needs to know what your um unit plans are for the year what your subjects are, this would also help her to have the right resources ready in that library, helps her with collection development, um, if if the social studies department's coming to me and the English department's coming to me, i might see where those two could work together on something maybe they didn't know they were both doing the same thing, um it happens sometimes the teacher will design an assignment which really, is almost unworkable because of, maybe we don't have the resources for it, or it's too narrow, and if he leaves it like that he's gonna get thirty papers that all sound the same, um so we can help you redesign it to make it bigger maybe it's too big you need to make it smaller, um when i did this curriculum guide for the um, first part they have to do the histories and they have to use a lot of those different kind of resources. i got together with the public librarian to find out what resources were there cuz, a great percentage of your kids are gonna be going to the public library, and her and i put the list together, so um they can find things in my library or her library, and that's an important thing for you to remember too um, public librarian would love to hear from you also, um if she knows what's going on in the schools they can do their collection development better they can have the resources necessary, um maybe she's only got, five or ten books on this uh project that  you want to do, if you don't tell her you're doing it the first ten kids come in and take those books, next fifteen kids have nothing to work with so she can put 'em on reserve, she can do inter-library loan, um, if she knows ahead of time what the assignment is she understands what it is, um in one of my other classes i i i did a project on this, and i used the anecdote of the little boy who waited to the last minute to do his homework of course, and he runs to dad and goes dad dad i gotta go to the library, um i'm supposed supposed to find pictures of what the <SEG TYPE="PRON" SUBTYPE="/seltiks/"> Celtics </SEG> used to wear. so he and dad went to the library and they asked the librarian for pictures of old <SEG TYPE="PRON" SUBTYPE="/seltik/"> Celtic </SEG> uniforms the basketball team, and it turns out that the project was he was supposed to find <SEG TYPE="PRON" SUBTYPE="/keltik/"> Celtic </SEG> costumes. <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> so if the librarian knew this she could have helped this little boy. so um, communicate with your lonely librarian. it'll make it easier for everybody. thank you </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<U WHO="S7"> Does somebody have a question? </U>
			<U WHO="S4"> i have a question, i was just curious like, when you create the websites do they just like disappear cuz you said you wanted to keep it up there, is there something that you have to like type in as far as the codes for the H-T-M, for it to stay, <OVERLAP> or? is- they- </OVERLAP>
			</U>
			<U WHO="S7">
				<OVERLAP> oh yeah </OVERLAP> yeah you_ we're gonna put it on the website the school will have it's own website, and in fact where's this piece of paper? (xx) </U>
			<U WHO="S4"> i'm just wondering in general like if, do they_ does someone just come in and erase like certain websites if you create 'em? </U>
			<U WHO="S7"> no no one else can erase 'em but the school may not keep 'em. there's_ you must_ have you ever done any work on the web and you've put in a a web <OVERLAP> address and it's not </OVERLAP>
				<U WHO="S4">
					<OVERLAP> yeah that's why i was </OVERLAP>
				</U> there anymore? </U>
			<U WHO="S4"> right yeah </U>
			<U WHO="S7"> it hasn't been kept up, um <U WHO="S4">
					<OVERLAP> but who erases it does? </OVERLAP>
				</U>
				<OVERLAP> maybe the server address </OVERLAP> was moved and the address for that particular page was never changed, so now it's in limbo out there, can't be found, um this project is tied in with five other countries, and, they're all there this year we'll have that resource this year but next year maybe it won't be there so we'd like a hard copy in our library to always have this resource. and this is actually um, this is actually um an expansion, of, a project that i found on the web and this project was for elementary students, and they were making a um calendar, and they would send in what they thought about holidays and so this is the kinda stuff you might get back when you're working with other countries which is kind of interesting, now these are little kids um, and their project wasn't as big but, for the New Year holiday, <SEG TYPE="READING"> in Denmark, um, at six o'clock, we hear the New Year speech from the queen. and then we have dinner we usually have fish and potatoes, and then when dinner is finished eaten we wait for the clock to strike twelve, and then we jump into the New Year from a chair </SEG>
			</U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="LAUGH"/>
			<U WHO="S7"> jump both feet into the New Year i guess, um in Japan, nobody works on the first three days of the New Year. they have a little, a holiday three-day holiday. uh the period called and i don't know how to say this if anybody else does S H O U G A T S shougats or something like that. shougats originally referred to the whole of January which made me wonder did they not work for the whole of January? i don't know. uh but now it just refers to those three days and on those days they go to shrines visit friends drink sake, eat special New Year dishes, um the kids uh, play battledore shuttlecock and fly kites, uh they hang pine boughs in the doorways and (xx) the descent of the gods, um this pine decoration's left in place from January the first to the seventh, this's a little kid that wrote this and then in parentheses he goes <SEG TYPE="READING"> until the fifteenth in the olden times </SEG> which coulda been all of twenty years ago for all we know <EVENT WHO="SU-f" DESC="LAUGH"/> and the period referred to as, uh well um, i can't say this it's in Japanese but in parentheses he goes <SEG TYPE="READING"> cash is paid to children for New Year presents by their parents and grand- grandparents, children totally get a hundred to five hundred dollars. children become rich during shougats </SEG>
				<EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> and then in Norway, <SEG TYPE="READING"> on New Year's Day schools and factories are closed some people go to church and others stay home recovering from last night's parties, </SEG> that sounds familiar so far, but then he says <SEG TYPE="READING"> a lot of people watch th- the New Year's Day concert from Vienna on T-V the concert is truly great </SEG> and he's got that in capital letters. <SEG TYPE="READING"> with music by composers named Strauss. </SEG> and i just hafta_ had to wonder if we could get our guys to give up those football games and listen to Strauss instead but i doubted it <EVENT DESC="LAUGH" WHO="SS"/> so, i think that this'll be kind of a a fun project for the kids to do um, it's an authentic meaningful project they're, they're actually um making something, for their community, and so i think they'll get a lot out of it. </U>
			<EVENT WHO="SS" DESC="APPLAUSE"/>
			<P> {END OF TRANSCRIPT} </P>
		</BODY>
	</TEXT>
</TEI.2>
