<bncDoc id=BDF98 n=AKenny>
<header creator=dominic status=UPDATE update="2 Feb 1999" type=TEXT>
<fileDesc>
<titStmt>
<title>
Computers and the humanities -- an electronic version
</title>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Data capture and transcription
</resp>
<name>
Oxford University Press
</name>
</respStmt>
</titStmt>
<ednStmt n=s1>
Header automatically generated by mkhdr 0.30
Updated for sampler by interleave 1.1
</ednStmt>
<extent words=5551 kb=109>
</extent>
<pubStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Archive site
</resp>
<name>
Oxford University Computing Services
</name>
</respStmt>
<address>
13 Banbury Road, Oxford OX2 6NN U.K.
Telephone:     +44 1865 273280
Facsimile:     +44 1865 273275
Internet mail: natcorp@oucs.ox.ac.uk
</address>
<idno n=AKenny type=bnc>
AKenny
</idno>
<avail region=world status=UNKNOWN>
THIS TEXT IS AVAILABLE THROUGHOUT THE WORLD only as
part of the British National Corpus at nominal charge FOR
ACADEMIC RESEARCH PURPOSES SUBJECT TO A SIGNED END USER
LICENCE HAVING BEEN RECEIVED BY OXFORD UNIVERSITY COMPUTING
SERVICES, from whom forms and supporting materials are
available.

THIS TEXT IS NOT AVAILABLE FOR COMMERCIAL RESEARCH AND
EXPLOITATION unless terms have first been agreed with the
BNC Consortium Exploitation Committee.  Apply in the first
instance to Oxford University Computing Services.

It is your responsibility, as a user, to ensure that an End
User Licence is in place.  For your information, the Terms
of the End User Licence are set out in the corpus header, which is
likely to have a file name similar to "corphdr" or "CORPHDR".

Distribution of any part of the corpus under the terms of
the Licence must include a copy of the corpus header.
Distribution of this corpus text under the terms of the
Licence must include this header embodying this notice.

THE EXACT CONDITIONS OF USE FOR THIS TEXT ARE NOT CURRENTLY
KNOWN TO THE ARCHIVING AGENCY.  PLEASE CONTACT THE DATA
CAPTURE AGENCY NAMED IN THIS HEADER FOR FURTHER INFORMATION.
</avail>
<date value=1997-03-10>
1997-03-10
</date>
</pubStmt>
<srcDesc>
<biblStr>
<monogr>
<title>
Computers and the humanities
</title>
<author n=KennyA1 domicile=Oxford>
Kenny, A
</author>
</monogr>
</biblStr>
</srcDesc>

</fileDesc>
<encDesc>
<projDesc>
See the project description in the corpus header for
information about the British National Corpus project.
</projDesc>
<refsDecl>
Canonical references in the British National Corpus
are to text segment (&lt;s&gt;) elements, and
are constructed by taking the value of the n attribute
of the &lt;cdif&gt; element containing the target text,
and concatenating a dot separator, followed by the value
of the n attribute of the target &lt;s&gt; element.
</refsDecl>
<tagsDecl>
<tagUsage gi=c occurs=641>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=div1 occurs=1>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=div2 occurs=1>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=head occurs=5>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=item occurs=18>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=label occurs=6>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=list occurs=2>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=p occurs=42>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=reg occurs=9>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=s occurs=225>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=text occurs=1>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=w occurs=5551>
</tagUsage>
</tagsDecl>
</encDesc>
<profDesc>
<creation date=1992>
</creation>
<txtClass>
<catRef target="allava0 alltyp5  wriaag0 wriad922 wriase1 wriaty3 wriaud3 wridom3 wrilev3 wrimed4 wripp922 wrisam0 wrista1 writas3  ">
<keywords>
<term>
computing
</term>
</keywords>
</txtClass>
</profDesc>
<revDesc>
<change><date>2 Feb 1999</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>Normalize S numbers</name></respStmt>
</change>
<change><date>16 Oct 98</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>oneLinePatch</name></respStmt>
</change>
<change><date>10 May 97</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>catRefPatch</name></respStmt>
</change><change n=s1>
<date value=1997-03-10>
1997-03-10
</date>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Amendments for initial release of sampler
</resp>
<name>
dominic
</name>
</respStmt>
</change>
<change n=1>
<date value=1994-11-24>
1994-11-24
</date>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Initial accession to corpus
</resp>
<name>
dominic
</name>
</respStmt>
</change>
</revDesc>
</header>
<text decls="CN001 QN000 SN001" complete=Y org=SEQ>
<div1 complete=Y org=SEQ>
<head type=MAIN>
<s n=0001><w AT>The <w MD>Ninth <w JJ>British <w NN1>Library <w NN1>Research <w NN1>Lecture </s>
</head>
<head type=SUB>
<s n=0002><w NN2>Computers <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities </s>
</head>
<head type=BYLINE>
<s n=0003><w NP1>Anthony <w NP1>Kenny </s>
</head>
<head type=SUB>
<s n=0004><w AT>The <w NP1>British <w NNL1>Library <w MC>1992 </s>
</head>
<p>
<s n=0005><w NN2>Scholars <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities<c YCOM>, <w II>like <w NN2>researchers <w II>in <w JJ>other <w NN2>subjects<c YCOM>, <w VV0>make <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w IF>for <w NN1>word-processing<c YCOM>, <w IF>for <w VVG>cataloguing <w AT>the <w NN2>books <w II>in <w APPGE>their <w JJ>departmental <w NN2>libraries<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>also <w IF>for <w NN1>desk-top <w NN1>publishing<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0006><w DD1>This <w JJ>generic <w NN1>computer <w NN1>use <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w APPGE>my <w NN1>topic<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0007><w PPIS1>I <w VV0>want <w TO>to <w VVI>talk <w II>about <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w II>in <w JJ>actual <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>features <w IO>of <w DD1>that <w NN1>use <w DDQ>which <w VV0>derive <w II>from <w AT>the <w JJ>special <w NN2>characteristics <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0008><w NN1>University <w NN2>lecturers <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w VBR>are <w VVG>making <w JJ>increasing <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w IF>for <w NN1>teaching <w NN2>purposes<c YSCOL>; <w CCB>but <w DD1>this <w RR>too <w VVZ>lies <w II>outside <w APPGE>my <w NN1>scope<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0009><w AT>The <w NN2>uses <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w II>in <w NN2>humanities <w NN1>research <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>divided <w II>into <w MC>three <w JJ>main <w NN2>kinds<c YCOM>, <w II>depending on <w AT>the <w NN1>nature <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>objects <w VVN>studied<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0010><w ZZ1>A <w NN2>humanities <w NN1>researcher <w VM>may <w VVI>use <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w NN2>strings <c YBL>(<w CSA>as <w II>in <w JJ>natural <w NN1>language <w NN1>processing <w CC>or <w AT>the <w NN1>analysis <w IO>of <w JJ>literary <w NN2>texts<c YBR>) <w CC>or <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w NN2>numbers <c YBL>(<w IO>of <w JJ>discrete <w NN2>items <w CC>or <w NN2>events<c YCOM>, <w CSA>as <w II>in <w JJ>social <w CC>and <w JJ>economic <w NN1>history<c YBR>) <w CC>or <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w NN2>icons<c YCOM>, <w CSW>whether <w JJ>visual <c YBL>(<w CSA>as <w II>in <w NN1>art <w NN1>history<c YBR>)<c YCOM>, <w CC>or <w JJ>acoustic<c YBL>(<w CSA>as <w II>in <w NN1>musicology<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0011><w RR>Of course <w JJ>individual <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines <w VV0>make <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w RR>more than <w MC1>one <w IO>of <w DD2>these <w NN2>types <w IO>of <w NN1>computer <w NN1>study<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>student <w IO>of <w JJ>literary <w NN1>style <w VM>will <w VVI>make <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>frequency <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>lexical <w NN2>strings <w CC>and <w JJ>grammatical <w NN2>features <w VVN>identified <w II>in <w APPGE>his <w JJ>chosen <w NN1>text<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w NN1>historian <w VM>may <w VHI>have <w NN1>occasion <w TO>to <w VVI>search <w II>through <w CC>and <w VVI>analyse <w AT>the <w NN2>texts <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w JJ>primary <w NN2>sources <w II>in <w JJ>machine-readable <w NN1>form<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0012><w II>In <w NN1>art <w NN1>history <w AT1>a <w JJ>large <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w JJ>electronic <w NN>data <w NN1>processing <w VVZ>takes <w AT>the <w NN1>form <w IO>of <w VVG>cataloguing <w NN2>works <w IO>of <w NN1>art<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>only <w AT1>a <w JJ>small <w NN1>proportion <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w VVZ>concerns <w NN1>pattern <w NN1>recognition <w CC>or <w NN1>digitization <w IO>of <w NN2>images<c YSCOL>; <w II>in <w NN1>musicology <w PPH1>it <w VHZ>has <w RR>only <w RR>recently <w VVN>become <w JJ>possible <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w NN2>scores <w RR>directly <w VVN>input <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w IW>without <w AT>the <w NN1>mediation <w IO>of <w JJ>alphanumeric <w NN1>code<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0013><w II>In <w DB>all <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VBZ>is <w VVN>used <w II>in <w AT1>an <w NN1>endeavour <w TO>to <w VVI>replace <w NN1>intuition <w IW>with <w NN1>quantification<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0014><w NN2>Linguists<c YCOM>, <w NN2>students <w IO>of <w NN1>literature<c YCOM>, <w NN1>art <w NN2>historians <w CC>and <w NN2>musicologists <w DB>all <w VV0>seek <w TO>to <w VVI>identify <w NN2>styles<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>similarity <w CC>and <w NN2>differences <w II>between <w PPHO2>them<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0015><w JJ>Common <w II>to <w DB>all <w DD2>these <w NN2>disciplines <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w NN1>question<c YCOL>: <w DDQ>what <w NN>statistics <w VV0>define <w AT1>a <w NN1>style<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0016><w RGQ>How <w RR>far <w VM>can <w AT1>a <w NN1>style <w VBI>be <w VVN>identified <w IW>with <w AT1>an <w NN1>aggregate <w IO>of <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>features<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0017><reg sic=Similary> <w RR>Similarly </reg><c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w NN1>historian <w VM>will <w VVI>make <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>techniques <w TO>to <w VVI>give <w JJ>objective <w NN1>substance <w II>to <w RR>intuitively <w VVD>sensed <w JJ>historical <w NN2>processes <w CC>or <w NN2>trends<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0018><w II>In <w DB>all <w NN2>humanities <w VVZ>disciplines <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w VVZ>seems <w TO>to <w VHI>have <w VVN>passed <w II>through <w MC>three <w NN2>stages<c YCOM>, <w DD1>each <w JJ>corresponding <w RR>roughly <w II>to <w AT1>a <w NNT1>decade<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0019><w AT>The <w MD>first <w NN1>stage <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w NN1>period <w IO>of <w VVG>pioneering <w NN1>work<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w JJ>abortive <w MD>first <w NN2>attempts <w II>at <w NN1>machine <w NN1>translation<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w JJT>earliest <w NN1>computer <w NN2>concordances<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w JJ>early <w NN1>authorship <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w NP1>Morton<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Ellegard<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Mosteller <w CC>and <w NP1>Wallace<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w MD>first <w NN2>conferences <w II>on <w VVG>computing <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <c YBL>(<w MCMC>1964&ndash;7<c YBR>) <w CC>and <w AT>the <w RGR>more <w JJ>specialised <w NN2>ones <w II>in <w NN1>history <w CC>and <w NN1>anthropology <c YBL>(<w II>from <w MC>1962<c YBR>) <w CC>and <w II>in <w NN1>literature <w CC>and <w NN1>linguistics <c YBL>(<w II>from <w MC>1970<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0020><w II>During <w DD1>this <w NN1>period <w NN2>concordances <w II>to <w DA2>many <w JJ>major <w NN>works <w IO>of <w NN1>literature <w VBDR>were <w VVN>produced <w II>by <w NN1>computer<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VVD>published <w II>in <w JJ>traditional <w JJ>hard <w NN1>copy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0021><w DA2>Many <w IO>of <w DD2>these <w JJ>early <w NN2>projects <w VBDR>were <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w JJ>interdisciplinary <w NN1>research <w NN2>teams<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w XX>not <w RR>only <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>scholars <w CCB>but <w JJ>senior <w NN1>information <w NN2>scientists<c YCOM>, <w JJ>responsible <w IF>for <w JJ>custom-designed <w NN1>software<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0022><w DD1>This <w NN1>period <w VVD>lasted <w CS>until <w II>about <w AT>the <w NN1>end <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MC2>sixties<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0023><w AT>The <w MD>second <w NN1>period <w VVD>lasted <w II>through <w AT>the <w MC2>seventies <w II>until <w AT>the <w JJ>early <w MC2>eighties<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0024><w NN2>Humanities <w NN2>scholars <w VVD>learned <w RRQ>how <w TO>to <w VVI>write <w APPGE>their <w DA>own <w NN2>programs<c YCOM>, <w CSA>as <w NN1>programming <w NN2>languages <w VVD>became <w JJR>easier <w TO>to <w VVI>master<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0025><w CCB>But <w RGR>more <w RR>significantly <w AT>the <w NN1>development <w CC>and <w JJ>widespread <w NN1>availability <w IO>of <w JJ>pre-designed <w NN2>packages<c YCOM>, <w II>such as <w NP1>OCP <c YBL>(<w AT>the <w NP1>Oxford <w NN1>Concordance <w NN1>Package<c YBR>) <w IF>for <w NN1>concordance <w NN1>construction<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NP1>SPSS <c YBL>(<w JJ>Statistical <w NN1>Package <w IF>for <w JJ>Social <w NN2>Sciences<c YBR>) <w IF>for <w JJ>statistical <w NN1>analysis<c YCOM>, <w VVD>meant <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>possible <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>humanist <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w RGR>more <w JJ>independent <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>computing <w NN2>experts<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w TO>to <w VVI>operate <w IW>with <w RR>at most <w JJ>low-level <w NN1>assistance<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0026><w II>In <w NN1>history<c YCOM>, <w RR>in particular<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w TO>to <w VVI>provide <w NN1>material <w IF>for <w NN1>use <w II>in <w NN2>monographs<c YCOM>, <w CS>once <w AT1>a <w NN1>matter <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>trumpeted <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>text<c YCOM>, <w VVD>became <w AT1>a <w NN1>commonplace <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>noted <w IW>without <w NN1>elaboration <w II>in <w NN2>footnotes<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0027><w NN2>Humanities <w NN1>computing <w NN2>centres <w VBDR>were <w VVN>set <w RP>up <w II>in <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Liege<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Tubingen <w CC>and <w JJ>other <w NN2>places<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0028><w CS>While <w AT>the <w NN1>availability <w IO>of <w NN2>systems <w II>such as <w NP1>SPSS <w VVD>meant <w CST>that <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w NN1>temptation <w IF>for <w NN2>humanists <w TO>to <w VVI>fit <w APPGE>their <w JJ>special <w NN>data <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>software<c YCOM>, <w CS>rather than <w TO>to <w VVI>design <w NN1>software <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN>data<c YCOM>, <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w NN1>hand <w EX>there <w VVD>began <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>developed <w NN2>systems <w IF>for <w JJ>source-oriented <w NN>data <w NN1>entry<c YCOM>, <w IO>of <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w RGT>most <w JJ>famous <w VBDZ>was <w NP1>CLIO<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0029><w II>Throughout <w AT>the <w MC2>seventies <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>early <w MC2>eighties<c YCOM>, <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>scholars<c YCOM>, <w II>despite <w APPGE>their <w JJ>growing <w NN1>independence<c YCOM>, <w RR>still <w VVD>worked <w II>in <w NN1>collaboration <w IW>with<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>usually <w II>in <w NN1>proximity <w II>to<c YCOM>, <w APPGE>their <w NN2>colleagues <w II>in <w NN1>computing <w NN2>centres<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0030><w IW>With <w AT>the <w NN1>advent <w IO>of <w JJ>cheap <w NN2>microcomputers <w II>in <w AT>the <w MC2>mid-eighties<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>typical <w NN2>humanities <w NN1>scholar <w VBDZ>was <w RGR>more <w JJ>likely <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>found <w VDG>doing <w NN1>research <w II>at <w RL>home <w II>on <w AT1>a <w JJ>personal <w NN1>computer<c YCOM>, <w VVN>attached <w RR>no doubt <w II>to <w AT1>a <w NN1>network<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VVN>engaged <w RR>much <w RGR>less <w RR>interactively <w IW>with <reg sic=colleqgues> <w NN2>colleagues </reg> <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>computing <w NN1>centre<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0031><w II>As <w AT1>a <w NN1>result <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>microcomputer <w NN1>revolution<c YCOM>, <w JJ>electronic <w NN>data <w NN1>processing <w VHZ>has <w VVN>become <w AT1>a <w JJ>familiar <w NN1>feature <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w II>in <w DAT>most <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0032><w RT>Nowadays<c YCOM>, <w PPIS1>I <w VBM>am <w VVN>told<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w NP1>Germany <w DAT>most <w JJ>doctoral <w NN2>students <w II>in <w NN1>history <w VV0>make <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers<c YCOM>, <w XX>not <w RR>just <w IF>for <w NN1>word <w NN1>processing<c YCOM>, <w II>at <w DD>some <w NN1>stage <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w NN2>studies<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0033><w RR>No doubt <w DD1>this <w VM>will <w RR>shortly <w VBI>be <w AT>the <w NN1>case<c YCOM>, <w CS>where <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w RR>so <w RR>already<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w JJ>other <w JJ>European <w NN2>countries<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0034><w AT>The <w NN1>building <w IO>of <w JJ>large <w NN2>databases<c YCOM>, <w CSW>whether <w JJ>unstructured<c YBL>(<w II>like <w NN2>text-archives<c YBR>) <w CC>or <w JJ>structured <c YBL>(<w II>like <w DA2>many <w JJ>historical <w NN2>databases<c YBR>) <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w AT1>a <w JJ>major <w NN1>preoccupation <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>period<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0035><w AT>The <w NN1>development <w IO>of <w NP1>CD-ROM <w NN2>techniques <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w IO>of <w JJ>particular <reg sic=signficance> <w NN1>significance </reg> <w IF>for <w NN2>students <w IO>of <w NN2>texts<c YCOL>: <w NN2>classics <w NN2>students <w VM>can <w VVI>search <w AT>the <w JJ>complete <w NN1>database <w IO>of <w JJ>ancient <w NN1>literature <w II>by <w VVG>using <w AT>the <w NP1>IBYCUS <w NN1>implementation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Thesaurus <w FW>Linguae <w FW>Graecae<c YSCOL>; <w NN2>students <w IO>of <w NN1>English <w VM>can <w VVI>use <w AT>the <w NP1>CD-ROM <w NN1>version <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Oxford <w NN1>English <w NN1>Dictionary <w TO>to <w VVI>conduct <w NN2>searches <w DDQ>which <w VM>would <w VVI>take <w NNT2>lifetimes <w CS>if <w VVN>conducted <w II>on <w AT>the <w MC>twenty <w NN2>volumes <w IO>of <w JJ>hard <w NN1>copy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0036><w II>In <w NN1>archaeology<c YCOM>, <w PPIS1>I <w VV0>understand<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VM>can <w RT>now <w VBI>be <w VVN>said <w CST>that <w NN2>computers <w VBR>are <w RR>automatically <w VVN>considered <w IF>for <w DD>any <w NN1>project<c YCOM>, <w RGQV>however <w JJ>small<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0037><w II>Throughout <w DD2>these <w NN2>stages <w IO>of <w NN1>development<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>research <w VVN>conducted <w II>by <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>scholars <w VHZ>has <w VVN>taken <w NN1>place <w II>at <w MC>three <w NN2>levels<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0038><w AT>The <w JJT>lowest<c YCOM>, <w RGT>most <w JJ>general<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RGT>most <w RR>unambiguously <w JJ>useful <w NN1>level <w VVZ>consists <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>employment <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer <w TO>to <w VVI>perform <w AT1>a <w JJ>humdrum <w NN1>task <w II>in <w DAR>less <w NNT1>time <w CSN>than <w VM>would <w VBI>be <w JJ>possible <w IF>for <w AT1>an <w JJ>unaided <w NN1>human<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>search <w II>through <w AT1>a <w NN1>text <w IF>for <w AT1>a <w NN1>quotation<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>determination <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>word <w NN1>frequency<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>construction <w CC>and <w NN1>analysis <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>contingency <w NN1>table<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>classification <w IO>of <w JJ>iconic <w NN>data<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0039><w DD1>This <w NN1>kind <w IO>of <w NN1>activity <w VM>will <w VVI>leave <w DA1>little <w JJ>visible <w NN1>trace <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>published <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>researcher<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0040><w II>At <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w NN1>end <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>scale <w EX>there <w VBR>are <w JJ>ambitious <w NN1>research <w NN2>projects <w VVN>undertaken <w IF>for <w JJ>methodical <w NN1>demonstration <w NN2>purposes<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0041><w AT>The <w NN2>results <w VBR>are <w VVN>sought <w XX>not <w RG>so <w RR>much <w TO>to <w VVI>enrich <w AT>the <w NN1>domain <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w IW>with <w RR>fundamentally <w JJ>new <w NN2>findings <w CSA>as <w TO>to <w VVI>demonstrate <w AT>the <w NN1>validity <w IO>of <w DD>some <w JJ>new <w NN1>form <w IO>of <w JJ>automatic <w NN1>processing<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0042><w MC>Two <w NN2>examples <w IO>of <w DA>such <w NN2>projects <w VBR>are <w VVN>discussed <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>recent <w NN1>paper <w II>by <w NP1>Manfred <w NP1>Thaller<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0043><w II>In <w NP1>France <w NP1>Gian <w NP1>Piero <w NP1>Zarri <w VHZ>has <w VVN>developed <w AT1>a <w NN1>system <w VVN>known <w II>as <w NP1>RESEDA <w TO>to <w VVI>allow <w JJ>Artificial <w NN1>Intelligence <w NN2>techniques <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>applied <w II>to <w JJ>historical <w NN1>source <w NN1>material <c YBL>(<w II>concerning <w AT>the <w NNO>Hundred <w NNT2>Years <w NN1>War<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0044><w AT>The <w NN1>project <w VBZ>is <w RR>well <w VVN>known <w II>in <w NN1>AI <w NN2>circles<c YSCOL>; <w CCB>but <w PPH1>it <w VVZ>seems <w TO>to <w VHI>have <w VVN>left <w RR>virtually <w AT>no <w NN1>trace <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>historical <w NN1>literature<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0045><w DD1>This <w VBZ>is <w CS>because <w AT>the <w NN1>system <w VBZ>is <w RG>so <w JJ>complicated <w CST>that <w AT>no <w NN1>historian <w VM>could <w VVI>use <w PPH1>it <w IW>without <w JJ>explicit <w NN1>support <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN1>AI <w NN1>project <w NN1>group<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0046><w RT>Again<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w MCMC>1981&ndash;7 <w AT>the <w NP1>Volkswagenstiftung <w VVD>funded <w II>on <w AT1>a <w JJ>large <w NN1>scale <w AT>the <w NP1>ARCOS <w NN1>project<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w NN1>system <w DDQ>which <w VVZ>photographs <w AT1>a <w JJ>three-dimensional <w JJ>archaeological <w NN1>object<c YCOM>, <w VVZ>provides <w AT1>a <w NN1>drawing <w CC>and <w VVZ>converts <w PPH1>it <w II>into <w NN>data <w DDQ>which <w VV0>lend <w PPX2>themselves <w RR>easily <w II>to <w NN2>methods <w II>like <w NN1>Cluster <w NN1>Analysis<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0047><w AT>The <w NN1>prototype <w VBDZ>was <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>vanguard <w IO>of <w JJ>technical <w NN1>development<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0048><w RR>Unfortunately <w AT>the <w NN1>price <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>prototype <w VBDZ>was <w RG>so <w JJ>high <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w II>out of <w AT>the <w JJ>financial <w NN1>reach <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>archaeological <w NN1>community<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0049><w NN2>Projects <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>kind <w VV0>win <w NN1>reclaim <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>literature <w IO>of <w NN1>AI<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VV0>pass <w RR>almost <w IW>without <w NN1>remark <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>parent <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines <w II>such as <w NN1>history <w CC>and <w NN1>archaeology<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0050><w RRQ>Where<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w NN1>fact<c YCOM>, <w VBR>are <w PPIS2>we <w TO>to <w VVI>look <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>major <w NN2>effects <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w II>in <w NN2>humanities <w NN1>research<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0051><w AT>The <w RGT>most <w JJ>spectacular <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w NN1>creation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>whole <w JJ>new <w NN1>topic <w IO>of <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w NN1>discipline <w IO>of <w JJ>computational <w NN1>linguistics<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0052><w AT>The <w RGT>most <w RR>widely <w VVN>felt <w NN1>effect <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w AT>the <w NN1>perfecting <w IO>of <w JJ>traditional <w NN2>tools <w IO>of <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w NN2>data-collections<c YCOM>, <w NN2>concordances<c YCOM>, <w NN2>dictionaries<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN2>corpora<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0053><w JJ>New <w NN2>tools <w IO>of <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w JJ>new <w NN2>testbeds <w IF>for <w NN2>theories <w VV0>become <w JJ>possible<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0054><w RR>Perhaps <w AT>the <w RGT>most <w JJ>dramatic <w NN1>opportunity <w VBG>being <w VVN>developed <w IF>for <w JJ>linguistic <w NN2>studies <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w JJ>National <w NN1>Corpus<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0055><w DD1>This <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w JJ>collaborative <w NN1>venture<c YCOM>, <w VVG>involving <w MC>three <w NN2>publishers <c YBL>(<w NP1>OUP<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Longman<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Chambers<c YBR>)<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NP1>British <w NNL1>Library<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w MC>two <w NN2>universities <c YBL>(<w NP1>Oxford <w CC>and <w NP1>Lancaster<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0056><w AT>The <w NN1>aim <w VBZ>is <w TO>to <w VVI>provide <w AT1>a <w NN1>corpus <w IO>of <w MC>100 <w NNO>million <w NN2>words <w IO>of <w JJ>contemporary <w JJ>spoken <w CC>and <w JJ>written <w NN1>English <w TO>to <w VVI>provide <w JJ>raw <w NN>data <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>empirical <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN1>language <w II>by <w AT1>a <w JJ>wide <w NN1>variety <w IO>of <w NN2>disciplines<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0057><w AT>The <w NN1>project <w VVD>started <w II>in <w NPM1>January <w MC>1991 <w IW>with <w AT1>a <w NN1>grant <w II>from <w AT>the <w NP1>DTI <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NP1>SERC<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0058><w CS>When <w JJ>complete <w PPH1>it <w VM>should <w VVI>provide <w AT1>an <w JJ>unparalleled <w NN1>resource <w IF>for <w NN2>lexicographers<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN1>information <w NN2>technologists<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w NN1>test-bed <w IF>for <w JJ>theoretical <w NN2>linguists<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0059><w CCB>But <w II>in spite of <w AT>the <w NN1>multiplication <w IO>of <w JJ>new <w JJ>basic <w NN1>research <w NN2>tools <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w RR>surprisingly <w JJ>difficult <w TO>to <w VVI>point<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w JJ>specific <w NN2>areas<c YCOM>, <w II>to <w JJ>solid<c YCOM>, <w JJ>uncontroverted <w NN2>gains <w II>to <w NN1>scholarship <w DDQ>which <w VM>could <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>achieved <w IW>without <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w NN1>technology<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0060><w AT>The <w JJ>high <w NN2>hopes <w DDQ>which <w DD>some <w NN1>computer <w NN2>enthusiasts <w VVD>held <w RP>out <w CST>that <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VM>would <w VVI>revolutionise <w JJ>humanistic <w NN1>study <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>proved<c YCOM>, <w RP>over <w CC>and <w RP>over <w RT>again<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w JJ>unrealistic<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0061><w RT>Sometimes <w AT>the <w JJ>initial <w NN2>claims <w VVN>made <w VBDR>were <w RR>much <w VVN>exaggerated<c YCOL>: <w CSA>as <w AT>the <w NN1>claim <w VVN>made <w II>in <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w NN2>studies <w CST>that <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VM>would <w IF>for <w AT>the <w MD>first <w NNT1>time <w VVI>reveal <w AT>the <w JJ>true <w NN2>lineaments <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Bible <w CST>that <w PPIS2>we <w VHD>had <w RR>ignorantly <w VVN>worshipped<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0062><w CCB>But <w RR>even <w II>in <w NN2>areas <w RRQ>where <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w AT>no <w NN1>hubris <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>initial <w NN2>claims<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>results <w VVN>delivered <w VH0>have <w RR>often <w VBN>been <w JJ>disappointing<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0063><w II>Between <w JJ>humdrum <w NN1>research <w CC>and <w NN1>showpiece <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>what <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w JJ>scholarly <w NN1>community <w VBZ>is <w RR>really <w JJ>anxious <w TO>to <w VVI>see <w VBZ>is <w NN1>work <w DDQ>which <w VBZ>is <w RR>both <c YBL>(<w ZZ1>a<c YBR>) <w VVN>respected <w II>as <w AT1>an <w JJ>original <w JJ>scholarly <w NN1>contribution <w II>within <w APPGE>its <w DA>own <w NN1>discipline <w CC>and <c YBL>(<w ZZ1>b<c YBR>) <w VM>could <w RR>clearly <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w VBN>been <w VDN>done <w IW>without <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0064><w II>In <w AT>the <w MD>last <w MC>three <w NNT2>decades <w AT>the <w NN1>number <w IO>of <w DA>such <w NN2>contributions <w VBZ>is <w RR>sadly <w JJ>small<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0065><w RR>No doubt <w II>in <w DD1>each <w NN1>discipline <w APPGE>my <w NN2>colleagues <w VM>could <w VVI>single <w RP>out <w AT1>a <w NN1>handful <w IO>of <w JJ>seminal <w NN2>projects<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0066><w DDQ>What <w PPIS1>I <w VV0>want <w TO>to <w VDI>do<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w DD1>this <w MD>second <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w APPGE>my <w NN1>lecture<c YCOM>, <w VBZ>is <w TO>to <w VVI>illustrate <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>field <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w PPIS1>I <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w PPX1>myself <w JJ>involved <c YDSH>&mdash; <w NN1>literature <w CC>and <w NN1>stylistics <c YDSH>&mdash; <w AT>the <w NN1>kind <w IO>of <w NN2>projects <w DDQ>which <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>attempted <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>limited <w NN1>success <w DDQ>which <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w VVN>achieved<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0067><w II>From <w AT>the <w NN1>outset<c YCOM>, <w DD>some <w NN2>scholars <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w RR>highly <w JJ>suspicious <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w JJ>numerical <w NN2>methods <w II>in <w JJ>literary <w NN2>studies<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0068><w DD1>This <w NN1>suspicion <w VBZ>is <w RR>particularly <w JJ>strong <w II>among <w JJ>biblical <w NN2>scholars<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w MC1>one <w IO>of <w PPHO2>them<c YCOM>, <w NNB>Principal <w NP1>T. <w NP1>M. <w NP1>Knox<c YCOM>, <w VVD>said <w RR>more than <w MC>twenty <w NNT2>years <w RA>ago<c YQUO>&bquo;<w AT>The <w NN1>spirit <w VV0>moveth <w RRQ>where <w PPH1>it <w VV0>listeth <w CC>and <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>reduced <w II>to <w AT>the <w JJ>numerical <w NN2>terms <w IW>with <w DDQ>which <w RR>alone <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer <w VM>can <w VVI>cope<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0069><w CCB>But <w DA>such <w NN1>hostility <w II>to <w JJ>numerical <w NN2>methods <w VVZ>seems <w JJ>irrational<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>often <w JJ>inconsistent<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0070><w JJ>Biblical <w NN2>scholars <w VH0>have <w RR>long <w VVN>noticed<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVN>based <w NN2>arguments <w II>on<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>occurrence <w IO>of <w FW>hapax <w FW>legomena<c YCOM>, <w CC>or <w NN2>words <w DDQ>which <w VV0>occur <w RR>once <w RR>only <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>given <w NN1>text <w CC>or <w NN1>author<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0071><w CCB>But <w CS>if <w PN1>one <w VBZ>is <w TO>to <w VVI>allow <w VVG>counting <w RR>at all <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>literary <w NN1>context<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VVZ>seems <w JJ>perverse <w TO>to <w VVI>insist <w CST>that <w VVG>counting <w VM>should <w VVI>stop <w II>at <w AT>the <w NN1>number <w MC1>one <w CC>and <w VVI>go <w RR>no <w RRR>further<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0072><w CS>Since <w RR>long <w II>before <w AT>the <w NN1>invention <w IO>of <w NN2>computers<c YCOM>, <w NN2>students <w IO>of <w JJ>literary <w NN2>texts <w VH0>have <w VVN>made <w JJ>extensive <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>concordances<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0073><w NN2>Concordances <w VBR>are <w RR>often <w RGR>more <w JJ>helpful <w CSN>than <w NN2>dictionaries <w IF>for <w VVG>determining <w AT>the <w JJ>precise <w NN1>sense <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>word <w II>in <w AT1>an <w NN1>author<w GE>'s <w NN1>vocabulary<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w PPHS2>they <w VV0>enable <w JJ>favourite <w NN2>phrases <w CC>and <w NN2>tricks <w IO>of <w NN1>style <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>identified <w CC>and <w VVN>catalogued<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0074><w TO>To <w VVI>make <w AT1>a <w NN1>concordance <w IO>of <w AT1>a <reg sic=lenghty> <w JJ>lengthy </reg> <w NN1>text <w II>by <w NN1>hand <w VVZ>calls <w IF>for <w NNT2>months <w CC>or <w NNT2>years <w IO>of <w JJ>tedious <w NN1>labour<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0075><w IW>With <w AT>the <w NN1>aid <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer<c YCOM>, <w NN2>concordances <w IO>of <w DA2>many <w NN2>kinds <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>made <w IW>with <w RR>comparatively <w DA1>little <w NN1>difficulty<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0076><w NN2>Students <w IO>of <w NN1>literature <w PNQS>who <w VVD>used <w NN1>concordance <w NN2>packages <w II>on <w NN2>mainframes <w RR>commonly <w VVD>asked <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w TO>to <w VVI>produce <w IF>for <w PPHO2>them <w AT1>a <w JJ>complete <w NN1>print-out <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w JJ>chosen <w NN1>concordance<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RT>then <w VVD>took <w PPH1>it <w RL>home <w TO>to <w VVI>consult <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>traditional <w NN1>manner<c YCOM>, <w VVG>turning <w AT>the <w NN2>pages <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>sheaf <w IO>of <w NN1>paper<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0077><w VVG>Producing <w DA2>several <w NNO>hundred <w NN2>pages <w IO>of <w JJ>hard <w NN1>copy <w IW>with <w AT1>a <w JJ>desk-top <w NN1>computer <w CC>and <w NN1>printer <w VM>would <w VBI>be <w AT1>a <w JJ>long <w CC>and <w JJ>tedious <w NN1>business<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0078><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w RR>much <w RGR>more <w JJ>common <w RT>now <w TO>to <w VVI>use <w AT>the <w NN2>facilities <w VVN>provided <w II>by <w AT1>a <w NN1>package <w II>such as <w NP1>micro-OCP <w TO>to <w VVI>generate <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w NN1>concordance <w NN1>entry <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>screen <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>PC <w RR>directly <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN1>text-base <w RRQV>whenever <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w VVN>needed<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0079><w RR>Thus<c YCOM>, <w CS>if <w PPY>you <w VV0>want <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>word <c YQUO>&bquo; <w JJ>true<c YQUO>&equo; <w II>in <w NP1>Arthur <w NP1>Hugh <w NP1>Clough<c YCOM>, <w II>rather than <w VVI>generate <w AT1>a <w JJ>massive <w NN1>concordance <w VVG>containing <w DB>all <w AT>the <w NN2>words <w II>in <w NP1>Clough<w GE>'s <w NN2>poems<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RT>then <w VVG>leafing <w II>through <w PPH1>it <w TO>to <w VVI>find <w AT>the <w NN1>word<c YQUO>&bquo;<w JJ>true<c YQUO>&equo;<c YCOM>, <w PPY>you <w VV0>use <w AT>the <w NN1>concordance <w NN1>package <w NN2>commands <w TO>to <w VVI>generate <w AT1>a <w NN1>concordance <w DDQ>which <w VVZ>contains <w DB>all <w CC>and <w RR>only <w AT>the <w NN2>uses <w IO>of <c YQUO>&bquo;<w JJ>true<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0080><w PPY>You <w RT>then <w VV0>consult <w DD1>that <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>screen <w CC>and <w VV0>print <w PPH1>it <w RP>out <w RR>only <w CS>if <w PPY>you <w VV0>think <w PPY>you <w VBR>are <w VVGK>going <w TO>to <w VVI>want <w TO>to <w VVI>look <w RP>up <w AT>the <w DA>same <w NN1>word <w RT>again<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0081><w NN2>Concordances <w VVN>produced <w II>by <w NN1>computer <w VM>may <w VVI>differ <w II>from <w JJ>traditional <w JJ>hand-made <w NN2>concordances <w II>in <w DA2>several <w NN2>ways<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0082><w MC1>One <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w PPHS2>they <w VM>will <w VBI>be <w RR>much <w RGR>more <w JJ>complete<c YCOL>: <w PPHS2>they <w VM>will <w VVI>contain <w DB>all <w AT>the <w JJ>tiny <w NN1>function <w NN2>words <w DDQ>which <w VBDR>were <w RG>too <w JJ>frequent<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVN>regarded <w II>as <w RG>too <w JJ>unimportant<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VVI>figure <w II>in <w AT1>a <w NN1>work <w II>like <w NP1>Cruden<w GE>'s <w NN1>Concordance <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN2>Scriptures<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0083><w RGR>More <w RR>interestingly<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>items <w DDQ>which <w VV0>provide <w AT>the <w NN1>focus <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>concordance <w VM>need <w XX>not <w VBI>be <w NN1>dictionary <w NN2>headings <w CC>or <w RR>even <w NN1>vocabulary <w NN2>words <w RR>at all<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0084><w AT1>A <w JJ>particular <w JJ>grammatical <w NN1>feature<c YCOM>, <w II>rather than <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w JJ>lexical <w NN1>item<c YCOM>, <w VM>may <w VVI>provide <w AT>the <w NN1>focus <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>concordance<c YSCOL>; <w RR>thus<c YCOM>, <w PPY>you <w VM>may <w VVI>look <w RP>up<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT1>a <w NP1>Virgil <w NN1>concordance<c YCOM>, <w XX>not <w AT>the <w NN2>occurrences <w IO>of <c YQUO>&bquo;<w FW>bellum<c YQUO>&equo;<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w AT>the <reg sic=occurences> <w NN2>occurrences </reg> <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>second <w NN1>declension <w JJ>neuter <w JJ>singular <w JJ>nominative <w NN1>noun<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0085><w NN2>Concordances <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>kind <w II>to <w AT>the <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>produced <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>basis <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Analytical <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w VVN>compiled <w II>by <w NP1>Barbara <w CC>and <w NP1>Timothy <w NP1>Friberg <c YBL>(<w NP1>Baker <w NN2>Books<c YCOM>, <w MC>1981<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0086><w DDQ>What <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>literary <w NN1>scholar <w TO>to <w VDI>do <w IW>with <w DB>all <w AT>the <w NN1>information <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>found <w II>in <w AT>the <reg sic=concordanes> <w NN2>concordances </reg> <w CC>and <w NN2>word-lists <w VVN>generated <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w NN1>technology<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0087><w DA1>Much <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>material <w VM>will <w RR>no doubt <w VBI>be <w VVN>exploited <w II>in <w DB>all <w NN2>kinds <w IO>of <w JJ>traditional <w NN2>ways<c YCOM>, <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN1>meaning<c YCOM>, <w NN1>style<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN1>language <w NN1>history<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0088><w CCB>But <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w RR>also <w VVZ>facilitates <w MC1>one <w JJ>particular <w NN1>type <w IO>of <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN2>texts<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w JJ>quantifiable <w NN2>features <w II>by <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>methods<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0089><w AT>The <w JJ>statistical <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN1>style <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>discipline <w DDQ>which <w VBZ>is <w RR>still <w II>in <w APPGE>its <w NN1>infancy<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VHZ>has <w RR>recently <w VBN>been <w VVG>showing <w NN2>signs <w IO>of <w JJ>vigorous <w NN1>growth<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0090><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w RR>often <w VVN>called <c YQUO>&bquo;<w NN1>stylometry<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0091><w JJ>Stylometric <w NN2>studies <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w VVN>undertaken <w IF>for <w DA2>many <w JJ>different <w NN2>reasons<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0092><w PN1>One <w VM>may <w VVI>wish <w TO>to <w VVI>study <w AT>the <w NN>statistics <w IO>of <w NN1>word <w NN1>usage <w CC>or <w NN1>word <w NN1>order <w II>with a view to <w VVG>understanding <w AT1>a <w NN1>text <w RRR>better<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VVI>catch <w NN2>nuances <w IO>of <w NN1>meaning <w CC>and <w RR>perhaps <w TO>to <w VVI>render <w PPHO2>them <w II>into <w AT1>a <w JJ>different <w NN1>language<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0093><w CC>Or <w PN1>one <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w JJ>interested <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>history <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>development <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>language<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVI>study <w AT>the <w NN1>speech <w NN2>habits <w IO>of <w JJ>particular <w NN2>authors <w II>as <w AT1>an <w NN1>indication <w IO>of <w JJ>linguistic <w NN1>change<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0094><w CC>Or <w PN1>one <w VM>may <w VVI>hope <w TO>to <w VVI>use <w AT>the <w JJ>quantifiable <w NN2>features <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>text <w II>as <w AT1>an <w NN1>indication <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>authorship <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>text <w CS>when <w DD1>this <w VBZ>is <w II>in <w NN1>question<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0095><w NN1>Authorship <w NN1>attribution <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>kind <w VH0>have <w VVN>caught <w AT>the <w NN1>public <w NN1>eye <w RG>rather <w RRR>more <w CSN>than <w JJ>other <w NN2>types <w IO>of <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>inquiry<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0096><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w RT>sometimes <w VVN>claimed <w CST>that <w NN1>stylometry <w VVZ>enables <w AT>the <w NN1>scholar <w TO>to <w VVI>identify <w AT>the <w NN1>fingerprint <w IO>of <w AT1>an <w NN1>author<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>stylistic <w NN1>criterion<c YCOM>, <w CC>or <w NN1>set <w IO>of <w NN2>criteria<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>used <w TO>to <w VVI>determine <w IW>with <w NN1>certainty <w NN2>questions <w IO>of <w JJ>disputed <w NN1>authorship<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0097><w DA>Such <w NN2>claims <w VV0>seem <w JJ>exaggerated<c YCOM>, <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>basis <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>evidence <w VVN>presented <w RT>hitherto<c YSCOL>; <w CCB>but <w EX>there <w VBZ>is <w AT>no <w NN1>doubt <w CST>that <w NN1>stylometry <w VM>can <w VVI>offer <w JJ>valuable <w NN1>evidence <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>novel <w NN1>kind <w DDQ>which<c YCOM>, <w VVN>taken <w II>in conjunction with <w RGR>more <w JJ>traditional <w NN1>evidence<c YCOM>, <w VM>can <w RR>often <w VVI>throw <w JJ>new <w NN1>light <w II>on <w JJ>ancient <w NN2>problems<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0098><w AT>The <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w FW>hapax <w FW>legomena <w VVD>formed <w AT>the <w NN1>basis <w IO>of <w MC1>one <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJT>earliest <w JJ>sophisticated <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Bible<c YCOM>, <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w NP1>K. <w NP1>Grayston <w CC>and <w NP1>G. <w NP1>Herdan <w II>in <w MC>1960<c YCOM>, <w PNQS>who<c YCOM>, <w VVG>building <w II>on <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w NP1>P. <w NP1>N. <w NP1>Harrison <w II>in <w AT>the <w MC>nineteen <w MC2>twenties<c YCOM>, <w VVD>argued <w CST>that <w AT>the <w JJ>Pastoral <w NN2>Epistles <w VM>could <w XX>not <w VBI>be <w AT>the <w JJ>authentic <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Apostle <w NP1>Paul<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0099><w RR>Probably <w AT>the <w RRT>best <w VVN>known <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>work <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w VBZ>is <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w NP1>A. <w NP1>Q. <w NP1>Morton<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0100><w NP1>Morton<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w NN1>collaboration <w IW>with <w NN2>others<c YCOM>, <w VHZ>has <w VVN>argued<c YCOM>, <w II>from <w MC>1966 <w II>to <w AT>the <w JJ>present <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w CST>that <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>Pauline <w NN1>corpus <w RR>only <w NN2>Romans<c YCOM>, <w MC1>1 <w CC>and <w MC>2 <w NN2>Corinthians<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN2>Galatians <w VV0>form <w AT1>a <w JJ>homogeneous <w NN1>group <w DDQ>which <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>attributed <w II>to <w AT1>a <w JJ>single <w NN1>hand<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0101><w NP1>Morton<w GE>'s <w NN2>arguments <w VBDR>were <w VVN>based <w II>on <w AT1>a <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN1>sentence <w NN2>lengths<c YCOM>, <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN2>frequencies <w IO>of <w JJ>common <w NN2>words<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>on <w JJ>other <w JJ>grammatical <w NN2>features <w II>such as <w AT>the <w NN1>proportion <w IO>of <w JJ>different <w NN2>parts <w IO>of <w NN1>speech<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0102><w APPGE>My <w DA>own <w NN2>investigations <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN1>NT<c YCOM>, <w VVN>based <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>full <w NN>data <w VVN>provided <w II>by <w AT>the <w NP1>Friberg <w JJ>Analytical <w NN1>NT<c YCOM>, <w VVD>came <w II>to <w RR>much <w RGR>less <w JJ>dramatic <w NN2>conclusions <w CSN>than <w NP1>Morton<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0103><w PPIS1>I <w VVD>addressed <w MD>first <w MC>two <w JJ>ancient <w NN2>problems<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>relationship <w II>between <w NP1>Luke <w CC>and <w NN2>Acts <c YBL>(<w PPIS1>I <w VVD>found <w CST>that <w NN2>Acts <w VVD>resembled <w NP1>Luke <w RRR>more <w CSN>than <w PPH1>it <w VVD>resembled <w DD>any <w JJ>other <w NN1>book <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>NT<c YBR>) <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>relationship <w II>between <w AT>the <w NN1>Apocalypse <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>Gospel <w IO>of <w NP1>St <w NP1>John<c YBL>(<w PPIS1>I <w VVD>found <w CST>that <w PPHS2>they <w VVD>differed <w II>from <w PPX2>each other <w RRR>more <w CSN>than <w DD>any <w JJ>other <w MC>two <w NN2>books <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>NT<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0104><w II>On <w AT>the <w RGR>more <w JJ>difficult <w NN1>topic <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Pauline <w NN1>corpus <w PPIS1>I <w VVD>concluded <w CST>that <w AT>the <w NN1>evidence <w VBDZ>was <w RR>equally <w JJ>compatible <w IW>with <w AT1>a <w RR>widely <w VVG>differing <w NN1>set <w IO>of <w NN2>authors <w CC>or <w AT1>a <w JJ>single <w RR>unusually <w JJ>versatile <w NN1>author<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VDD>did <w XX>not <w VVI>support <w AT>the <w NN1>view <w CST>that <w MC>four <w NN2>epistles <w VVD>stood <w RP>out <w CSA>as <w JJ>uniform <w II>by <w NN1>comparison <w IW>with <w DB>all <w NN2>others<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0105><w AT>The <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN1>stylometry <w II>in <w NN1>authorship <w NN1>attribution <w NN2>studies <w VVZ>depends <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>hypothesis <w CST>that <w EX>there <w VBR>are <w JJ>quantifiable <w NN2>features <w IO>of <w NN1>style <w DDQ>which <w VBR>are <w JJ>characteristic <w IO>of <w JJ>particular <w NN2>authors<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0106><w RR>Ideally<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>test <w IO>of <w NN1>authorship <w VM>should <w VBI>be <w AT1>a <w NN1>feature <w DDQ>which <w VBZ>is <w JJ>characteristic <w IO>of <w DB>all <w AT>the <w JJ>known <w NN2>works <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w NN1>author <w CC>and <w DDQ>which <w VBZ>is <w JJ>unique <w II>to <w APPGE>his <w NN2>works<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0107><w NN2>Features <w DDQ>which <w VBR>are <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>found <w II>in <w DB>all<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>only<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>works <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w NN1>author <w VV0>turn <w RP>out <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w RR>frustratingly <w JJ>difficult <w TO>to <w VVI>come <w II>by<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0108><w NN1>Authorship <w NN1>attribution <w NN2>problems <w VBR>are <w JJR>easier <w TO>to <w VVI>deal <w IW>with <w CS>when <w PPHS2>they <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>cast <w II>into <w AT>the <w JJ>following <w NN1>form<c YCOL>: <w II>in respect of <w AT>the <w JJ>measured <w NN2>features<c YCOM>, <w VDZ>does <w AT>the <w JJ>doubtful <w NN1>work <w VVI>resemble <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w NN1>candidate <w NN1>author <w ZZ1>A <w RRR>more <w CSN>than <w PPH1>it <w VVZ>resembles <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w NN1>candidate <w NN1>author <w ZZ1>B<c YQUE>? </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0109><w AT1>A <w JJ>classic <w NN1>example <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>kind <w IO>of <w NN1>study <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Harvard <w NN2>statisticians <w NP1>Frederick <w NP1>Mosteller <w CC>and <w NP1>David <w NP1>Wallace <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>Federalist <w NN2>Papers<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0110><w DD2>These <w NN2>papers <w VBDR>were <w AT1>a <w NN>series <w IO>of <w NN2>articles <w VVN>published <w II>in <w MC>1787 <w CC>and <w MC>1788 <w TO>to <w VVI>persuade <w AT>the <w NN2>citizens <w IO>of <w NP1>New <w NP1>York <w TO>to <w VVI>ratify <w AT>the<w NP1>U.S. <w NN1>Constitution<c YSCOL>; <w DAT>most <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>papers <w VBDR>were <w VVN>known <w TO>to <w VHI>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>written <w II>by <w NP1>Hamilton <w CC>or <w II>by <w NP1>Madison<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w AT>the <w NN1>authorship <w IO>of <w MC>twelve <w IO>of <w PPHO2>them <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>disputed<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0111><w II>By <w VVG>comparing <w AT>the <w NN1>rate <w IO>of <w NN1>occurrence <w IO>of <w JJ>particular <w NN2>words <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>disputed <w NN2>papers <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN2>rates <w II>in <w JJ>known <w NP1>Hamilton <w NN2>papers<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN2>rates <w II>in <w JJ>known <w NP1>Madison <w NN2>papers<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>authors <w VBDR>were <w JK>able <w TO>to <w VVI>establish <w II>beyond <w JJ>reasonable <w NN1>doubt <w CST>that <w NP1>Madison <w VVD>wrote <w AT>the <w JJ>disputed <w NN2>papers<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0112><w AT1>A <w RR>partly <w JJ>similar <w NN1>problem <w VBZ>is <w VVN>presented <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>Aristotelian <w NN1>corpus<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VVZ>contains <w MC>two <w JJ>ethical <w NN2>treatises <w IO>of <w JJ>parallel <w NN1>structure<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>Nicomachean <w NN>Ethics <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>Eudemian <w NN>Ethics<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0113><w AT>The <w NN1>problem <w RL>here <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w PN1>one <w IO>of <w NN1>authorship <w NN1>attribution<c YCOM>, <w CS>since <w DAT>most <w NN2>scholars <w VV0>regard <w PPHO2>them <w DB2>both <w CSA>as <w RR>genuinely <w JJ>Aristotelian<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w NN1>puzzle <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w MC>three <w NN2>books <w VV0>make <w AT1>a <w JJ>double <w NN1>appearance <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>manuscript <w NN1>tradition<c YCOM>, <w RR>once <w II>as <w NN2>books <w MC>five<c YCOM>, <w MC>six <w CC>and <w MC>seven <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Nicomachean <w NN>Ethics<c YCOM>, <w RR>once <w II>as <w NN2>books <w MC>four<c YCOM>, <w MC>five <w CC>and <w MC>six <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Eudemian <w NN>Ethics<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0114><w II>In <w MC>1978 <w PPIS1>I <w VVD>published <w AT1>a <w NN1>study <c YBL>(<w AT>The <w JJ>Aristotelian <w NN>Ethics<c YBR>) <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w PPIS1>I <w VVD>argued<c YCOM>, <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>basis <w IO>of <w MC>twenty-four <w JJ>independent <w NN2>tests <w VVN>based <w II>on <w NNU>60% <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>word <w NN1>usage <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>text<c YCOM>, <w CST>that <w AT>the <w JJ>disputed <w NN2>books <w VVD>resembled <w AT>the <w JJ>Eudemian <w NN1>context <w II>rather than <w AT>the <reg sic=Nichomachean> <w JJ>Nicomachean </reg> <w PN1>one<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0115><w JJ>Similar <w NN2>problems <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>studied <w II>by <w JJ>similar <w NN2>methods <w II>in <w AT>the <w RG>very <w JJ>different <w NN1>context <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>law-courts<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0116><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w RT>sometimes <w AT1>a <w NN1>question <w CSW>whether <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w NN1>confession <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>unaided <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w AT1>an <w JJ>accused <w CC>or <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>fabrication <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN2>police <w NN1>officer<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0117><w NP1>A. <w NP1>Q. <w NP1>Morton<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w APPGE>his <w NN1>book <w JJ>Literary <w NN1>Detection <w VVZ>records <w RRQ>how <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>evidence <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>admitted <w II>in <w DA>such <w AT1>a <w NN1>case <w II>in <w MC>1974<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0118><w AT>The <w JJ>Californian <w NN1>court <w VVG>trying <w NP1>Patricia <w NP1>Hearst <w IF>for <w NN1>bank <w NN1>robbery <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>asked <w TO>to <w VVI>hear <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>evidence <w TO>to <w VVI>help <w VVI>determine <w CSW>whether <w PPHS1>she <w VVD>composed <w AT>the <w NN1>propaganda <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>Symbionese <w NN1>Liberation <w NN1>Army <w DDQ>which <w VBDZ>was <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>case <w II>against <w PPHO1>her<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0119><w AT>The <w NN1>trial <w NN1>judge <w VVD>refused <w AT>the <w NN1>evidence <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN2>grounds <w IO>of <c YQUO>&bquo;<w AT>the <w JJ>relative <w NN1>infancy <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>area <w IO>of <w JJ>scientific <w NN1>endeavour<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0120><w CCB>But <w PN1>anyone <w VVG>working <w II>in <w DD1>this <w NN1>field <w VM>will <w VVI>receive <w RR>from time to time <w NN2>invitations <w TO>to <w VVI>offer <w NN1>evidence <w II>as <w AT1>an <w JJ>expert <w NN1>witness <w II>in <w DA>such <w NN2>cases<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0121><w II>In <w JJ>recent <w NNT2>years <w DA2>many <w NN1>authorship <w NN1>attribution <w NN2>problems<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT1>a <w NN1>variety <w IO>of <w NN2>languages<c YCOM>, <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>tackled<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w JJ>varying <w NN2>degrees <w IO>of <w NN1>success<c YCOM>, <w II>by <w JJ>stylometric <w NN2>methods<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0122><w RR>Thus <w NP1>Thomas <w NP1>Merriam <w VHZ>has <w VVN>used <w DD2>these <w NN2>methods <w TO>to <w VVI>try <w TO>to <w VVI>show <w CST>that <w NNB>Sir <w NP1>Thomas <w NP1>More <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>genuine <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w NP1>Shakespeare<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w RR>partly <w II>on <w JJ>stylometric <w NN2>grounds <w CST>that <w AT>the <w NN1>poem <c YQUO>&bquo;<w VM>Shall <w PPIS1>I <w VVI>die<c YQUE>?<c YQUO>&equo; <w VVD>won <w APPGE>its <w NN1>place <w II>in <w AT>the <w NP1>Oxford <w NP1>Shakespeare<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0123><w NP1>Y. <w NP1>Radday <w VHZ>has <w VVN>used <w JJ>Hebrew <w NN1>stylometry <w TO>to <w VVI>address <w AT>the <w NN1>problem <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>unity <w IO>of <w NP1>Isaiah <w CC>and <w TO>to <w VVI>argue <w II>against <w AT>the <w JJ>standard <w JJ>critical <w NN1>theory <w DDQ>which <w VVZ>sees <w AT>the <w NN1>book <w IO>of <w NN1>Genesis <w CSA>as <w VVN>woven <w II>from <w MC>three <w JJ>disparate <w NN2>strands <w IO>of <w NN1>tradition<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0124><w II>In spite of <w AT>the <w NN1>proliferation <w IO>of <w JJ>stylometric <w NN1>authorship <w NN2>studies<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VM>would <w VBI>be <w JJ>wrong <w TO>to <w VVI>think <w CST>that <w NN1>attribution <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>only <w NN1>goal <w IF>for <w JJ>statistical <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w NN1>style<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0125><w MC1>One <w IO>of <w AT>the <w RGT>most <w JJ>interesting <w JJ>recent <w NN>works <w VBZ>is <w NP1>J. <w NP1>F. <w NP1>Burrows<w GE>' <w NN1>Computation <w II>into <w NN1>Criticism<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0126><w DD1>This <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NP1>Jane <w NP1>Austen<w GE>'s <w NN2>novels <w VVN>based <w II>on <w JJ>common <w NN2>prepositions<c YCOM>, <w NN2>conjunctions<c YCOM>, <w NN2>pronouns <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>like<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0127><c YQUO>&bquo;<w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>truth <w XX>not <w RR>generally <w VVN>acknowledged<c YQUO>&equo; <w NP1>Burrows <w VVZ>points <w RP>out<c YQUO>&bquo;<w CST>that <w II>in <w DAT>most <w NN2>discussions <w IO>of <w NN2>works <w IO>of <w JJ>English <w NN1>fiction<c YCOM>, <w PPIS2>we <w VV0>proceed <w CS>as if <w AT1>a <w MD>third <w IO>of <w APPGE>our <w NN1>material <w VBDR>were <w XX>not <w RR>really <w RL>there<c YSTP>.<c YQUO>&equo; </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0128><w NP1>Burrows <w VVZ>shows <w RRQ>how <w NP1>Jane <w NP1>Austen <w VVZ>makes <w JJ>skilful <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>common <w NN2>words <w TO>to <w VVI>build <w RP>up <w JJ>different <w NN2>idiolects <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>different <w NN2>persons <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>novels <w TO>to <w VVI>bring <w RP>out <w AT>the <w NN2>differences <w II>in <w APPGE>their <w NN2>characters<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0129><w NNB>Admiral <w NP1>Croft<c YCOM>, <w REX>for instance<c YCOM>, <w VVZ>uses <c YQUO>&bquo; <w PPIS2>we<c YQUO>&equo; <w CC>and <w APPGE>its <w NN2>cases <w RR>more than <w MC>ten <w NNT2>times <w RG>as <w RR>frequently <w CSA>as <w NNB>Lady <w NP1>Catherine <w NP1>de <w NP1>Burgh<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0130><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w II>by <w JJ>tiny <w NN2>touches <w II>such as <w DD2>these <c YDSH>&mdash; <w CS>though <w RR>only <w AT1>a <w NN1>stylometrist <w VM>would <w RR>consciously <w VVI>notice <w PPHO2>them <c YDSH>&mdash; <w CST>that <w NP1>Jane <w NP1>Austen <w VVZ>builds <w RP>up <w AT>the <w NN1>picture <w IO>of <w MC1>one <w NN1>character<w GE>'s <w NN1>clubbability<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>other<w GE>'s <w NN1>insolence <w IO>of <w NN1>rank<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0131><w JJ>Computer-assisted <w NN2>studies <w IO>of <w NN1>style <w VH0>have <w RR>often <w VVN>attempted <w TO>to <w VVI>settle <w NN2>questions <w IO>of <w NN1>chronology <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w IO>of <w NN2>authors <w DDQGE>whose <w NN2>works <w VBR>are <w JJ>undated<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0132><w NP1>Leonard <w NP1>Brandwood <w VHZ>has <w VVN>worked <w IF>for <w DA2>many <w NNT2>decades <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>chronology <w IO>of <w NP1>Plato<w GE>'s <w NN2>dialogues<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0133><w MC1>One <w IO>of <w AT>the <w RGT>most <w JJ>recent <w NN2>contributions <w II>to <w DD1>this <w NN1>debate <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w NP1>Gerland <w NP1>Ledger<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w APPGE>his <w NN1>book <w VVG>Recounting <w NP1>Plato<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0134><w NP1>Ledger <w VVD>took <w AT>the <w JJT>simplest <w JJ>possible <w NN1>feature <w IO>of <w NN1>language <c YDSH>&mdash; <w AT>the <w NN1>occurrence <w IO>of <w JJ>particular <w NN2>letters <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>alphabet <c YDSH>&mdash; <w CC>and <w II>by <w VVG>subjecting <w DD1>this <w II>to <w AT1>a <w JJ>complicated <w JJ>multivariate <w NN1>analysis <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>came <w JJR>closer <w CSN>than <w DA2>many <w JJ>previous <w NN2>workers <w II>to <w VVG>identifying <w JJ>particular <w NN2>authors <w CC>and <w RR>even <w NN2>works<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0135><w PPHS1>He <w VVD>drew <w JJ>new <w NN2>conclusions <w II>about <w AT>the <w NN1>authenticity <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>dubious <w NN2>dialogues<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>chronology <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>entire <w NN1>corpus<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0136><w II>In <w AT>the <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN1>literature<c YCOM>, <w JJ>quantitative <w NN2>methods <w VM>can <w RR>never <w VVI>achieve <w AT>the <w NN1>primacy <w DDQ>which <w PPHS2>they <w VV0>enjoy <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>experimental <w NN2>sciences <w CC>and <w II>in <w DA2>many <w NN2>branches <w IO>of <w JJ>social <w NN2>studies<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0137><w CCB>But <w NN2>scholars <w PNQS>who <w VV0>use <w PPHO2>them <w IW>with <w AT1>a <w JJ>sober <w NN1>sense <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w NN2>limitations <w VM>can <w VVI>add <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>dimension <w II>to <w JJ>literary <w NN2>studies<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>in <w AT1>an <w NN1>age <w IO>of <w JJ>divided <w NN2>cultures <w PPIS2>we <w VM>should <w RR>surely <w VBI>be <w JJ>ready <w TO>to <w VVI>welcome <w AT1>a <w NN1>marriage <w IO>of <w NN1>literacy <w CC>and <w NN1>numeracy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0138><w RR>However<c YCOM>, <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>studies <w PPIS1>I <w VH0>have <w VVN>mentioned <w PPH1>it <w VM>would <w VBI>be <w JJ>difficult <w TO>to <w VVI>claim <w CST>that <w DAR>more <w CSN>than <w AT1>a <w NN1>handful <w VVD>fulfilled <w AT>the <w NN2>criteria <w PPIS1>I <w VVD>mentioned <w RRR>earlier<c YCOL>: <w RR>both <c YBL>(<w ZZ1>a<c YBR>) <w VVN>respected <w II>as <w AT1>an <w JJ>original <w JJ>scholarly <w NN1>contribution <w II>within <w APPGE>its <w DA>own <w NN1>discipline <w CC>and <c YBL>(<w ZZ1>b<c YBR>) <w VM>could <w RR>clearly <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w VBN>been <w VDN>done <w IW>without <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0139><w RR>Indeed <w II>throughout <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines<c YCOM>, <w II>after <w JJ>thirty-odd <w NNT2>years <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w NN1>kind <w IO>of <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w EX>there <w VBR>are <w RR>embarrassingly <w DA2>few <w NN2>books <w CC>and <w NN2>articles <w DDQ>which <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w RR>confidently <w VVN>pointed <w RP>out <w CSA>as <w VVG>passing <w DB2>both <w NN2>tests<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0140><w DD1>This <w VHZ>has <w VVN>meant <w CST>that <w DA2>many <w NN2>enthusiasts <w IF>for <w NN1>computing <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w VH0>have <w AT1>an <w JJ>uncomfortable <w NN1>sense <w IO>of <w NN1>crisis<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w NN1>feeling <w IO>of <w NN1>promise <w JJ>unfulfilled<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0141><w VVN>Gone <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>glad <w JJ>confident <w NNT1>morning <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w NP1>Ladurie <w VM>could <w VVI>say <c YQUO>&bquo;<w FW>L'historien <w FW>de <w FW>demain <w FW>sera <w FW>programmeur <w FW>ou <w FW>il <w FW>ne <w FW>sera <w FW>plus<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0142><w AT>The <w NN1>feeling <w IO>of <w NN1>disillusion <w VBZ>is <w RR>indeed <w RR>partly <w AT>the <w NN1>result <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>misplaced <w NN1>optimism <w CC>and <w JJ>exaggerated <w NN2>claims <w IO>of <w DD>some <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>pioneers<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>belief <w VBDZ>was <w RT>sometimes <w VVN>encouraged <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>past <w CST>that <w VVG>feeding <w NN>data <w II>into <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer <w VM>would <w RR>automatically <w VVI>solve <w AT1>a <w NN1>scholar<w GE>'s <w NN2>problems<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0143><w JJ>Rare <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w NN1>project <w DDQ>which <w VDD>did <w XX>not<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>course <w IO>of <w NN1>execution<c YCOM>, <w VVI>bring <w II>to <w NN1>light <w AT1>an <w JJ>initial <w NN1>overestimation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>technical <w NN2>possibilities<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT1>an <w NN1>underestimation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>problems <w IO>of <w NN>data <w NN1>preparation<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0144><w AT>The <w NN1>proliferation <w IO>of <w JJ>personal <w NN2>computers <w II>in <w AT>the <w MD>last <w NNT1>decade <w VHZ>has <w RR>often<c YCOM>, <w RR>embarrassingly<c YCOM>, <w VVN>gone <w IW>with <w AT1>an <w JJ>actual <w NN1>diminution <w II>in <w JJ>methodological <w NN1>sophistication<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0145><w CS>If <w AT>the <w NN2>fruits <w IO>of <w NN1>computing <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w VBR>are <w RGR>less <w JJ>abundant <w CSN>than <w PN1>one <w VM>might <w VHI>have <w VVN>hoped<c YCOM>, <w EX>there <w VBR>are <w RR>also <w NN2>disadvantages <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>introduction <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w DDQ>which <w VBR>are <w VVG>becoming <w RR>all <w RG>too <w JJ>obvious<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0146><w VV0>Let <w PPIO1>me <w VVI>mention <w MC>six<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w PPIS1>I <w VM>will <w VVI>call<c YCOL>: <w NN1>redundancy <w IO>of <w NN>people<c YCOM>, <w NN1>redundancy <w IO>of <w NN1>effort<c YCOM>, <w NN1>diversion <w IO>of <w NN1>effort<c YCOM>, <w NN1>diversion <w IO>of <w NN1>funding<c YCOM>, <w NN1>distortion <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w CC>and <w NN1>transfer <w IO>of <w NN1>population<c YSTP>. </s>
<list>
<label>
<s n=0147><w MC1>1<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0148><w NN1>Redundancy <w IO>of <w NN>people<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0149><w NP1>Alexander <w NP1>Cruden <w VVD>spent <w AT>the <w JJT>best <w NNT2>years <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w NN1>life <w VVG>preparing <w APPGE>his <w NN1>concordance <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>Bible<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0150><w EX>There <w VBZ>is <w RR>no longer <w DD>any <w NN1>need <w IF>for <w JJ>dedicated <w NP2>Crudens <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w NN2>concordances<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0151><w JJ>Classical <w NN2>scholars <w II>among <w PPIO2>us <w VM>will <w DB>all<c YCOM>, <w II>as <w NN2>students<c YCOM>, <w VH0>have <w VVN>stood <w II>in <w NN1>awe <w IO>of <w APPGE>our <w NN2>seniors <w PNQS>who<c YCOM>, <w VVN>given <w AT1>a <w JJ>rare <w JJ>Greek <w NN1>word<c YCOM>, <w VM>could <w VVI>pluck <w II>out of <w APPGE>their <w NN2>memories <w AT>the <w MC>ten <w NN2>contexts <w II>in <w JJ>different <w JJ>classical <w NN2>authors <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>used<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0152><w RT>Nowadays <w DD>any <w NN1>student <w VM>can <w VVI>discover <w DD1>that <w NN1>information <w II>in <w NN2>moments <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>aid <w IO>of <w NP1>IBYCUS<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0153><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w RR>no longer <w JJ>possible <w TO>to <w VVI>found <w AT1>a <w NN1>reputation <w IF>for <w NN1>scholarship <w II>on <w VBG>being <w JJ>good <w II>at <w VVG>spotting <w NN2>allusions<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0154><w DD1>This <w NN1>problem <w VBZ>is <w AT>the <w JJ>humanistic <w NN1>analogue <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>problem <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>stoker <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>electric <w NN1>train<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0155><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w AT1>a <w JJ>serious <w PN1>one <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>discipline<c YCOM>, <w CC>nor <w RR>even <w II>in <w JJ>human <w NN2>terms <w VDZ>does <w PPH1>it <w VVI>compare <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>undesirable <w NN2>side-effects <w IO>of <w JJ>technological <w NN2>innovations <w II>in <w JJ>practical <w NN1>life <w CC>and <w JJ>scientific <w NN1>research<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<label>
<s n=0156><w MC>2<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0157><w NN1>Redundancy <w IO>of <w NN1>effort<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0158><w NN2>Scholars <w PNQS>who <w VBR>are <w JJ>good <w II>at <w VVG>knowing <w RRQ>where <w TO>to <w VVI>look <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN2>sources <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w NN1>subject <w NN1>matter <w VM>may <w XX>not <w VBI>be <w JJ>good <w II>at <w VVG>knowing <w RRQ>where <w TO>to <w VVI>look <w IF>for <w JJ>suitable <w NN1>software<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0159><w AT>The <w NN1>replacement <w IO>of <w NN1>mainframe <w NN1>use <w II>by <w NN1>desktop <w NN1>computing <w II>in <w JJ>recent <w NNT2>years <w VVZ>means <w CST>that <w NN2>scholars <w VVG>working <w RR>alone <w VD0>do <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w RG>as <w DA1>much <w NN1>contact <w IW>with <w JJ>computer-learned <w NN>people <w CSA>as <w PPHS2>they <w VMK>used <w TO>to <w VDI>do<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0160><w DD1>This <w NN>means <w PPHS2>they <w VBR>are <w RRR>less <w II>in touch with <w NN1>software <w NN2>developments<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0161><w RR>Hence<c YCOM>, <w CS>if <w PPHS2>they <w VV0>get <w JJ>interested <w II>in <w VVG>designing <w APPGE>their <w DA>own <w NN1>software<c YCOM>, <w NN2>scholars <w VM>may <w VVI>spend <w APPGE>their <w NNT1>time <w VVG>reinventing <w MD>last <w NNT1>year<w GE>'s <w NN1>wheel<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<label>
<s n=0162><w MC>3<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0163><w NN1>Diversion <w IO>of <w NN1>effort<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0164><w CS>Even if <w AT>the <w NN1>software <w VVN>designed <w VBZ>is <w RR>genuinely <w JJ>original <w CC>and <w JJ>useful<c YCOM>, <w EX>there <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>danger <w CST>that <w NN2>scholars <w VV0>become <w JJ>hooked <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>production <w IO>of <w NN1>software<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0165><w EX>There <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>risk <w CST>that <w AT1>a <w NN1>scholar <w DDQGE>whose <w NN2>talents <w CC>and <w JJ>academic <w NN1>position <w VV0>call <w IF>for <w JJ>historical <w CC>and <w JJ>critical <w NN1>work <w VM>will <w VVI>spend <w DAT>most <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w CC>or <w APPGE>her <w NN1>working <w NNT1>time <w II>as <w AT1>a <w NN1>programmer<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<label>
<s n=0166><w MC>4<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0167><w NN1>Diversion <w IO>of <w NN1>funding<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0168><w CS>Because <w EX>there <w VBZ>is <w NN1>pressure <w II>on <w NN2>departments <w II>in <w JJ>humanistic <w NN2>subjects <w TO>to <w VVI>appear <w JJ>up to date <w CC>and <w JJ>efficient<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w RR>much <w JJR>easier <w TO>to <w VVI>persuade <w NN1>funding <w NN2>bodies <w TO>to <w VVI>give <w NN1>money <w IF>for <w NN2>computers <w CC>and <w NN1>software <w CSN>than <w TO>to <w VVI>buy <w NN2>manuscripts<c YCOM>, <w JJ>rare <w NN2>books<c YCOM>, <w CC>or <w MD>second <w CC>and <w MD>third <w NN2>copies <w IO>of <w RR>frequently <w VVN>used <w NN1>library <w NN2>texts<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0169><w II>After <w DD2>a few <w NNT2>years <w AT1>a <w NN1>department <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w VVN>left <w IW>with <w JJ>serious <w NN2>gaps <w II>in <w APPGE>its <w NN1>library <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w NN1>load <w IO>of <w JJ>superannuated <w NN1>computing <w NN1>equipment<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<label>
<s n=0170><w MC>5<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0171><w NN1>Distortion <w IO>of <w NN1>research<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0172><w EX>There <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>danger <w CST>that <w NN2>projects <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w VVN>undertaken <w XX>not <w CS>because <w PPHS2>they <w VBR>are <w JJ>likely <w TO>to <w VVI>lead <w II>to <w RR>academically <w JJ>interesting <w NN2>results<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w RR>simply <w CS>because <w PPHS2>they <w VBR>are <w JJ>susceptible <w II>to <w NN1>computerisation<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0173><w NN2>Scholars <w VV0>feel <w AT>the <w NN1>need <w TO>to <w VVI>show <w PPHS2>they <w VH0>have <w VVN>used <w AT>the <w JJT>latest <w NN1>technology<c YCOM>, <w CS>even if <w JJ>electronic <w NN2>methods <w VBR>are <w XX>not <w AT>the <w JJ>appropriate <w PN1>one<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0174><w CCB>But <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>words <w IO>of <w NP1>Manfred <w NP1>Thaller <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w JJ>important <w IF>for <w NN2>humanists <w TO>to <w VVI>adapt <w AT>the <w NN1>software <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>scholarship<c YCOM>, <w XX>not <w AT>the <w NN1>scholarship <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>software<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<label>
<s n=0175><w MC>6<c YBR>) </s>
</label>
<item>
<s n=0176><w NN1>Transfer <w IO>of <w NN2>populations<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0177><w NNB>Professor <w NP1>Connor<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>fascinating <w NN1>paper <w II>on <w NN2>computers <w II>in <w JJ>classical <w NN2>studies<c YCOM>, <w VVZ>claims <w CST>that <w NN2>computers <w VVD>came <w RR>just <w II>at <w AT>the <w JJ>wrong <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w II>at <w AT1>a <w NNT1>time <w RRQ>when <w NN1>scholar<w GE>'s <w NN2>interests <w VBDR>were <w VVG>moving <w II>from <w JJ>textual <w NN2>studies <w II>to <w JJ>critical <w NN1>theory<c YCOM>, <w NN2>women<w GE>'s <w NN2>studies <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>like<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0178><w PPHS1>He <w VVZ>says<c YCOL>: <c YQUO>&bquo; <w NN1>Computer <w NN1>technology <w VVD>became <w JJ>available <w RR>precisely <w II>at <w AT>the <w JJ>wrong <w NN1>moment <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>profession<w GE>'s <w NN1>development<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0179><w AT>The <w NN1>era <w IO>of <w JJ>traditional <w JJ>lexical <w CC>and <w JJ>textual <w NN2>studies <w VHD>had <w RR>largely <w VVN>passed<c YLIP>&hellip;</s>
<s n=0180><w AT>The <w NN1>energy <w IO>of <w NP1>North <w JJ>American <w NN2>classicists<c YCOM>, <w RR>by and large<c YCOM>, <w VHZ>has <w VVN>concentrated <w II>on <w JJ>interpretive <w NN2>questions <w CC>and <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>writing <w IO>of <w NN2>essays <w CC>and <w NN2>monographs <w IO>of <w JJ>social <w NN2>themes<c YCOM>, <w JJ>cultural <w NN1>history <w CC>and <w JJ>literary <w NN1>criticism<c YLIP>&hellip; </s>
<s n=0181><w AT>The <w NN2>questions <w VVN>posed <w II>by <w JJ>Feminist<c YCOM>, <w JJ>Marxist<c YCOM>, <w JJ>Structuralist <w CC>and <w JJ>Post-Structuralist <w NN1>criticism <w VH0>have <w XX>not <w VVN>lent <w PPX2>themselves <w II>to <w JJ>computer-based <w NN2>responses<c YSTP>.<c YQUO>&equo; </s>
</item>
</list>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0182><w VBZ>Is <w DD1>this <w RR>just <w AT1>a <w JJ>malign <w NN1>coincidence<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0183><w PN1>One <w VM>may <w RR>well <w VVI>speculate <w II>on <w JJ>possible <w NN2>causes <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>phenomenon<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0184><w PN1>One <w VDZ>does <w XX>not <w VVI>need <w TO>to <w VVI>draw <w JJ>exaggerated <w NN2>conclusions <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN2>differences <w II>between <w AT>the <w JJ>left <w CC>and <w JJ>right <w NN1>hand <w NN2>sides <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>brain <w BCL>in order <w TO>to <w VVI>accept <w CST>that <w NN2>humanists <w CC>and <w NN2>scientists <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w JJ>different <w NN2>kinds <w IO>of <w NN>people<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0185><w DD2>Those <w DDQGE>whose <w NN2>gifts <w CC>and <w NN2>tastes <w VV0>lie <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>certain <w NN1>direction <c YDSH>&mdash; <w NN>people <w PNQS>who <w VD0>do <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w AT1>a <w NN1>head <w IF>for <w NN1>mathematics <c YDSH>&mdash; <w VM>may <w RR>well <w VHI>have <w VBN>been <w VVN>influenced <w II>by <w DD1>this <w II>in <w AT1>an <w JJ>early <w NN1>career <w NN1>choice<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0186><w II>To <w APPGE>their <w NN1>dismay <w PPHS2>they <w VV0>see <w NN1>quantification <w VVG>invading <w APPGE>their <w DA>own <w NN1>subject<c YCOL>: <w PPHS2>they <w VM>might <w RR>as well <w VHI>have <w VVN>become <w NN2>physicists <w CC>or <w NN2>engineers <w CS>if <w JJ>English <w NN1>literature<c YCOM>, <w JJ>Greek <w NN1>history <w CC>and <w RR>even <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w NN1>theology <w RT>now <w VV0>offer <w AT>no <w NN1>escape <w II>from <w DD2>those <w JJ>wretched <w NN2>numbers<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0187><w RR>So <w RT>now <w AT>the <w RGR>more <w JJ>abstract<c YCOM>, <w JJ>intuitive<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w JJ>ideological <w NN2>branches <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w VV0>become <w RGR>more <w JJ>attractive<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0188><w AT>The <w NN1>number <w IO>of <w NN2>practitioners <w II>in <w DD2>these <w NN2>areas <w VVZ>grows <c YDSH>&mdash; <w RR>largely<c YCOM>, <w RR>no doubt<c YCOM>, <w II>through <w AT>the <w JJ>genuine <w NN1>fascination <w IO>of <w APPGE>their <w NN2>subjects<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VVN>swollen <w RR>perhaps <w IW>with <w AT1>an <w NN1>influx <w IO>of <w NN2>refugees <w II>from <w AT>the <w JJ>relentless <w NN1>advance <w IO>of <w JJ>technological <w NN1>rigour<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0189><w EX>There <w VBR>are <w JJ>still<c YCOM>, <w VV0>thank <w NP1>God<c YCOM>, <w DD2>a few <w NN2>areas <w RRQ>where <w PN1>one <w VM>can <w VVI>work <w IW>without <w RR>either <w VHG>having <w TO>to <w VVI>use <w NN2>computers <w CC>or <w VVG>feeling <w JJ>guilty <w CS>because <w PN1>one <w VDZ>does <w XX>not<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0190><w CS>If <w DD1>this <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w JJ>correct <w NN1>analysis <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>situation<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <reg sic=consquences> <w NN2>consequences </reg> <w IF>for <w APPGE>our <w NN2>disciplines <w VM>may <w VBI>be <w JJ>far-reaching <w II>in <w JJ>unexpected <w NN2>ways <w DDQ>which <w VBR>are <w RR>only <w RR>just <w VVG>beginning <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>noticed<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0191><w PPIS1>I <w VM>would <w VVI>like <w TO>to <w VVI>end <w II>by <w VVG>asking <w DDQ>what <w NN2>lessons <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w VVN>drawn <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN2>successes <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>disappointments <w IO>of <w JJ>recent <w NNT2>decades<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0192><w RR>No doubt <w EX>there <w VBR>are <w DA2>many<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w PPIS1>I <w VM>would <w VVI>like <w TO>to <w VVI>single <w RP>out <w RR>just <w MC>three<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0193><w AT>The <w MD>first <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VBZ>is <w JJ>important <w RR>never <w TO>to <w VVI>lose <w NN1>sight <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>fact <w CST>that <w AT1>a <w NN1>computer <w VBZ>is <w AT1>an <w NN1>assistant <w II>to<c YCOM>, <w XX>not <w AT1>a <w NN1>substitute <w IF>for<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>human <w NN1>researcher<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0194><w NN1>Neglect <w IO>of <w DD1>this <w JJ>obvious <w NN1>truth <w VVD>led <w II>to <w NN1>computer <w NN2>programs <c YBL>(<w VV0>say<c YCOM>, <w IF>for <w NN1>language <w NN1>analysis<c YBR>) <w VBG>being <w VVN>regarded <w II>as <w NN2>failures <w CS>if <w PPHS2>they <w VM>could <w XX>not <w VVI>record <w NNU>100% <w NN1>success<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0195><w RGR>More <w RR>recently<c YCOM>, <w PPIS2>we <w VH0>have <w VVN>learnt <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w JJ>grateful <w IF>for <w JJ>robust <w NN2>programs <w DDQ>which <w VM>will <w VDI>do <w NNU>95% <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>work <w CC>and <w VVI>leave <w AT>the <w JJ>human <w NN1>being <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w AT>the <w JJ>decisive <w NN1>intervention <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w NNU>5% <w IO>of <w NN2>cases<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0196><w AT1>A <w MD>second <w NN1>lesson <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w CS>even when <w AT>the <w NN1>computerization <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>research <w NN1>project <w VVZ>fails <w II>because of <w AT>the<reg sic=intractibility> <w NN1>intractability </reg> <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>particular <w NN1>set <w IO>of <w NN>data<c YCOM>, <w PPH1>it <w VM>can <w VBI>be <w AT1>an <w RR>intellectually <w JJ>instructive <w NN1>task <w TO>to <w VVI>try<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVI>fail<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VVI>prepare <w AT>the <w NN>data <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>formalized <w NN1>manner<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0197><w CC>And <w AT>the <w JJ>successful <w NN1>formalization <w IO>of <w NN>data <w VM>can <w VVI>open <w RP>up <w NN2>questions <w IF>for <w NN1>research<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN2>types <w IO>of <w NN1>evidence<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VM>would <w XX>not <w VHI>have <w VVN>occurred <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>research <w NN1>community <w IW>without <w AT>the <w NN1>effort <w TO>to <w VVI>present <w AT>the <w NN>data <w II>in <w JJ>computer-friendly <w NN1>form<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0198><w AT>The <w MD>third <w NN1>lesson <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VM>will <w XX>not <w VBI>be <w JJ>possible <w IF>for <w NN2>humanists <w TO>to <w VVI>take <w JJ>full <w NN1>stock <w IO>of <w DDQ>what <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VHZ>has <w TO>to <w VVI>offer <w II>to <w APPGE>their <w NN2>disciplines <w CS>until <w AT>the <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w NN>statistics <w VVZ>becomes <w AT1>a <w JJ>normal <w CC>and <w JJ>inescapable <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>training <w IO>of <w DD2>those <w PNQS>who <w VV0>plan <w AT1>an <w JJ>academic <w NN1>career <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0199><w DD1>This <w VVZ>needs <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>recognized <w XX>not <w RR>only <w II>at <w NN1>university <w NN1>level <c YBL>(<w CSA>as <w II>in <w NP1>France<c YCOM>, <w RRQ>where <w RT>now <w AT1>a <w NN1>course <w IO>of <w NN>statistics <w VBZ>is <w AT1>an <w JJ>essential <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>training <w IO>of <w AT1>an <w JJ>academic <w NN1>historian<c YBR>) <w CCB>but <w RR>also <w II>in <w DD>any <w JJ>high <w NN1>school <w DDQ>which <w VHZ>has <w AT1>an <w NN1>interest <w II>in <w VVG>sending <w RP>on <w NN2>students <w TO>to <w VDI>do <w NN1>university <w NN1>work <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0200><w EX>There <w VBZ>is <w RR>still <w AT1>a <w JJ>great <w NN1>lack<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT1>every <w NN1>language<c YCOM>, <w IO>of <w JJ>good <w NN2>textbooks <w VVN>designed <w TO>to <w VVI>teach <w NN>statistics <w II>outside <w AT>the <w NN1>context <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>natural <w CC>and <w JJ>social <w NN2>sciences<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0201><w II>Apart from <w RR>strictly <w JJ>academic <w NN1>consideration<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>ordinary <w NN1>citizen <w IO>of <w DD>any <w JJ>modern <w NN1>democracy <w VM>will <w VVI>find <w AT1>an <w JJ>elementary <w NN1>course <w II>in <w NN>statistics <w IO>of <w DAR>more <w JJ>general <w JJ>educational <w NN1>value <w CSN>than <w NN2>courses <w II>in <w REX>e.g. <w JJ>differential <w NN1>calculus<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VBR>are <w RGR>more <w JJ>popular <w II>in <w JJ>science-oriented <w NN2>schools<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0202><w MC1>One <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>unquestionable <w NN2>advantages <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w II>by <w NN2>humanists <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VHZ>has <w VDN>done <w PN1>something <w TO>to <w VVI>bridge <w AT>the <w NN1>divide <w II>between <w MC>two <w NN2>cultures <c YDSH>&mdash; <w JJ>scientific <w CC>and <w JJ>humanist <c YDSH>&mdash; <w DDQ>which <w DA2>many <w NN2>writers <w VH0>have <w VVN>lamented <w CSA>as <w VVG>threatening <w TO>to <w VVI>fragment <w AT>the <w NN1>community <w IO>of <w NN2>scholars <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>republic <w IO>of <w NN1>learning<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0203><w AT1>A <w NN1>by-product <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w NN1>revolution <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w AT1>an <w JJ>increased <w NN1>understanding <w II>by <w NN2>scientists <w CC>and <w NN2>humanists <w IO>of <w DD1>each <w NN2>others<w GE>' <w NN2>methods <w CC>and <w NN2>preoccupations<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0204><w RR>Surprisingly<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT>the <w MD>last <w NNT2>decades <w VBZ>is <w CST>that <w JJ>literary <w NN2>studies<c YCOM>, <w RR>perhaps <w RR>especially <w JJ>classical <w NN2>studies<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VM>may <w VVI>seem <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w II>at <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w NN1>extreme <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>academic <w NN1>spectrum <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN2>sciences<c YCOM>, <w VH0>have <w VVN>shown <w PPX2>themselves <w RGR>more <w NN1>self <w JJ>confident <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>use <w IO>of <w NN2>computers <w CSN>than <w NN1>history <w VHZ>has <w VDN>done<c YCOM>, <w CS>even though <w NN1>history <w VBZ>is <w JJR>closer <w II>to <w AT>the <w JJ>social <w NN2>sciences <w DDQ>which <w VH0>have <w RR>for long <w VBN>been <w VVN>acclimatized <w II>to <w NN1>quantification <w CC>and <w NN1>computerization<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0205><w II>On <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w NN1>hand<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>flight <w II>in <w DD>some <w NN1>literature <w NN2>departments <w II>from <w JJ>traditional <w NN2>methods <w IO>of <w NN1>study<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w APPGE>their <w NN1>emphasis <w II>on <w AT>the <w JJ>detailed <w NN1>analysis <w IO>of <w NN2>texts<c YCOM>, <w II>towards <w JJ>theory-laden <w NN2>forms <w IO>of <w NN1>criticism <w IW>with <w AT1>an <w JJ>explicit <w JJ>political <w NN1>agenda<c YCOM>, <w VBZ>is <w AT1>a <w NN1>development <w DDQ>which <w VBZ>is <w XX>not <w JJ>favourable <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>search <w IF>for <w RR>objectively <w JJ>quantifiable <w NN2>features <w JJ>capable <w IO>of <w JJ>computerized <w NN1>study<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0206><w DDQ>What <w VM>will <w AT>the <w MD>next <w NNT2>decades <w VVI>hold<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0207><w VM>Will <w PPH1>it <w VBI>be <w VVN>seen<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w NN1>hindsight<c YCOM>, <w CST>that <w AT>the <w NN1>introduction <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>disciplines <w VHZ>has <w VVN>made <w AT>no <w RGR>more <w JJ>substantial <w NN1>change <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>eventual <w NN1>output <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w CSN>than <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>made <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN1>introduction <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>electric <w NN1>typewriter<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0208><w CC>Or <w VM>will <w EX>there <w VBI>be <w AT1>a <w NN1>flowering <w IO>of <w NN1>research <w NN2>papers<c YCOM>, <w RR>neither <w JJ>pedestrian <w CC>nor <w JJ>spectacular<c YCOM>, <w VVG>containing <w JJ>solid <w CC>and <w JJ>original <w NN2>results <w VVN>obtained <w II>by <w NN2>techniques <w IF>for <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VBZ>is <w JJ>indispensable<c YQUE>? </s>
<s n=0209><w PPH1>It <w VBZ>is <w JJ>hard <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w AT1>a <w JJ>confident <w NN1>prediction<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0210><w CCB>But <w AT>the <w NN1>testing <w NNT1>time <w VHZ>has <w RT>now <w VVN>arrived<c YSCOL>; <w CS>because <w IF>for <w AT>the <w MD>first <w NNT1>time <w NN2>posts <w IO>of <w NN1>leadership <w II>in <w NN2>humanities <w NN2>departments <w VBR>are <w VBG>being <w VVN>taken <w RP>up <w II>by <w AT1>a <w NN1>generation <w IO>of <w NN2>scholars <w PNQS>who <w VH0>have <w VBN>been <w JJ>familiar <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w II>from <w APPGE>their <w JJT>earliest <w NN2>schooldays<c YCOM>, <w NN2>scholars <w PNQS>who <w VBR>are <w RR>neither <w VVN>frightened <w II>by<c YCOM>, <w CC>nor <w JJ>over-respectful <w IO>of<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w NN2>powers <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w NN1>computer <w VHZ>has <w VVN>brought<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<div2 complete=Y org=SEQ>
<head type=MAIN>
<s n=0211><w NN2>References </s>
</head>
<list>
<item>
<s n=0212><w NP1>Brandwood<c YCOM>, <w NP1>L.<c YCOM>, <w AT1>A <w NN1>Word <w NN1>Index <w II>to <w NP1>Plato<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Manchester<c YCOM>, <w MC>1976<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0213><w NP1>Burrows<c YCOM>, <w NP1>J. <w NP1>F. <w NN1>Computation <w II>into <w NN1>Criticism<c YCOL>: <w AT1>A <w NN1>Study <w IO>of <w NP1>Jane <w NP1>Austen<w GE>'s <w NN2>Novels <w CC>and <w AT1>an <w NN1>Experiment <w II>in <w NN1>Method<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w MC>1987<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0214><w NP1>Friberg<c YCOM>, <w NP1>B. <w CC>and <w NP1>T. <w JJ>Analytical <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Grand <w NP1>Rapids<c YCOM>, <w MC>1981<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0215><w NP1>Grayston<c YCOM>, <w NP1>K. <w CC>and <w NP1>Herdan <w NP1>G.<c YCOM>, <c YQUO>&bquo; <w AT>The <w NN1>Authorship <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>Pastorals <w II>in the Light of <w JJ>Statistical <w NN1>Linguistics<c YQUO>&equo;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0216><w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament <w NN2>Studies <w MC>6<c YBL>(<w MC>1960<c YBR>)<c YCOM>, <w MCMC>1&ndash;15<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0217><w NP1>Kenny<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Anthony<c YCOM>, <w AT1>A <w JJ>Stylometric <w NN1>Study <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>New <w NN1>Testament<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w MC>1987<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0218><w NP1>Kenny<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Anthony<c YCOM>, <w AT>The <w JJ>Aristotelian <w NN>Ethics<c YCOL>: <w AT1>A <w NN1>study <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Relationship <w II>between <w AT>the <w JJ>Eudemian <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>Nicomachean <w NN>Ethics <w IO>of <w NP1>Aristotle <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w MC>1978<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0219><w NP1>Ledger<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Gerard <w NP1>R. <w VVG>Re-Counting <w NP1>Plato<c YCOL>: <w AT1>A <w NN1>Computer <w NN1>Analysis <w IO>of <w NP1>Plato <w GE>'s <w NN1>Style<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w MC>1989<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0220><w NP1>Morton<c YCOM>, <w NP1>A. <w NP1>Q. <w CC>and <w NP1>McLeman <w NP1>J. <w NP1>J.<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Paul<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>Man <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>Myth<c YCOM>, <w NP1>London<c YCOM>, <w MC>1966<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0221><w NP1>Morton<c YCOM>, <w NP1>A. <w NP1>Q. <w JJ>Literary <w NN1>Detection<c YCOM>, <w NP1>London<c YCOM>, <w MC>1978<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0222><w NP1>Mosteller<c YCOM>, <w NP1>F. <w CC>and <w NP1>Wallace<c YCOM>, <w NP1>D.<c YCOM>, <w NN1>Inference <w CC>and <w JJ>Disputed <w NN1>Authorship<c YCOL>: <w AT>the <w NN1>Federalist<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Reading<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Mass<c YCOM>, <w MC>1964<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0223><w NP1>Radday<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Yehuda<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0224><w NN1>Genesis<c YCOL>: <w AT1>An <w NN1>Authorship <w NN1>Study <w II>in <w JJ>Computer-assisted <w JJ>Statistical <w NN1>Linguistics<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Rome<c YCOM>, <w MC>1985<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
<item>
<s n=0225><w AT>The <w NN2>Humanities <w NN1>Computing <w NN1>Yearbook<c YCOM>, <w MCMC>1989&ndash;90<c YCOM>, <w NN1>ed. <w NP1>I. <w NP1>Lancashire<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Oxford<c YCOM>, <w MC>1991<c YSTP>. </s>
</item>
</list>
</div2>
</div1>
</text>
</bncDoc>
