<bncDoc id=BDJXL n=nasser>
<header creator=dominic status=UPDATE update="2 Feb 1999" type=TEXT>
<fileDesc>
<titStmt>
<title>
Nasser -- an electronic sample
</title>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Data capture and transcription
</resp>
<name>
Longman ELT
</name>
</respStmt>
</titStmt>
<ednStmt n=s1>
Header automatically generated by mkhdr 0.30
Updated for sampler by interleave 1.1
</ednStmt>
<extent words=4430 kb=86>
</extent>
<pubStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Archive site
</resp>
<name>
Oxford University Computing Services
</name>
</respStmt>
<address>
13 Banbury Road, Oxford OX2 6NN U.K.
Telephone:     +44 1865 273280
Facsimile:     +44 1865 273275
Internet mail: natcorp@oucs.ox.ac.uk
</address>
<idno n=nasser type=bnc>
nasser
</idno>
<avail region=world status=UNKNOWN>
THIS TEXT IS AVAILABLE THROUGHOUT THE WORLD only as
part of the British National Corpus at nominal charge FOR
ACADEMIC RESEARCH PURPOSES SUBJECT TO A SIGNED END USER
LICENCE HAVING BEEN RECEIVED BY OXFORD UNIVERSITY COMPUTING
SERVICES, from whom forms and supporting materials are
available.

THIS TEXT IS NOT AVAILABLE FOR COMMERCIAL RESEARCH AND
EXPLOITATION unless terms have first been agreed with the
BNC Consortium Exploitation Committee.  Apply in the first
instance to Oxford University Computing Services.

It is your responsibility, as a user, to ensure that an End
User Licence is in place.  For your information, the Terms
of the End User Licence are set out in the corpus header, which is
likely to have a file name similar to "corphdr" or "CORPHDR".

Distribution of any part of the corpus under the terms of
the Licence must include a copy of the corpus header.
Distribution of this corpus text under the terms of the
Licence must include this header embodying this notice.

THE EXACT CONDITIONS OF USE FOR THIS TEXT ARE NOT CURRENTLY
KNOWN TO THE ARCHIVING AGENCY.  PLEASE CONTACT THE DATA
CAPTURE AGENCY NAMED IN THIS HEADER FOR FURTHER INFORMATION.
</avail>
<date value=1997-03-11>
1997-03-11
</date>
</pubStmt>
<srcDesc>
<biblStr>
<monogr>
<title>
Nasser
</title>
<author n=WoodwP1>
Woodward, Peter
</author>
<imprint n=LONGMA1>
<name>
Longman Group UK Ltd
</name>
<pubPlace>
Harlow
</pubPlace>
<date>
Ltd
</date>
</imprint>
<biblScop type=PP>
1-13
</biblScop>
</monogr>
</biblStr>
</srcDesc>

</fileDesc>
<encDesc>
<projDesc>
See the project description in the corpus header for
information about the British National Corpus project.
</projDesc>
<refsDecl>
Canonical references in the British National Corpus
are to text segment (&lt;s&gt;) elements, and
are constructed by taking the value of the n attribute
of the &lt;cdif&gt; element containing the target text,
and concatenating a dot separator, followed by the value
of the n attribute of the target &lt;s&gt; element.
</refsDecl>
<tagsDecl>
<tagUsage gi=c occurs=460>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=div1 occurs=2>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=gap occurs=1>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=head occurs=2>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=p occurs=23>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=pb occurs=11>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=s occurs=166>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=text occurs=1>
</tagUsage>
<tagUsage gi=w occurs=4430>
</tagUsage>
</tagsDecl>
</encDesc>
<profDesc>
<creation date=Ltd>
See &lt;biblStr&gt; for publication details.
</creation>
<txtClass>
<catRef target="allava0 alltyp3  wriaag0 wriad0 wriase1 wriaty3 wriaud3 wridom5 wrilev2 wrimed1 wripp826 wrisam2 wrista0 writas0 ">
<keywords>
<term>
history
</term>
</keywords>
</txtClass>
</profDesc>
<revDesc>
<change><date>2 Feb 1999</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>Normalize S numbers</name></respStmt>
</change>
<change><date>16 Oct 98</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>oneLinePatch</name></respStmt>
</change>
<change><date>10 May 97</date>
<respStmt><resp>Patched</resp><name>catRefPatch</name></respStmt>
</change><change n=s1>
<date value=1997-03-11>
1997-03-11
</date>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Amendments for initial release of sampler
</resp>
<name>
dominic
</name>
</respStmt>
</change>
<change n=1>
<date value=1994-11-24>
1994-11-24
</date>
<respStmt>
<resp>
Initial accession to corpus
</resp>
<name>
dominic
</name>
</respStmt>
</change>
</revDesc>
</header>
<text decls="CN004 SN001" complete=N org=SEQ>
<div1 n=1 complete=Y type=chapter org=SEQ>
<head>
<s n=0001><w NP1>Egypt <w II>before <w NP1>Nasser </s>
</head>
<p>
<s n=0002><w AT>The <w NP1>Egypt <w II>into <w DDQ>which <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>born <w VBDZ>was <w II>at <w APPGE>its <w NN1>base <w AT1>an <w JJ>old <w CC>and <w JJ>stable <w NN1>society<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0003><w AT>The <w JJ>recorded <w NN1>history <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w VVZ>goes <w RP>back <w MC>5000 <w NNT2>years <w II>to <w AT>the <w MD>first <w JJ>known <w NN2>pharaohs<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w CS>though <w IF>for <w MC>2000 <w NNT2>years <w EX>there <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w NN2>waves <w IO>of <w NN2>invaders <w VVG>bringing <w MC1>one <w JJ>foreign <w NN1>ruler <w II>after <w DD1>another<c YCOM>, <w IF>for <w DAT>most <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>peasants <c YBL>(<w AT>the <w FW>fellahin<c YBR>) <w NN1>life <w VVD>continued <w RR>much <w CSA>as <w PPH1>it <w VHD>had <w IF>for <w NNT2>centuries<c YCOM>, <w VVN>regulated <w RG>as <w DA1>much <w II>by <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>miracle <w IO>of <w APPGE>its <w JJ>annual <w NN1>flood<c YCOM>, <w CSA>as <w II>by <w JJ>successive <w JJ>new <w NN2>masters<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0004><w AT>The <w NN2>origins <w IO>of <w JJ>Pharaonic <w NP1>Egypt <w VBR>are <w RR>of course <w JJR>older <w CSN>than <w DD1>that <w CC>and <w VV0>derive <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN1>fact <w CST>that <w NP1>Egypt <w VBZ>is <c YQUO>&quot;<w AT>the <w NN1>gift <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile<c YQUO>&quot;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0005><w II>From <w NP1>Wadi <w NP1>Halfa <w II>in <w AT>the <w ND1>south <w II>to <w AT>the <w NP1>Mediterranean <w II>in <w AT>the <w ND1>north<c YCOM>, <w JJ>local <w NN2>communities <w VVD>developed <w JJ>settled <w NN1>agriculture <w II>along <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile <w CC>and <w II>in <w APPGE>its <w JJ>fertile <w NN1>delta<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0006><w VVN>Hemmed <w RP>in <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>vast <w JJ>Libyan <w CC>and <w JJ>Arabian <w NN2>deserts <w II>to <w ND1>west <w CC>and <w ND1>east<c YCOM>, <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w DA1>little <w NN1>room <w TO>to <w VVI>expand<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>densely <w VVN>populated <w JJ>stable <w NN2>communities <w VVD>developed <w II>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>fertile <w NN1>environment <w CST>that <w VVD>encouraged <w JJ>political <w NN1>organisation <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>emergence <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>level <w IO>of <w NN1>civilisation<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0007><w PPH1>It <w VVD>culminated <w II>in <w MC>3000 <w RA>BC <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>unification <w II>by <w NP1>Menes <w IO>of <w JJ>upper <w CC>and <w JJR>lower <w NP1>Egypt <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>flowering <w IO>of <w MC1>one <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>world<w GE>'s <w JJT>greatest <w CC>and <w JJT>longest-lived <w NN2>civilisations<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0008><w CS>Though <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w RRR>later <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>ruled <w IF>for <w NNT2>centuries <w II>by <w AT1>a <w NN1>variety <w IO>of <w NN2>outsiders<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>sense <w IO>of <w AT1>an <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>identity <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN1>grandeur <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>past <w VBDR>were <w RR>never <w RR>entirely <w VVN>forgotten<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0009><w DA1>Much <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>archaeological <w NN1>treasure <w NN1>house <w VVD>decayed<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w APPGE>its <w JJ>sheer <w NN1>scale<c YCOM>, <w VVN>coupled <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>preserving <w NN2>qualities <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>warm <w JJ>dry <w NN1>climate<c YCOM>, <w VVD>ensured <w CST>that <w AT1>a <w NN1>consciousness <w VVD>survived<c YCOM>, <w RGQV>however <w RR>much <w VVN>overlain <w II>by <w JJR>later <w JJ>political <w CC>and <w JJ>cultural <w NN2>changes<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0010><pb n=2> <w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w DA2>many <w CC>and <w JJ>varied <w NN2>invaders <w PNQS>who <w VDD>did <w DA1>much <w TO>to <w VVI>overlay <w DD1>that <w NN1>consciousness <w II>in <w JJ>complex <w CC>and <w JJ>competing <w NN2>ways<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0011><w II>In <w AT>the <w JJR>later <w JJ>pharaonic <w NNT2>centuries <w NP1>Egypt <w VVD>found <w PPX1>itself <w VVN>sacked <w DA2>several <w NNT2>times <w II>by <w NN2>Libyans<c YCOM>, <w NN2>Ethiopians<c YCOM>, <w NN2>Persians <w CC>and <w NN2>Assyrians<c YCOM>, <w II>before <w VBG>being <w VVN>conquered <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN2>Greeks <w II>under <w NP1>Alexander <w II>in <w MC>332 <w RA>BC<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0012><w II>During <w APPGE>his <w NN1>rule <w AT>the <w JJ>great <w JJ>Mediterranean <w NN1>city <w IO>of <w NP1>Alexandria <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>established<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0013><w AT>The <w NN2>Greeks <w VBDR>were <w VVN>followed <w II>in <w MC>30 <w RA>BC <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN1>arrival <w IO>of <w JJ>Roman <w CC>and <w RRR>later <w JJ>Byzantine <w NN2>rulers <w PNQS>who <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>survive <w II>until <w NN1>AD <w MC>638<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0014><w II>In <w JJ>Western <w NN2>minds <w AT>the <w NN1>period <w VBZ>is <w VVN>associated <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>saga <w IO>of <w NP1>Antony <w CC>and <w NP1>Cleopatra<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w IF>for <w JJ>ordinary <w NN2>Egyptians <w II>at <w AT>the <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w MC1>one <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJT>greatest <w NN2>legacies <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w NN1>introduction <w IO>of <w NN1>Christianity <w DDQ>which <w VVD>came <w TO>to <w VVI>replace <w AT>the <w NN1>worship <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>river <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w NN1>panoply <w IO>of <w JJ>associated <w NN2>gods <w CST>that <w VHD>had <w VVN>characterised <w AT>the <w JJ>religious <w NN1>life <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>pharaonic <w NN1>age<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0015><w RR>However<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>indigenous <w NN1>church <w CST>that <w VVD>developed <w II>in <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>Copts<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w APPGE>their <w DA>own <w NN1>monophysite <w NN1>doctrine <w DDQ>which <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>deemed <w JJ>heretical <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>Byzantine <w NN2>rulers<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0016><w JJ>Byzantine <w NN1>rule <w VVD>became <w RR>increasingly <w JJ>unpopular <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN>people<c YCOM>, <w RR>both <w II>because of <w AT>the <w NN1>division <w II>on <w NN1>Christianity<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>high <w NN2>levels <w IO>of <w NN1>taxation <w VVN>exacted<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0017><w II>In <w AT>the <w MD>seventh <w NNT1>century <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>Arabian <w NN2>deserts <w II>to <w AT>the <w ND1>east <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>message<c YCOM>, <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w NN1>Islam<c YCOM>, <w VVD>arose <w CC>and <w VVD>went <w RP>out <w RL>northwards <w II>before <w VVG>turning <w II>to <w AT>the <w ND1>west <w II>into <w ND1>north <w NP1>Africa<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0018><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w RR>only <w AT1>a <w RR>relatively <w JJ>small <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>army <w CST>that <w VVD>arrived <w II>in <w NP1>Egypt <w II>in <w NN1>AD <w MC>639<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>welcomed <w II>by <w DA2>many <w NN2>Egyptians <w JJ>anxious <w TO>to <w VVI>see <w AT>the <w NN1>overthrow <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>unpopular <w JJ>Byzantine <w NN2>rulers<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0019><w AT>The <w NN1>arrival <w IO>of <w NN1>Islam <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>Arabic <w NN1>language <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>mark <w DD1>another <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>great <w JJ>turning <w NN2>points <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>history <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w APPGE>their <w NN1>absorption <w II>by <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>society <w VVD>went <w RP>on <w II>over <w AT1>a <w JJ>long <w NN1>period<c YCOM>, <w VBG>being <w RR>generally <w AT1>a <w JJ>peaceful <w CC>and <w JJ>incremental <w NN1>process<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0020><w CS>Though <w NN2>Arabs <w VDD>did <w VVI>emigrate <w II>to <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>large <w NN1>majority <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>population <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>unchanged<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>indeed <w AT1>a <w JJ>significant <w NN1>minority <w IO>of <w RR>some <w MC>10 <w NNU>per cent <w VVD>remained <w JJ>committed <w NN2>Copts<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0021><w JJ>Arab <w NN1>rule<c YCOM>, <w II>like <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>preceding <w NN2>conquerors<c YCOM>, <w VVD>meant <w NN1>involvement <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJR>wider <w NN2>fortunes <w IO>of <w NN2>empires <w CC>and <w NN2>dynasties <w II>around <w AT>the <w NP1>Mediterranean<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0022><w AT>The <w NN2>Ummayads<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w NN1>dynasty <w VVN>based <w II>in <w NP1>Damascus<c YCOM>, <w VVD>seized <w NP1>Egypt <w II>in <w MC>658<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w VVD>held <w PPH1>it <w RR>only <w II>until <w MC>750<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0023><w II>During <w DD1>that <w NN1>period <w AT>the <w JJ>great <w NN1>schism <w II>within <w NN1>Islam <w II>between <w NN1>sunni <w CC>and <w NN1>shi'ite <w VVD>occurred<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w NP1>Egypt <w VVD>became <w VVN>associated <w IW>with <w AT>the <w DA>former<c YCOM>, <w CSA>as <w PPH1>it <w VHZ>has <w VVN>remained <w RR>ever <w RR>since<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0024><w AT>The <w NN2>Ummayads <w VBDR>were <w VVN>followed <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN2>Abbassids <w PNQS>who <w VVD>sent <w AT1>a <pb n=3> <w NN>series <w IO>of <w NN2>governors <w IO>of <w JJ>Turkish <w NN1>origin <w II>from <w APPGE>their <w NN1>capital <w II>in <w NP1>Baghdad<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0025><w II>In <w NN1>practice <w AT>the <w NN2>governors <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w RR>effectively <w JJ>autonomous<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NP1>Ibn <w NP1>Tulun <w RR>in particular <w VVD>sought <w DD1>this <w NN1>freedom<c YCOM>, <w VVG>bequeathing <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>capital <w NP1>al-Qahira <c YBL>(<w NP1>Cairo<c YBR>) <w II>at <w AT>the <w NN1>centre <w IO>of <w DDQ>which <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w JJ>vast <w NN1>mosque <w JJ>capable <w IO>of <w VVG>housing <w APPGE>his <w NN1>army<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0026><w CS>After <w NP1>Ibn <w NP1>Tulun<w GE>'s <w NN1>death <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w NN1>period <w IO>of <w NN1>confusion <w CC>and <w NN1>decay <w II>before <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>conquest <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN2>Fatimids <w II>from <w ND1>north-west <w NP1>Africa <w II>in <w MC>969<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0027><w II>During <w AT>the <w JJ>brilliant <w NN1>period <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>Fatimids <w AT>the <w NN1>university <w NN1>mosque <w IO>of <w NP1>Al-Azhar<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJT>oldest <w JJ>surviving <w NN1>university <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>world<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>built<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0028><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w AT>the <w JJ>major <w NN1>centre <w IO>of <w NN1>learning <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>Islamic <w NN1>world<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w TO>to <w VVI>provide <w AT1>a <w NN1>source <w IO>of <w NN1>authority <w IF>for <w JJ>successive <w NN2>rulers <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0029><w AT>The <w NN1>period <w IO>of <w NN1>growth <w II>under <w AT>the <w NN2>Fatimids<c YCOM>, <w II>outside <w CC>as well as <w II>inside <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>checked <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>coming <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>Crusaders <w II>from <w NP1>Europe<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0030><w II>In <w NN1>response <w AT>the <w JJ>Syrian-based <w JJ>Seljuk <w NN1>dynasty <w VVD>fought <w RP>back<c YCOM>, <w RR>especially <w II>through <w AT>the <w NN2>exploits <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Kurd <w NP1>Salah <w NP1>al-Din <c YBL>(<w NP1>Saladdin <w CSA>as <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>became <w VVN>known <w II>in <w AT>the <w NP1>West<c YBR>) <w PNQS>who <w PPX1>himself <w VVD>took <w NP1>Egypt <w VVG>establishing <w APPGE>his <w DA>own <w JJ>Ayyubid <w NN1>dynasty <w II>in <w MC>1171<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0031><w VVG>Securing <w PPX1>himself <w II>in <w AT>the <w RR>newly <w VVN>built <w NN1>citadel <w II>on <w AT1>a <w NN1>hill <w VVG>overlooking <w AT>the <w JJ>Fatimid <w NN1>city<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Salah <w NP1>al-Din <w RR>also <w VVD>launched <w APPGE>his <w NN1>army <w RR>once more <w II>against <w AT>the <w NN2>Crusaders <w VVG>driving <w PPHO2>them <w II>from <w NP1>Jerusalem <w II>in <w MC>1178<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0032><w II>Under <w AT>the <w NN2>Ayyubids <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w RR>also <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w DD1>another <w JJ>major <w NN1>development<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>raising <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>mercenary <w NN1>army <w IO>of <w JJ>Turkish <w NN1>slave <w NN2>soldiers <w TO>to <w VVI>protect <w AT>the <w NN2>rulers<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0033><w VVN>Known <w II>as <w NN2>mamluks <c YBL>( <w AT1>an <w JJ>Arabic <w NN1>term <w VVG>meaning <c YQUO>&quot;<w VVN>owned<c YQUO>&quot;<c YBR>) <w DD1>this <w NN1>army <w VVN>raised <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>slave <w NN2>markets <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Caucasus <w CC>and <w RL>beyond<c YCOM>, <w VVD>took <w RP>over <w NN1>power <w II>in <w MC>1250 <w II>at <w AT1>a <w NNT1>time <w IO>of <w JJ>Mongol <w NN1>threat <w II>from <w AT>the <w ND1>east<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0034><w AT>The <w NN2>mamluks <w VBDR>were <w JJ>Turkish-speaking <w CC>and <w II>from <w APPGE>their <w NN1>number <w VVD>arose <w JJ>successive <w NN2>sultans <w TO>to <w VVI>rule <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0035><w TO>To <w VVI>protect <w PPX2>themselves <w NN2>mamluks <w VVD>returned <w II>to <w APPGE>their <w NN1>slave <w NN2>markets <w IO>of <w NN1>origin <w TO>to <w VVI>purchase <w NN2>boys <w PNQS>who <w VBDR>were <w RT>then <w VVN>reared <w II>in <w JJ>existing <w JJ>mamluk <w NN2>households <w VVG>creating <w AT1>an <w JJ>isolated <w JJ>military <w NN1>caste <w TO>to <w VVI>rule <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0036><w NN1>Land <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>parcelled <w RP>out <w II>to <w JJ>major <w NN2>mamluks <w TO>to <w VVI>enrich <w PPX2>themselves <w CC>and <w DD1>this <w JJ>unusual <w NN1>form <w IO>of <w JJ>alien <w NN1>rule <w VVD>perpetuated <w PPX1>itself <w IF>for <w DA2>several <w NNT2>centuries<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0037><w CS>While <w RR>militarily <w JJ>strong <w CC>and <w JK>able <w TO>to <w VVI>protect <w PPX2>themselves <w II>from <w NN1>threat <w RR>both <w II>from <w IW>without <w CC>and <w II>within <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>mamluks <w VBDR>were <w JJ>inefficient <w NN2>rulers<c YCOM>, <w CC>and<c YCOM>, <w CS>though <w PPHS2>they <w VVD>left <w DD>some <w JJ>magnificent <w NN1>architecture<c YCOM>, <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJR>later <w MD>thirteenth <w NNT1>century <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w NN>series <w IO>of <w NN2>revolts<c YCOM>, <w NN2>plagues <w CC>and <w NN2>famines<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0038><w DD1>This <w NN1>weakness <w VVD>left <w NP1>Egypt <w AT1>an <w JJ>easy <w NN1>prey <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>rising <pb n=4> <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN1>empire <w CST>that <w VVD>seized <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w II>in <w MC>1517<c YCOM>, <w VVG>making <w PPH1>it <w RT>then <w AT1>a <w NN1>province <w IO>of <w NP1>Istanbul <w CC>and <w DD1>that <w RR>loosely <w VVN>structured <w NN1>empire <w CST>that <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>dominate <w AT>the <w NP1>Middle <w NP1>East <w II>until <w MC>1918<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0039><w CCB>But <w II>in <w NN1>practice <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN2>rulers <w VVD>worked <w RR>well <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>Circassian <w NN2>mamluks <w IW>with <w PNQO>whom <w PPHS2>they <w VVD>shared <w AT1>a <w JJ>common <w JJ>linguistic <w CC>and <w JJ>cultural <w NN1>background<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0040><w II>In <w NN1>fact<c YCOM>, <w CS>once <w NN2>taxes <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w VVN>paid <w II>to <w NP1>Istanbul<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w RR>largely <w VVN>left <w II>to <w PPX1>itself <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>governed <c YDSH>&mdash; <w CC>and <w RR>increasingly <w VVN>misgoverned <c YDSH>&mdash; <w II>by <w AT1>an <w JJ>Ottoman-mamluk <w JJ>military <w NN1>oligarchy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0041><w VVN>Cut <w RP>off <w II>from <w AT>the <w NN1>mass <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN>people <w II>by <w NN1>race <w CC>and <w NN1>language<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>rulers <w RR>also <w VVD>became <w RR>increasingly <w JJ>acquisitive <w II>in terms of <w NN1>land<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0042><w DD>Some <w NN2>peasants <w RR>effectively <w VVD>found <w PPX2>themselves <w VVN>forced <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w JJ>landless <w JJ>agricultural <w NN2>labourers <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN2>estates <w AT>the <w NN2>Ottomans <w CC>and <w NN2>mamluks <w VVD>carved <w RP>out <w IF>for <w PPX2>themselves<c YCOM>, <w CC>or <w RR>even <w VVN>forced <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN2>cities<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0043><w II>Under <w DD1>this <w JJ>alien <w NN1>system <w AT>the <w NN2>conditions <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Arab <w JJ>Muslim <w NN2>masses <w VVD>became <w RR>ever <w JJR>harsher<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0044><w CC>And <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>hardship <w CC>and <w NN1>suffering <w VVD>went <w AT1>a <w JJ>slow <w CCB>but <w JJ>real <w NN1>decline <w II>in <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0045><w II>At <w AT>the <w NNT1>time <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>invasion <w II>in <w MC>639 <w AT>the <w NN1>population <w VHZ>has <w VBN>been <w VVN>estimated <w II>at <w II>between <w MC>20 <w CC>and <w MC>30 <w NNO>million<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w CS>when <w NP1>Napoleon <w VVD>invaded <w AT>the <w JJ>decaying <w JJ>Ottoman <w NP1>Egypt <w II>in <w MC>1798 <w PPH1>it <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w VVN>reduced <w II>to <w RR>some <w MC>two <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w DB>half <w NNO>million<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0046><w AT>The <w NN1>arrival <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>French <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>usher <w RP>in <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>era<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0047><w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w VVN>shaped <w CC>and <w RT>then <w VVN>dominated <w II>by <w JJ>European <w NN2>developments <w IO>of <w RR>both <w AT1>a <w JJ>political <w CC>and <w JJ>economic <w NN1>character<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0048><w DB2>Both <w NN2>themes <w VBDR>were <w JJ>present <w II>in <w NP1>Napoleon<w GE>'s <w NN1>invasion <w CS>for <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>hoped <w TO>to <w VVI>strike <w AT1>a <w NN1>blow <w II>against <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w NN1>control <w IO>of <w NP1>India <w II>by <w VVG>cutting <w AT>the <w JJ>short <w NN1>overland <w NN1>route <w II>across <w AT>the <w NN1>isthmus <w II>from <w AT>the <w NP1>Mediterranean <w II>to <w AT>the <w NP1>Red <w NNL1>Sea<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>also <w TO>to <w VVI>develop <w JJ>new <w NN1>trading <w NN2>opportunities <w IF>for <w NP1>France <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>eastern <w NP1>Mediterranean<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0049><w AT>The <w NN2>mamluks <w VVD>came <w RP>out <w TO>to <w VVI>meet <w PPHO1>him <w II>in <w NN1>battle<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w APPGE>their <w JJ>colourful <w JJ>medieval <w NN>cavalry <w VBDZ>was <w AT>no <w NN1>match <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>modern <w NN1>firepower <w CC>and <w NN1>discipline <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>army <w IO>of <w NP1>France <w DDQ>which <w VVD>won <w AT1>a <w JJ>decisive <w NN1>victory <w II>at <w AT>the <w NN1>Battle <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>Pyramids<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0050><w NP1>Napoleon <w RT>then <w VVD>climbed <w AT1>a <w NN1>pyramid <w TO>to <w VVI>tell <w APPGE>his <w JJ>triumphant <w NN2>forces <w CST>that <c YQUO>&quot; <w II>From <w DD2>these <w NN2>monuments <w MC>forty <w NNT2>centuries <w VV0>look <w RP>down <w II>upon <w PPY>you<c YQUO>&quot;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0051><w NP1>Napoleon<c YCOM>, <w RR>however<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>given <w DA1>little <w NNT1>time <w TO>to <w VVI>enjoy <w APPGE>his <w NN1>victory<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0052><w AT1>A <w JJ>British <w NN1>fleet <w II>under <w NP1>Nelson <w VVD>sailed <w RP>up <w TO>to <w VVI>defeat <w APPGE>his <w DA>own <w NN2>ships <w II>at <w AT>the <w NN1>Battle <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w IW>with <w JJ>bad <w NN1>news <w II>from <w NP1>Paris <w RR>as well<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Napoleon <w VVD>slipped <w RP>away <w II>in <w MC>1799<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0053><w MC>Two <w NNT2>years <w RRR>later <w AT>the <w JJ>remaining <w JJ>French <w NN2>troops <w VBDR>were <w VVN>confronted <w II>by <w AT1>a <w JJ>Turkish-British <w NN1>land <w NN1>force <w CC>and <w VVD>agreed <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>shipped <w RL>home<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>followed <w RR>voluntarily <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>British<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0054><pb n=5> <w RR>Perhaps <w AT>the <w JJ>outstanding <w NN1>legacy <w IO>of <w NP1>Napoleon<w GE>'s <w NN1>invasion <w VVD>lay <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>bevy <w IO>of <w NN2>experts <w PPHS1>he <w VHD>had <w VVN>brought <w IW>with <w PPHO1>him <w PNQS>who <w VVD>created <w AT>the <c YQUO>&quot; <w FW>Institute <w FW>d'Egypte<c YQUO>&quot; <w VVG>producing <w JJ>numerous <w NN2>volumes <w CST>that <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>launch <w NN1>Egyptology <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>Western <w JJ>academic <w NN1>world <w CC>and<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VVI>remind <w JJ>educated <w NN2>Egyptians <w IO>of <w DA>former <w NN2>glories<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0055><w AT>The <w NN1>departure <w IO>of <w JJ>French <w CC>and <w JJ>British <w NN2>forces <w VVD>left <w PN1>something <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>vacuum<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w VBDZ>was <w RR>swiftly <w VVN>filled <w II>by <w DD1>another <w JJ>Circassian <w NN1>alien<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>wily <w JJ>ambitious <w JJ>Albanian <w NN1>soldier <w IO>of <w NN1>fortune <w PNQS>who <w VHD>had <w VVN>landed <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN1>force<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0056><w VVN>Backed <w II>by <w JJ>Albanian <w NN2>regiments <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>manoeuvred <w RR>skilfully <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>struggles <w II>between <w NN2>Turks <w CC>and <w NN2>mamluks <w CC>and <w II>after <w VVG>imprisoning <w AT>the <w JJ>Turkish <w NN1>governor <w II>in <w MC>1805<c YCOM>, <w VVD>persuaded <w NP1>Istanbul <w TO>to <w VVI>recognise <w PPHO1>him <w II>as <w NP1>Egypt<w GE>'s <w NN1>sultan<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0057><w RT>Then<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w MC>1811<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>he <w RR>cruelly <w VVD>disposed <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>remaining <w JJ>senior <w NN2>mamluks<c YCOM>, <w VVG>massacring <w PPHO2>them <w II>after <w VVG>entertaining <w PPHO2>them <w II>to <w AT1>a <w NN1>feast <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>citadel<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0058><w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w JJ>ruthless <w NN1>figure <w PNQS>who <w VVD>realised <w CST>that <w TO>to <w VVI>exploit <w APPGE>his <w JJ>effective <w NN1>autonomy <w II>as <w NN1>ruler <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>face <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w NN1>power <w IO>of <w NP1>Europe <w RR>in particular<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>he <w VM>would <w VHI>have <w TO>to <w VVI>modernise <w APPGE>his <w NN1>country<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0059><w RR>Firstly<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>needed <w TO>to <w VVI>reform <w AT>the <w NN1>army<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>to <w DD1>this <w NN1>end <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>imported <w MD>first <w JJ>Italian <w CC>and <w RRR>later <w JJ>French <w NN2>experts<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0060><w NN2>Europeans <w CC>and <w NN2>Turks <w VBDR>were <w RR>also <w VVN>engaged <w II>as <w NN2>officers<c YCOM>, <w CS>though <w RRR>later <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w JJ>military <w NN1>college <w VVD>produced <w DD>some <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN2>officers <w II>from <w JJR>better-off <w NN2>families<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0061><w AT>The <w NN2>peasants <w VBDR>were <w RR>only <w TO>to <w VVI>serve <w II>as <w NN2>conscripts<c YCOM>, <w AT1>an <w JJ>unpopular <w NN1>exercise <w CST>that <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>prove <w AT1>a <w JJ>continuing <w NN1>weakness <w IO>of <w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali<w GE>'s <w NN1>army<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0062><w RR>Secondly<c YCOM>, <w JJ>educational <w NN2>reforms <w II>along <w JJ>Western <w NN2>lines <w VVD>produced <w XX>not <w RR>only <w JJ>military <w NN2>officers<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w RR>also <w NN2>professionals <w II>such as <w NN2>doctors<c YCOM>, <w NN2>engineers<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN2>translators<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0063><w RR>Thirdly<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>encouraged <w NN1>health <w NN2>improvements <w II>in <w AT1>an <w NN1>effort <w TO>to <w VVI>raise <w AT>the <w NN2>standards <w IO>of <w NN1>hygiene <w CC>and <w VVD>sought <w TO>to <w VVI>contain <w AT>the <w JJ>sweeping <w NN2>epidemics <w CST>that <w RR>intermittently <w VVD>tore <w II>through <w AT>the <w NN1>population<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0064><w RR>Fourthly<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali <w VVD>set <w RP>out <w TO>to <w VVI>modernise <w AT>the <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>economy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0065><w AT>The <w NN1>state <w VVD>improved <w NN1>irrigation<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVD>organised <w AT>the <w NN1>growing <w CC>and <w NN1>exporting <w IO>of <w NN2>crops <c YBL>(<w II>such as <w NN1>cotton<c YCOM>, <w NN1>indigo <w CC>and <w NN1>sugar<c YBR>) <w IF>for <w AT>the <w JJ>European <w NN1>market<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0066><w NN1>Land <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>parcelled <w RP>out <w II>to <w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali<w GE>'s <w NN1>family <w CC>and <w NN2>associates <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w JJ>new<c YCOM>, <w RR>largely <w JJ>Turkish-oriented<c YCOM>, <w NN1>class <w IO>of <w NN2>landowners <w VVD>developed <w II>in <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w VVG>profiting <w II>from <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w NN2>ties <w IW>with <w NP1>Europe<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0067><w NN2>Factories <w VBDR>were <w RR>also <w VVN>started<c YCOM>, <w RR>primarily <w TO>to <w VVI>meet <w JJ>military <w NN2>requirements<c YSCOL>; <w CCB>but <w CS>while <w NN1>export <w NN2>crops<c YCOM>, <w RR>especially <w NN1>cotton<c YCOM>, <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>expand <w JJ>unchecked<c YCOM>, <w NN1>competition <w II>from <w JJ>European <w NN2>manufacturers<c YCOM>, <pb n=6> <w VVN>permitted <w II>under <w AT>the <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN2>capitulations<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>undermine <w DD1>this <w JJ>nascent <w NN1>attempt <w II>at <w NN1>industrialisation<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0068><w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali<w GE>'s <w NN2>aims <w VBDR>were <w XX>not <w RR>just <w TO>to <w VVI>protect <w NP1>Egypt <w CCB>but <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w PPHO1>her <w AT1>an <w JJ>expansionist <w NN1>power <w II>in <w AT>the <w NP1>Eastern <w NP1>Mediterranean<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0069><w PPHS1>He <w RR>successfully <w VVD>invaded <w NP1>Sudan <w II>to <w AT>the <w ND1>south <w II>in <w MC>1820<c YCOM>, <w VVG>making <w PPH1>it <w RR>effectively <w AT1>a <w NN1>colony<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>in <w DD>some <w NN2>eyes <w RR>even <w AT1>a <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0070><w II>In <w MC>1831 <w CC>and <w MC>1833 <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>went <w RG>so <w RR>far <w CSA>as <w TO>to <w VVI>attack <w AT>the <w NN2>Turks<c YCOM>, <w CS>until <w NP1>Britain <w CC>and <w NP1>Russia <w VVD>intervened <w TO>to <w VVI>protect <w AT>the <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN1>empire <w II>from <w NN1>disintegration<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0071><w II>After <w DD1>that<c YCOM>, <w NN1>age <w VVD>got <w AT>the <w JJR>better <w IO>of <w PPHO1>him<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>both <w PPHS1>he <w CC>and <w APPGE>his <w NN2>efforts <w TO>to <w VVI>modernise <w NP1>Egypt <w VVD>languished<c YSTP>.</s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0072><w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali <w VHD>had <w RR>both <w VVN>established <w AT>the <w MD>last <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>numerous <w JJ>alien <w NN2>dynasties <w TO>to <w VVI>rule <w NP1>Egypt <w CC>and <w VVN>begun <w TO>to <w VVI>lay <w AT>the <w NN1>groundwork <w IF>for <w AT1>a <w JJ>modern <w NN1>state <w II>on <w JJ>European <w NN2>lines<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0073><w CCB>But <w APPGE>his <w JJ>immediate <w NN2>successors<c YCOM>, <w II>following <w APPGE>his <w NN1>death <w II>in <w MC>1849<c YCOM>, <w VVD>made <w DAR>less <w NN1>impression<c YCOM>, <w CS>though <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w JJ>French <w NN1>influence <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w VDD>did <w VVI>lead <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>granting <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>concession <w II>in <w MC>1856 <w II>to <w NP1>Ferdinand <w NP1>de <w NP1>Lesseps <w TO>to <w VVI>build <w AT>the <w NP1>Suez <w NNL1>Canal<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0074><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w XX>not <w CS>until <w NP1>Ismail <w VVD>became <w NN1>Sultan <w II>in <w MC>1863 <c YBL>(<w RR>soon <w VVN>changed <w II>to <w NN1>Khedive<c YBR>) <w CST>that <w EX>there <w VBDZ>was <w DD1>another <w JJ>major <w NN1>drive <w II>towards <w NN1>modernisation<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w AT1>an <w NN1>attempt <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w NP1>Cairo <w AT>the <w NP1>Paris <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>East<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0075><w CCB>But <w AT>the <w NN1>effort <w VVD>proved <w JJ>exhausting <w IF>for <w NP1>Egypt <w CC>and <w II>by <w MC>1875 <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w VBDZ>was <w VVG>heading <w IF>for <w NN1>bankruptcy<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0076><w DD1>This <w VVD>provided <w AT>the <w NN1>opportunity <w IF>for <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w JJ>prime <w NN1>minister<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Disraeli<c YCOM>, <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w AT1>a <w JJ>swift <w NN1>purchase <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<w GE>'s <w NN2>shares <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>canal<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0077><w AT1>A <w NNT1>year <w RRR>later <w AT>the <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>economy <w VBDZ>was <w RR>effectively <w II>in <w NN1>hock<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w JJ>French <w CC>and <w JJ>British <c YQUO>&quot; <w NN2>advisers<c YQUO>&quot; <w VBDR>were <w VVG>running <w AT>the <w FW>Caisse <w FW>de <w FW>la <w FW>Dette <w FW>Publique <w TO>to <w VVI>sort <w PPH1>it <w DB>all <w RP>out<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0078><w II>In <w MC>1879<c YCOM>, <w II>following <w JJ>attempted <w NN1>trickery <w II>by <w NP1>Ismail<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain <w VVD>intervened <w IW>with <w NP1>Istanbul <w TO>to <w VHI>have <w PPHO1>him <w VVN>thrown <w RP>out <w II>in favour of <w APPGE>his <w NN1>son<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Tewfik<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0079><w AT>The <w NN2>circumstances <w CST>that <w VVD>led <w II>to <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w JJ>growing <w NN1>intervention <w VBDR>were <w RR>also <w VVG>provoking <w AT1>a <w NN1>response <w II>among <w NN2>Egyptians<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0080><w AT>The <w JJ>nineteenth-century <w NN1>impact <w IO>of <w NP1>Europe <w II>on <w AT>the <w NP1>Middle <w NP1>East <w VBDZ>was <w VVG>giving <w NN1>rise <w II>to <w NN2>critics <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>Islamic <w NN1>world<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0081><w NP1>Jamal <w NP1>al-Afghani <w VHD>had <w VVN>travelled <w RR>widely <w VVG>encouraging <w JJ>religious <w NN1>reform <w CC>and <w NN2>ideas <w IO>of <w JJ>liberal <w NN1>constitutionalism<c YCOM>, <w DDQ>which <w RR>even <w VHN>had <w AT1>a <w JJ>brief <w NN1>effect <w II>on <w NNB>Khedive <w NP1>Tewfik<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0082><w II>At <w AT>the <w DA>same <w NNT1>time <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN2>intellectuals<c YCOM>, <w DA2>many <w IO>of <w PNQO>whom <w VBDR>were <w NN2>products <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>educational <w NN2>links <w IW>with <w NP1>Europe<c YCOM>, <w VBDR>were <w VVG>developing <w NN2>ideas <w IO>of <w JJ>secular <w NN1>nationalism<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0083><w RR>Meanwhile <w AT>the <w JJ>financial <w NN2>problems <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w VBDR>were <w VVG>leading <w II>to <w NN2>shortages <w CC>and <w NN2>arrears <w IO>of <w NN1>pay <w II>in<pb n=7> <w AT>the <w JJ>public <w NN2>services<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w AT>the <w NN1>army<c YCOM>, <w NN2>peasants <w VBDR>were <w VBG>being <w RR>heavily <w VVN>taxed <w CC>and <w NN2>harvests <w VBDR>were <w JJ>poor<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0084><w PPH1>It <w DB>all <w VVD>culminated <w II>in <w AT1>a <w NN1>rebellion <w II>during <w MCMC>1881&ndash;82<c YCOM>, <w VVN>led <w II>by <w AT1>a <w JJ>nationalistic <w NN1>army <w NN1>officer<c YCOM>, <w NNB>Colonel <w NP1>Ahmed <w NP1>Arabi<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0085><w CS>While <w NP1>France <w VVD>hesitated<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain <w VVD>acted <w RR>decisively <w II>by <w VVG>sending <w AT1>an <w NN1>army <w TO>to <w VVI>crush <w NP1>Arabi<w GE>'s <w NN2>men <w II>at <w NP1>Tel-el-Kebir <w II>in <w MC>1882<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVG>imposing <w DDQ>what <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w II>in <w DB>all <w II>but <w NN1>name <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w NN1>occupation <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0086><w JJ>British <w NN1>domination <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>set <w RP>up <w II>by <w NNB>Sir <w NP1>Evelyn <w NP1>Baring <c YBL>( <w RR>soon <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w NNB>Lord <w NP1>Cromer <w CC>and <w VVN>known <w II>to <w APPGE>his <w NN2>subordinates <w II>as <c YQUO>&quot;<w AT>the <w NN1>Lord<c YQUO>&quot;<c YBR>)<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0087><w CS>Though <w AT>the <w NN1>Khedive <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>remain<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VM>would <w VVI>name <w AT1>a <w NN1>Cabinet <w IO>of <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN2>ministers<c YCOM>, <w DB>all <w VHD>had <w TO>to <w VVI>obey <w AT>the <w NN2>directives <w IO>of <w NP1>Cromer <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>other <w JJ>British <w NN2>advisers <w VVN>appointed <w TO>to <w VVI>reform <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0088><w AT>The <w MD>first <w NN1>concern <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w NN1>stabilisation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>country<w GE>'s <w NN2>finances<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0089><w NN1>Irrigation <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>improved<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w AT>the <w NN1>building <w II>in <w MC>1902 <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>first <w NN1>dam <w II>at <w NP1>Aswan<c YCOM>, <w CS>while <w AT>the <w NN1>economy <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>pushed <w RR>ever <w RRR>more <w II>towards <w AT>the <w NN1>monocrop <w NN1>culture <w IO>of <w NN1>cotton<c YCOM>, <w RR>primarily <w IF>for <w NN1>export <w II>to <w JJ>British <w NN1>textile <w NN2>mills <w II>in <w NP1>Lancashire<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0090><w EX>There <w VBDZ>was <w RR>also <w NN1>reform <w II>in <w DA2>many <w NN2>areas <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>state<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w AT>the <w NN1>rebuilding <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>army<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0091><w CS>While <w EX>there <w VBDR>were <w NN2>improvements <w II>in <w NN1>standard <w II>in <w AT1>a <w NN1>number <w IO>of <w NN2>areas<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w NN1>control <w VVD>emphasised <w AT>the <w NN1>distance <w II>between <w NN2>rulers <w CC>and <w JJ>ruled<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0092><w RR>Formally <w AT>the <w NN2>rulers <w VBDR>were <w AT>the <w NN1>Khedive <w CC>and <w APPGE>his <w NN2>ministers<c YCOM>, <w RR>mainly <w JJ>Turco-Circassian <w II>in <w NN1>origin<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w II>behind <w PPHO2>them <w VVD>lay <w AT>the <w JJ>real <w NN1>power <w IO>of <w RR>even <w RGR>more <w JJ>alien <w NN2>masters<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w II>under <w DDQ>what <w VHD>had <w VVN>become <w VVN>known <w II>as <w AT>the <c YQUO>&quot;<w JJ>veiled <w NN1>protectorate<c YQUO>&quot;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0093><w II>In <w NNT1>time <w DD1>this <w VVD>led <w II>to <w NN1>resentment<c YCOM>, <w RR>especially <w II>among <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w JJ>educated <w NN1>group <w PNQS>who <w VVD>felt <w AT>the <w NN1>arrogance <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w RGT>most <w RR>directly<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0094><w TO>To <w VVI>make <w NN2>matters <w JJR>worse <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w NN1>government <w RR>repeatedly <w VVD>announced <w CST>that <w PPH1>it <w VM>would <w VBI>be <w VVG>pulling <w II>out of <w NP1>Egypt <w CS>once <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w VBDZ>was <w II>on <w AT1>a <c YQUO>&quot;<w JJ>sound<c YQUO>&quot; <w NN1>footing<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0095><w RR>Yet <w II>in <w NN1>practice <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w VVD>seemed <w TO>to <w VVI>dig <w RP>in <w RR>ever <w RRR>deeper<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0096><w II>As <w AT1>a <w NN1>result<c YCOM>, <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>early <w MC2>1900s<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>nationalist <w NN1>undercurrent <w VBDZ>was <w VVG>developing <w VVN>led <w II>by <w AT1>a <w JJ>charismatic <w JJ>young <w NN1>man<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Mustafa <w NP1>Kamil<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w CS>though <w EX>there <w VBDR>were <w NN2>strikes <w CC>and <w NN2>demonstrations <c YBL>( <w DDQ>which <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w AT1>a <w JJ>regular <w NN1>feature <w IO>of <w JJ>Egyptian <w JJ>political <w NN1>life<c YBR>)<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain <w VVD>remained <w RG>as <w JJ>unmoved<c YCOM>, <w JJ>aloof <w CC>and <w JJ>arrogant <w CSA>as <w RR>ever<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0097><w AT>The <c YQUO>&quot;<w NN1>veil<c YQUO>&quot; <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>lifted <w II>from <w JJ>British <w NN1>domination <w CC>and <w AT1>a <w NN1>protectorate <w VVN>proclaimed <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN1>coming <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>First <w NN1>World <w NN1>War <w II>in <w MC>1914<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0098><w RR>Legally <w NP1>Egypt <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w JJ>Ottoman<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w CS>since <w AT>the <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN1>empire <w VBDZ>was <w VVG>siding <w IW>with <w NP1>Germany <w NP1>Britain <w VBDZ>was <w II>at <w NN1>war <w IW>with <w NP1>Turkey <w CC>and <w RR>hence <w VVN>required <w TO>to <w VVI>annex <w NP1>Egypt <pb n=8> <w RR>formally<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0099><w II>During <w AT>the <w NN1>conflict <w NP1>Egypt <w VVD>became <w AT1>a <w JJ>vast <w NN1>transit <w NN1>camp <w CSA>as <w NNO2>thousands <w IO>of <w JJ>allied <w NN2>troops <w VVD>poured <w RP>through<c YCOM>, <w VVG>moving <w II>between <w NP1>Asia<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NP2>Antipodes <w CC>and <w NP1>Europe<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0100><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w RR>also <w AT1>a <w NN1>base <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN2>campaigns <w MD>first <w II>in <w NP1>Gallipoli <w CC>and <w RRR>later <w II>in <w NP1>Palestine<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0101><w DA>Such <w NN1>disruption <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>effects <w PPH1>it <w VHD>had <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>life <w CC>and <w NN1>economy <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w VVD>fuelled <w NN1>resentment <w II>against <w JJ>British <w NN1>domination<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0102><w AT>The <w NN1>principle <w IO>of <w NN1>self-determination <w VVN>enunciated <w II>by <w NP1>America<w GE>'s <w NNB>President <w NP1>Woodrow <w NP1>Wilson <w II>as <w AT>the <w NN1>basis <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>peace <w NN1>conference <w II>in <w NP1>Paris <w II>in <w MC>1918<c YCOM>, <w VVD>led <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>request <w IO>of <w JJ>senior <w NN2>Egyptians <w VVN>led <w II>by <w NP1>Sa'ad <w NP1>Zaghlul <w CST>that <w AT1>a <w NN1>Wafd <c YBL>(<w NN1>delegation<c YBR>) <w VBI>be <w VVN>sent <w TO>to <w VVI>represent <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Zaghulul <w VBDZ>was <w IO>of <w JJ>peasant <w NN1>background <w CC>and <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w JJ>charismatic <w NN1>figure <w IW>with <w JJ>great <w NN1>appeal <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>public<c YCOM>, <w II>among <w PNQO>whom <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w RR>popularly <w VVN>known <w II>as <w FW>al <w FW>zaim<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>leader<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0103><w II>As <w AT1>a <w NN1>result<c YCOM>, <w CS>when <w NP1>Britain <w VVD>refused <w AT>the <w NN1>request <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>Wafd <w TO>to <w VVI>go <w II>to <w NP1>Paris <w AT1>a <w NN1>wave <w IO>of <w JJ>nationalist <w NN2>demonstrations <w VVD>convulsed <w NP1>Egypt <w CC>and <w VVD>lasted <w IF>for <w DA1>much <w IO>of <w MC>1919<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0104><w NP1>Zaghlul <w CC>and <w APPGE>his <w NN2>colleagues <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w VVN>deported <w II>to <w NP1>Malta<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w NP1>Britain <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>forced <w TO>to <w VVI>allow <w PPHO2>them <w TO>to <w VVI>go <w II>to <w NP1>Paris<c YCOM>, <w CS>though <w XX>not <w II>as <w NN2>negotiators<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0105><w NP1>Britain<c YCOM>, <w RR>though<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w RR>still <w VVN>prepared <w TO>to <w VVI>offer <w DA1>little<c YCOM>, <w CS>for <w PPHS1>she <w VVD>saw <w NP1>Egypt <w II>as <w AT1>a <w JJ>vital <w JJ>strategic <w NN1>position <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>post-war <w NN1>world<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NN1>agitation <w VVD>broke <w RP>out <w RR>once more<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w NP1>Zaghlul <w RT>again <w VVN>exiled<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0106><w II>In <w AT1>a <w JJ>desperate <w NN1>attempt <w TO>to <w VVI>meet <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN2>demands <w CC>and <w JJ>British <w NN1>interest<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w JJ>new <w JJ>High <w NN1>Commissioner<c YCOM>, <w NNB>Lord <w NP1>Allenby<c YCOM>, <w VVD>announced <w II>in <w MC>1922 <w AT>the <w NN1>ending <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>Protectorate <w CC>and <w AT>the <c YQUO>&quot; <w NN1>independence<c YQUO>&quot; <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0107><w NP1>Britain <w RR>however <w VM>would <w VVI>retain <w NN1>control <w IO>of <w JJ>certain <w JJ>reserved <w NN2>subjects<c YCOL>: <w NP1>Egypt<w GE>'s <w NN1>defence<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w AT>the <w NN1>retention <w IO>of <w JJ>British <w NN2>bases<c YSCOL>; <w JJ>imperial <w NN2>communications<c YCOM>, <w RR>especially <w AT>the <w NP1>Suez <w NNL1>Canal<c YSCOL>; <w AT>the <w NN1>protection <w IO>of <w JJ>foreign <w NN2>interests <w II>in <w NP1>Egypt<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NP1>Sudan<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>route <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile <w NN2>waters<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0108><w DA>Such <c YQUO>&quot;<w JJ>controlled<c YQUO>&quot; <w NN1>independence <w VVD>fitted <w AT>the <w JJ>general <w NN1>pattern <w IO>of <w NN1>thinking <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>victorious <w JJ>European <w NN2>powers <w II>about <w AT>the <w JJ>post-war <w NP1>Middle <w NP1>East<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0109><w VHG>Having <w VVN>propped <w RP>up <w AT>the <w JJ>Ottoman <w NN1>empire <w IF>for <w AT>the <w DA>latter <w NN1>part <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>nineteenth <w NNT1>century<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Britain <w CC>and <w NP1>France <w RT>now <w VVD>set <w RP>about <w VVG>dismantling <w PPH1>it<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0110><w CS>While <w NP1>Egypt <w VM>might <w VBI>be <w RR>sufficiently <w JJ>advanced <w IF>for <w AT1>a <w JJ>liberal <w JJ>democratic <w NN1>experiment<c YCOM>, <w JJ>other <w NN2>states <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>region <w VBDR>were <w RR>certainly <w NN2>states <w CC>and <w VVD>elevated <w JJ>local <w NN2>leaders<c YCOM>, <w II>such as <w JJ>religious <w CC>or <w JJ>tribal <w NN2>chiefs <w II>into <w NN2>monarchs<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n="111(110)"><w VHG>Having <w VVN>seen <w AT>the <w NN1>possibility <w IO>of <w JJ>Arab <w JJ>national <w NN1>unity <w VVN>advanced <w II>during <w AT>the <w NN1>war <w VVN>dashed<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>Hashemite <w NN1>family <w IO>of <w NNB>Sherif <w NP1>Abdullah <w IO>of <w NP1>Mecca <w VBDZ>was <w RT>now <pb n=9> <w VVN>encouraged <w II>by <w NP1>Britain <w TO>to <w VVI>provide <w NN2>kings <w IF>for <w JJ>new <w NN2>states <w II>in <w NP1>Jordan <w CC>and <w NP1>Iraq<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0112><w CC>And <w CS>while <w NP1>Britain <w VVD>accepted <w AT>the <w NN1>rise <w IO>of <w NP1>Ibn <w NP1>Saud <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>new <w NN1>country <w IO>of <w NP1>Saudi <w NP1>Arabia<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>she <w RR>also <w VVD>kept <w NN1>faith <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>tiny <w NN2>emirates <w II>along <w AT>the <w JJ>western <w NN1>flank <w IO>of <w NP1>Arabia <w II>from <w NP1>Kuwait <w II>to <w NP1>Oman<c YCOM>, <w II>over <w DDQ>which <w PPHS1>she <w VHD>had <w VVN>exercised <w NN1>protection <w IF>for <w RR>more than <w AT1>a <w NNO>hundred <w NNT2>years<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0113><w RR>Meanwhile <w NP1>Palestine <w VVD>became <w AT1>a <w RR>directly <w VVN>administered <w JJ>British <w NN1>mandate<c YCOM>, <w CS>while <w AT>the <w JJ>French <w VVD>imposed <w PPX2>themselves <w II>in <w NP1>Syria <w CC>and <w NP1>Lebanon<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>Italians <w II>in <w NP1>Cyrenaica <c YBL>(<w NP1>Libya<c YBR>)<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0114><w NN2>Dreams <w IO>of <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>nationalism <w VVN>raised <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>revolt <w II>against <w AT>the <w NN2>Ottomans <w II>in <w AT>the <w MD>First <w NN1>World <w NN1>War<c YCOM>, <w RT>then <w VVD>turned <w RR>instead <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN1>reality <w IO>of <w JJ>separate <w NN2>states<c YCOM>, <w RR>clearly <w VVN>supervised <w II>by <w AT>the <w MC>two <w JJ>major <w JJ>European <w NN2>victors<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0115><w JJ>European <w NN1>overlordship<c YCOM>, <w RR>however<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>prove <w JJ>incompatible <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NN2>notions <w IO>of <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>nationalism <w CST>that <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w VVG>growing <w II>since <w AT>the <w NN1>end <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>nineteenth <w NNT1>century<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w AT>no <w NN1>surprise <w CST>that <w DD1>this <w VM>would <w VVI>become <w JJ>apparent <w MD>first <w II>in <w AT>the <w RGT>most <w JJ>advanced <w NN1>country <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN1>region<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Egypt<c YSTP>.</s>
<s n=0116><w NP1>Egypt<w GE>'s <w NN1>independence <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w AT1>a <w JJ>unilateral <w NN1>declaration <w II>by <w NP1>Britain<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w AT>the <w NN2>reservations <w VVN>imposed <w VBDR>were <w TO>to <w VVI>become <w AT1>a <w JJ>running <w NN1>sore <w II>in <w AT>the <w NN2>relations <w II>between <w AT>the <w MC>two <w NN2>countries<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0117><w EX>There <w VBDR>were <w JJ>repeated <w NN2>attempts <w TO>to <w VVI>negotiate <w AT1>a <w RG>more <w JJ>satisfactory <w NN1>agreement<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w DD2>these <w VVD>foundered <w II>in <w MC>1924<c YCOM>, <w MC>1926 <w CC>and <w MC>1929 <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>inability <w TO>to <w VVI>match <w AT>the <w NN2>aspirations <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w IF>for <w JJ>full <w NN1>independence <w IW>with <w NP1>Britain<w GE>'s <w NN1>perception <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>requirements <w VVN>needed <w TO>to <w VVI>protect <w APPGE>her <w NN2>interests<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0118><w II>At <w AT>the <w DA>same <w NNT1>time <w CSA>as <w NN2>Egyptians <w VBDR>were <w VVN>frustrated <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN2>reservations<c YCOM>, <w RR>so <w AT>the <w JJ>internal <w JJ>political <w NN2>arrangements <w VVD>proved <w JJ>unsatisfactory <w RR>as well<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0119><w II>In <w NN1>theory <w NP1>Egypt <w VBDZ>was <w VVG>embarking <w II>on <w AT1>a <w JJ>constitutional <w JJ>liberal <w NN1>democracy<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w NN1>practice <w VVD>proved <w PN1>something <w DAR>less<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0120><w AT>The <w NN1>king<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Faud<c YCOM>, <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>an <w JJ>autocratic <w NN1>character <w VVN>determined <w TO>to <w VVI>exercise <w NN1>power <w II>in <w APPGE>his <w DA>own <w NN1>right<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w CS>since <w PPHS1>he <w VHD>had <w VBN>been <w VVN>installed <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>felt <w II>by <w NN2>Egyptians <w CST>that <w NP1>Britain <w RR>effectively <w VVD>underwrote <w APPGE>his <w NN1>position<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0121><w EX>There <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>an <w JJ>elected <w NN1>parliament <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w NN1>Wafd <w VBDZ>was <w RT>now <w AT>the <w NN1>country<w GE>'s <w JJ>leading <w NN1>party <w CC>and <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w NN1>Wafd <w VBDZ>was <w RT>now <w AT>the <w NN1>country<w GE>'s <w JJ>leading <w NN1>party <w CC>and <w DDQ>which <w NP1>Zaghlul<c YCOM>, <w PNQS>who <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>opposed <w II>to <w NP1>Faud<c YCOM>, <w VVD>dominated <w II>until <w APPGE>his <w NN1>death <w II>in <w MC>1927<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0122><w CCB>But <w NN1>government <w VVD>needed <w AT>the <w NN1>acceptance <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>king<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>in <w NN1>practice <w AT>the <w NN1>support <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>British <w NN1>Residency<c YCOM>, <w VVG>making <w JJ>political <w NN1>life <w AT1>a <w JJ>triangular <w NN1>struggle <w CST>that <w VDD>did <w DA1>little <w TO>to <w VVI>make <w AT>the <w JJ>ordinary <w NN1>Egyptian <w VVI>feel <w CST>that <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>counted<c YCOM>, <w II>let alone <w VHD>had <w AT1>a <w NN1>part <w TO>to <w VVI>play<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0123><w II>By <w AT>the <w JJ>early <w MC2>1930s<pb n=10> <w NN1>scepticism <w IW>with <w JJ>liberal <w NN1>democracy <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>widespread<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0124><w IW>With <w AT>the <w JJ>popular <w NP1>Zaghlul <w JJ>dead <w PPH1>it <w VVD>seemed <w CS>as if <w AT>the <w JJ>British<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>king <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>old <w JJ>landed <w JJ>ruling <w NN1>class <w VVD>retained <w NN1>power <w CC>and <w VBDR>were <w VVG>becoming <w RGR>more <w JJ>autocratic<c YCOM>, <w VVG>negating <w AT>the <w JJ>nationalist <w NN1>upsurge <w IO>of <w MCMC>1919&ndash;22<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0125><w RR>Meanwhile<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>economy <w CC>and <w NN1>society<c YCOM>, <w VHG>having <w VBN>been <w VVN>drawn <w RR>ever <w RGR>more <w RR>tightly <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN1>world <w NN1>economy <w II>by <w AT>the <w NN1>concentration <w II>on <w NN1>cotton<c YCOM>, <w VBDR>were <w JJ>vulnerable <w II>to <w APPGE>its <w JJ>widening <w NN2>swings <w DDQ>which <w II>in <w MC>1929 <w VVD>culminated <w II>in <w AT>the <w NP1>Wall <w NNL1>Street <w NN1>Crash <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>subsequent <w NN1>Depression<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0126><w DA>Such <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w JJ>disturbed <w NN1>world <w II>in <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w JJ>young <w JJ>impressionable <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>take <w APPGE>his <w MD>first <w NN2>steps <w II>in <w NN1>politics <w II>in <w AT>the <w MC2>1930s<c YSTP>. <pb n=11></s>
</p>
</div1>
<div1 n=2 complete=Y type=chapter org=SEQ>
<head>
<s n=0127><w AT>The <w NN1>Making <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w NN1>Nationalist<c YCOL>: <w MCMC>1918&ndash;52 </s>
</head>
<p>
<s n=0128><w NP1>Gamal <w NP1>Abdul <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>born <w II>on <w MC>15 <w NPM1>January <w MC>1918 <w II>in <w NP1>Alexandria<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVD>grew <w RP>up <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>political <w NN1>turmoil <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w II>between <w AT>the <w MC>two <w NN1>world <w NN2>wars<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0129><w DD1>This <w NN1>experience <w VVD>shaped <w AT>the <w JJ>political <w NN1>ambition <w CST>that <w VVD>led <w RR>ultimately <w II>to <w APPGE>his <w NN1>coup <w IO>of <w MC>23 <w NPM1>July <w MC>1952<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0130><w AT>The <w MD>First <w NN1>World <w NN1>War <w VHD>had <w VVN>kindled <w NN2>hopes <w CC>and <w NN1>opportunity <w IW>with <w AT1>an <w NN1>outburst <w IO>of <w NN1>nationalism <w CST>that <w VVD>led <w II>to <w NP1>Egypt<w GE>'s <w JJ>formal <w NN1>independence <w II>from <w JJ>British <w NN1>control <w II>in <w MC>1922<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w II>by <w AT>the <w NNT1>time <w IO>of <w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w NN1>adolescence <w DD2>those <w NN2>feelings <w VBDR>were <w VVG>turning <w JJ>sour<c YSCOL>; <w VVG>causing <w NN1>disillusionment <w II>among <w AT>the <w JJ>youthful <w NN2>radicals <w IO>of <w PNQO>whom <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w PN1>one<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0131><w AT>The <w MD>Second <w NN1>World <w NN1>War <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VVI>bring <w RP>about <w AT1>an <w NN1>intensification <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>disillusionment <w IW>with <w JJ>national <w CC>and <w JJ>international <w NN1>politics <w CST>that <w VVD>led <w NP1>Nasser <w TO>to <w VVI>seek <w AT1>an <w NN1>alternative <w II>through <w AT>the <w NN1>organisation <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>Free <w NN1>Officer <w NN1>corps <w CC>and <w AT>the <w VVG>carrying <w RP>out <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>successful <w NN1>coup d'etat<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0132><w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w AT1>a <w NN1>figure <w XX>not <w RR>only <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w NNT1>time<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w JJ>social <w NN1>background <w RR>as well<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0133><w APPGE>His <w NN1>family <w VBDZ>was <w MC1>one <w NN1>generation <w VVN>removed <w II>from <w NN2>peasants<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>in <w JJ>close <w NN1>touch <w IW>with <w AT>the <w JJ>small <w NN1>village <w IO>of <w NP1>Beni <w NNL1>Moor <w II>near <w NP1>Assiut <w II>in <w NP1>Upper <w NP1>Egypt<c YCOM>, <w RRQ>where <w II>as <w AT1>a <w NN1>boy <w NP1>Nasser <w VVD>spent <w APPGE>his <w NN2>holidays<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0134><w AT>The <w NN1>family <w VBDZ>was <w RR>far <w II>from <w VBG>being <w AT>the <w JJT>poorest <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>peasants<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w NP1>Nasser <w RR>nonetheless <w VHD>had <w JJ>first-hand <w NN1>experience <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>poverty-stricken <w NN2>conditions <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>rural <w NN2>Egyptians<c YCOM>, <w VVN>crammed <w RP>in <w II>along <w AT>the <w NN2>banks <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NP1>Nile <w II>on <w DDQ>which <w AT>the <w JJ>whole <w NN1>country <w VVD>depended<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0135><w RR>Economically <w AT>the <w NN1>system <w VVD>continued <w TO>to <w VVI>serve <w AT>the <w JJ>tiny <w JJ>landed <w NN1>class<c YCOM>, <w DAT>most <w IO>of <w PPHO2>them <w IO>of <w JJ>Turkish <w II>rather than <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>origin <w VVG>reflecting <w AT>the <w NNT2>centuries <w IO>of <w NN1>domination <w II>by <w AT>the <w NP1>Ottoman <w NNL1>Empire<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0136><w AT>The <w NN1>introduction <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w RG>more <w JJ>commercial <w NN1>economy <w II>into <w AT>the <w NN1>country <w II>in <w AT>the <w MD>nineteenth <w NNT1>century <w VDD>did <w DA1>little <w TO>to <w VVI>change <w AT>the <w JJ>basic <w JJ>social <w NN1>structure <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>countryside<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0137><w RR>Politically <w AT>the <w NN1>life <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>peasants <w VBDZ>was <w RG>very <w JJ>parochial <w CC>and <pb n=12> <w VVN>dominated <w II>by <w AT>the <w JJ>local <w NN2>headmen<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN2>sheikhs <w CC>and <w NN2>omdas<c YCOM>, <w PNQS>who <w VVD>served <w II>as <w NN2>collaborators <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>state<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0138><w APPGE>Their <w NN2>tasks <w VVD>included <w VVG>collecting <w NN2>taxes <w CC>and <w CS>when <w JJ>necessary <w VVG>producing <w NN2>labourers <w IF>for <w JJ>public <w NN2>works <w II>on <w NN2>dams<c YCOM>, <w NN2>canals <w CC>or <w NN2>bridges<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w VVG>enlisting <w AT>the <w JJ>required <w NN2>numbers <w IO>of <w NN2>men <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>army <w PNQS>who <w VVD>lacked <w AT>the <w NN1>money <w TO>to <w VVI>buy <w PPX2>themselves <w II>out of <w JJ>national <w NN1>service<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0139><w NP1>Nasser <w VVD>maintained <w APPGE>his <w NN2>memories <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN2>peasants <w DB>all <w APPGE>his <w NN1>life <w CC>and <w RR>often <w VVD>referred <w II>to <w APPGE>their <w NN1>plight <w CS>before <w RR>even <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>came <w II>to <w NN1>power<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0140><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w AT>the <w JJ>social <w CC>and <w JJ>political <w NN1>change <w IO>of <w AT>the <w MD>nineteenth <w CC>and <w JJ>early <w MD>twentieth <w NNT1>century <w CST>that <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>reflected <w RR>both <w II>in <w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w NN1>background <w CC>and <w II>in <w APPGE>his <w JJ>early <w JJ>political <w NN1>thinking <w CC>and <w NN1>activity<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0141><w AT>The <w NN1>making <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w JJ>modern <w NN1>state <w VVD>provided <w JJ>new <w NN2>opportunities <w IF>for <w NN2>peasants <w IW>with <w DD>some <w NN1>education <w TO>to <w VVI>move <w II>into <w JJ>lower-middle-class <w NN2>occupations<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0142><w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w NN1>father <w VVD>belonged <w II>to <w DD1>this <w JJ>growing <w JJ>social <w NN1>stratum<c YCOM>, <w VVG>running <w AT1>a <w NN1>post <w NN1>office <w II>in <w NP1>Alexandria <w CS>when <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>born <w CC>and <w RRR>later <w VBG>being <w VVN>transferred <w II>to <w NP1>Khatatba<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>poor <w NN1>village <w II>on <w AT>the <w NN1>edge <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>delta<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0143><w VVG>Coming <w II>from <w JJ>upper <w NP1>Egypt <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>known <w II>as <w FW>saidi<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w CSA>as <w DA>such <w VVN>seen <w II>by <w APPGE>his <w NN2>countrymen <w II>in <w JJR>lower <w NP1>Egypt <w II>as <w AT1>a <w JJ>proud<c YCOM>, <w RG>rather <w JJ>prickly <w NN1>personality<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w AT1>a <w JJ>strong <w NN1>sense <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w DA>own <w NN1>dignity<c YCOL>: <w NN2>qualities <w DDQ>which <w VBDR>were <w VVN>inherited <w II>by <w APPGE>his <w NN1>son<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0144><w XX>Not <w CST>that <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w RG>very <w JJ>close <w II>to <w APPGE>his <w NN1>father<c YCOL>: <w RR>indeed <w APPGE>his <w JJ>early <w NN1>family <w NN2>relationships <w VV0>seem <w RG>rather <w JJ>traumatic<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0145><w PPHS1>He <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>attached <w II>to <w APPGE>his <w NN1>mother<c YCOM>, <w CCB>but <w PPHS1>she <w VVD>died <w II>in <w MC>1926<c YCOM>, <w CS>while <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w RL>away <w VVG>living <w IW>with <w APPGE>his <w NN1>uncle <w II>in <w NP1>Cairo<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0146><w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w XX>not <w VVN>informed <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w NN1>mother<w GE>'s <w NN1>death <w CS>until <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>returned <w II>to <w NP1>Khatatba<c YCOM>, <w DA2>several <w NNT2>months <w RRR>later<c YCOM>, <w CS>when <w PPH1>it <w VVD>came <w II>as <w AT1>a <w JJ>great <w NN1>shock<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0147><w PPHS1>He <w RRR>later <w VVD>said <w PPH1>it <w VBDZ>was <c YQUO>&quot;<w AT1>a <w JJ>cruel <w NN1>blow <w CST>that <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>imprinted <w RR>indelibly <w II>on <w APPGE>my <w NN1>mind<c YQUO>&quot;<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0148><w PPH1>It <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>followed <w II>by <w DD1>another <w CS>when <w APPGE>his <w NN1>father <w RR>swiftly <w VVD>remarried<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w II>from <w RT>then <w RP>on <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w RR>never <w JJ>close <w II>to <w PPHO1>him<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0149><w PPHS1>He <w VVD>felt <w JJ>estranged <w II>from <w APPGE>his <w NN1>father <w CC>and <w APPGE>his <w JJ>new <w NN1>family<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w IF>for <w AT>the <w MD>next <w DA2>few <w NNT2>years <w VBDZ>was <w RP>back <w CC>and <w RR>forth <w II>between <w NP1>Cairo <w CC>and <w NP1>Alexandria <w VVG>living <w IW>with <w APPGE>his <w NN2>uncles <w CC>and <w VVG>attending <w JJ>different <w NN2>schools<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0150><w PPHS1>He <w VBDZ>was <w XX>not <w AT1>a <w JJ>happy <w NN1>child<c YCOM>, <w VVG>appearing <w JJ>uneasy<c YCOM>, <w JJ>cautious <w CC>and <w IO>of <w AT1>a <w RG>rather <w JJ>secretive <w NN1>nature<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0151><w CCB>But <w II>like <w DA2>Many <w FW>saidi<c YCOM>, <w CS>when <w APPGE>his <w NN1>pride <w CC>or <w NN1>dignity <w VBDR>were <w VVN>crossed <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>capable <w IO>of <w JJ>fierce <w NN1>anger <w CC>and <w JJ>determinate <w NN1>action<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0152><w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w JJ>lower-middle-class <w NN1>background <w VVD>contributed <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>widening <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w JJ>political <w NN2>interests <w II>beyond <w DD2>those <w JJ>imaginable <w II>to <w AT>the <w FW>fellahin<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w NN1>peasantry<c YSCOL>; <w CS>while <w II>at <w AT>the <w DA>same <w NNT1>time <w VVG>making <w PPHO1>him <w JJ>aware <w IO>of <w AT>the <w DA>latter<w GE>'s <w NN1>situation<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w AT>the <w JJ>political <w CC>and <w JJ>economic <w NN1>oppression <w VVN>suffered<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0153><w II>In <w APPGE>his <w JJ>various <w NN2>schools <w II>in <w JJR>lower <w NP1>Egypt <w NP1>Nasser <w VHZ>has <w AT1>a <w JJ>certain <w NN1>self-consciousness <w II>as <w AT1>a <w FW>saidi <w CC>and <w PN1>one <w IO>of <w JJ>peasant <w NN1>background<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0154><w DD1>This <w VM>may <w VHI>have <w VVN>contributed <w II>to <w AT>the <w NN1>vigour <w IW>with <w DDQ>which <w PPHS1>he <w VVD>immersed <w PPX1>himself <w II>in <w AT>the <w JJ>growing <w NN1>student <w NN1>unrest <w CST>that <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w NN1>feature <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>political <w NN2>upheavals <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NNT1>time<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0155><w RR>Perhaps <w II>because of <w APPGE>his <w JJ>self-contained <w NN1>nature<c YCOM>, <w AT>the <w JJ>young <w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w AT1>a <w JJ>considerable <w NN1>reader<c YCOM>, <w VVG>focusing <w RR>particularly <w II>on <w JJ>historical <w NN2>works<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0156><w PPHS1>He <w VVD>liked <w NP1>Voltaire<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Rousseau<c YCOM>, <w NNB>Baroness <w NP1>Orczy <w CC>and <w NP1>Dickens<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w RR>also <w JJ>popular <w NN2>biographies <w IO>of <w AT>the <w JJ>famous<c YCOM>, <w II>including <w NP1>Alexander <w AT>the <w JJ>Great<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Julius <w NP1>Caesar<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Napoleon <w CC>and <w NP1>Bismarck<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0157><w RGR>More <w JJ>contemporary <w NN2>figures <w PNQS>who <w VVD>captured <w APPGE>his <w NN1>imagination <w VVD>included <w NP1>Gandhi <w CC>and <w NP1>Attaturk<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0158><w DD1>Another <w JJ>important <w NN1>strand <w IO>of <w APPGE>his <w NN1>reading <w VBDZ>was <w JJ>romantic <w JJ>Islamic <w CC>and <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>renaissance <w NN2>books<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0159><w DA>Such <w NN2>works <w VBDR>were <w RG>very <w JJ>popular<c YSCOL>; <w VVG>conjuring <w RP>up <w NN2>images <w IO>of <w JJ>past <w NN2>ages <w IO>of <w NN1>grandeur<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w VVG>fostering <w AT1>a <w NN1>yearning <w IF>for <w AT1>a <w JJ>new <w NN1>future<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0160><w NP1>Mahmoud <w NP1>Abbas <w NP1>al-Aqqad <w VVD>popularised <w JJ>Muslim <w NN2>heros <w RR>anew<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NP1>Tawfiq <w NP1>al-Hakim<c YCOM>, <w AT1>a <w JJ>great <w NN1>favourite <w IO>of <w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s<c YCOM>, <w VVD>called <w IF>for <w AT>the <w NN1>resurrection <w IO>of <w NP1>Egypt <w II>under <w AT1>a <w JJ>charismatic <w NN1>leader<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0161><w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w NN1>self-consciousness <w VVD>found <w JJ>imaginative <w NN1>redirection <w II>into <w JJ>romantic <w NN1>awareness <w IO>of <w JJ>Egyptian <w NN1>nationalism<c YSTP>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s n=0162><w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w RRR>later <w RR>both <w TO>to <w VVI>draw <w II>on <w DD1>that <w JJ>historical <w NN1>legacy<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>compared <w II>to <w NN2>figures <w II>from <w PPH1>it<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0163><w PPHS1>He <w VBDZ>was <w RR>often <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>referred <w II>to <w II>as <w AT1>a <w JJ>modern <w NN1>pharaoh <w II>by <w NN2>Egyptians <w CS>when <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w II>in <w NN1>power<c YSCOL>; <w CC>and <w RR>in particular <w AT>the <w NP1>High <w NNL1>Dam <w II>at <w NP1>Aswan <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>spoken <w IO>of <w II>as <w NP1>Nasser<w GE>'s <w NN1>pyramid<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0164><w APPGE>His <w RT>sometimes <w JJ>enigmatic <w NN1>expression <w CC>and <w NN1>behaviour <w VBDR>were <w VVN>likened <w II>to <w DD1>that <w IO>of <w AT>the <w NN1>sphinx <w II>in <w NN2>cartoonists<w GE>' <w NN2>caricatures<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0165><w II>In <w APPGE>his <w NN1>confrontation <w IW>with <w AT>the <w NP1>West <w II>over <w NP1>Suez <w CC>and <w APPGE>his <w NN1>arousing <w IO>of <w JJ>Arab <w NN1>nationalism <w TO>to <w VVI>confront <w AT>the <w JJ>intrusive <w JJ>Western <w NN1>position <w II>in <w AT>the <w NP1>Middle <w NP1>East<c YCOM>, <w PPHS1>he <w VBDZ>was <w VVN>spoken <w IO>of <w II>as <w AT1>a <w JJ>modern-day <w NP1>Salah <w NP1>al-Din<c YSTP>. </s>
<s n=0166><w NP1>Nasser <w VBDZ>was <w RR>also <w TO>to <w VBI>be <w VVN>compared <w II>to <w NP1>Mohamed <w NP1>Ali<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w APPGE>his <w NN2>efforts <w TO>to <w VVI>modernise <w NP1>Egypt <w CC>and <w VVI>industrialise <w APPGE>his <w NN1>economy<c YCOM>, <w NP1>Ahmed <w NP1>Arabi<c YCOM>, <w VVG>leading <w AT1>an <w JJR>earlier <w JJ>nationalist <w NN1>uprising<c YCOM>, <w CC>and <w NP1>Zaghlul<c YCOM>, <w NP1>al <w NP1>zaim<c YCOM>, <w IW>with <w APPGE>his <w NN1>popularity <w II>among <w AT>the <w JJ>Arab <w NN2>masses<c YSTP>.<gap cause="sampling strategy" desc="rest of chapter"></s>
</p>
</div1>
</text>
</bncDoc>
